<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Indonesian diary</title>
    <link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html</link>
    <description>My first trip in 2008 through Indonesia: records of  cultural, technological and artistic encounters along the way.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <generator>Emacs Muse</generator>

Journeys across Indonesia (2007 - 2008)

This  travel  diary gathers  the  documentation  of  my journeys  in
Indonesia:  impressions  of  cultural,  technological  and  artistic
encounters along the way.



<item>
<title>Arrival in Jakarta</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Arrival%20in%20Jakarta</link>
<description><![CDATA[I  quickly find a  good &  modest accommodation  in Jakarta,  sea food
goreng  and time  for  a nap.   On  the first  impression ,  Indonesia
reminds me of  India: people is very friendly and  smiles all the time
at  my curly  hair (kerupu  in  bahasa). I  look very  comical for  my
striking  resemblance  to  Ahmad   Albar  an  extremely  popular  '80s
Indonesian rock-star, currently jailed.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2007 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Arrival%20in%20Jakarta</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Never travel without ukulele</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Never%20travel%20without%20ukulele</link>
<description><![CDATA[Nothing  much  happening today,  before  leaving  to  Jogja I  briefly
visited a  market in Jakarta, there  i bought a  green Ukulele guitar:
here people enjoys  the long nights sitting at  the borders of streets
playing  instruments  and I'm  really  looking  forward  to join  them
whenever i can :)



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2007 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Never%20travel%20without%20ukulele</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Arrive in Jogja</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Arrive%20in%20Jogja</link>
<description><![CDATA[Arrival in Jogja with the train  was at 4 o'clock in the morning: best
choice  then is to  have a  2 hours  sleep on  the benches  inside the
station,  with the  relaxing  feeling of  not  having electronic  eyes
pointed  on  you:  the  train  station is  camera-free,  quite  unique
nowadays!

But  unfortunately the  liberating  feeling of  being  outside of  the
matrix  is interrupted  by a  fat tourist  with an  even  fatter photo
camera  around his  neck: he  stands  up and  takes a  picture of  all
passengers half asleep on this  mild, hot and humid Christmas morning,
then runs away ashamed of having disturbed everyone damn it.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2007 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Arrive%20in%20Jogja</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Jogja on a tall-bike</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Jogja%20on%20a%20tall%2Dbike</link>
<description><![CDATA[Just arrived in Jogja and thanks to the bicycle clown Piero I've had a
fixed a bike out  of spare parts since the very first  day. And one of
the bikes we use is a tall-bike!  I'm not sure i can describe it well,
but can you imagine us around in Jogja riding on tall-bikes?

Piero on his tall-bike

the  effect  is  really  explosive  :) people  starts  laughing  hard,
irresistible!



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2007 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Jogja%20on%20a%20tall%2Dbike</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Taring Padi</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Taring%20Padi</link>
<description><![CDATA[Taring Padi artist collective

I've  had the  opportunity to  visit the  atelier of  Taring  Padi, an
artist collective of international fame producing amazing paintings.

Soon ready with all documentation, I've started an article documenting
with  photos the procedure  on how  they make  these big  paintings on
cloth using simple materials, a relatively cheap technique and lots of
fun together.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2007 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Taring%20Padi</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Floods report</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Floods%20report</link>
<description><![CDATA[A  local newspaper  publishes the  sad list  of towns  flooded  by the
monsoon rains, here they follow the numbers i could catch:

Solo: 26.720 people relocated (5.344 families)
Karanganyar: 71 dead
Pekalongan: 1 dead
Pemalang: 1 lost
Wonogiri: 17 dead
Sragen: 3 lost
Banyumas: 1 dead



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2007 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Floods%20report</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Yogyakarta biennale opening</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Yogyakarta%20biennale%20opening</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://biennalejogja.com



I've Been there and my impression is more than positive; it has been a
privileged  introduction to  social  and cultural  issues depicted  by
Indonesian artists with colourful tints and creativity.

The  audience is  constantly confronted  with actual  issues,  be them
social  or  intimate,  absolutely  touching.   Several  paintings  and
sculptures  are blooming  from  the  artistic life  of  this place  to
witness good historical memory and  vivid imagination of the young and
aware scene of artists presented.

One of the  surprising features is the quality  of details: when these
artists  make art,  they really  do  it personally,  caring about  all
details, employing all the time  it takes. Plus they do it themselves,
while Bob Sick declares the death  of Beuys on the walls of an avenue,
ten  more artists  show  their dedication  in  mastering every  single
aspect of their productions.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2007 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Yogyakarta%20biennale%20opening</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>the Bike Clown Circus</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#the%20Bike%20Clown%20Circus</link>
<description><![CDATA[

The Bike-Clown-Circus made a  brilliant performance in occasion of the
Biennale,  so here  we  go  documenting about  this  amazing group  of
gypsies traveling around the world by  bike to give people a smile and
inspiration to save our world from pollution.

I couldn't resist from featuring them with photos and interviews.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#the%20Bike%20Clown%20Circus</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The Volcano lighting up the year</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#The%20Volcano%20lighting%20up%20the%20year</link>
<description><![CDATA[the Merapi vulcano welcoming 2008



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#The%20Volcano%20lighting%20up%20the%20year</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Looking for the second hand watch</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Looking%20for%20the%20second%20hand%20watch</link>
<description><![CDATA[Yogyakarta hosts  an amazing market  of recycled objects  ranging from
antique  decorations  to  bicycle  parts, numismatics  and  of  course
electronics, with plenty of  mobile phone and accessories, clothes and
tools. Friendly merchants look  at the overwhelmed me wandering around
and  ask "what are  you looking  for?" my  reply is  simply "this!"
meaning literally all this: such a big market, so many people making a
living with recycling - and knowing  well how to do it, some even live
performing soldering circuits in front of customers :)


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Looking%20for%20the%20second%20hand%20watch</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Borobudur temple</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Borobudur%20temple</link>
<description><![CDATA[A very  inspiring experience, i must  have walked through  it twice up
and  down  in  circles, until  i  realized  this  temple is  a  deeply
articulated opera recording and playing back the narrative of Buddhism
using  time,  space and  light  in a  way  that  media-art can  barely
describe even nowadays.

the Borobudur temple nearby Jogja

Incredible. Sorry, no further  words available in poor human language,
just a pitiful photo for the record.




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Borobudur%20temple</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Reflections, looking back and forth</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Reflections%2C%20looking%20back%20and%20forth</link>
<description><![CDATA[I'm still working in setting up this diary and journal, at the time of
writing it  is not yet public, but  by now some good  friends know its
existence. My  intention is also to  publish things noted  down in the
past, and in  this process time and thoughts  swirl and reference each
other.

Today, while  publishing the Net Collectivism collage  of thoughts, by
reading it again  something revamps in me the  passion, the confusion,
the intense feeling of being  connected in a network, dealing with Our
Mind.

I feel finally mature enough  to understand some of Artaud's words and
I dream, with  eyes wide open, to overcome  the cage of individualism,
to reach the state of grace  in his Common Soul. But, thinking back to
Europe, how can we steer out of nihilism and individualism?

On my way  back to Jakarta, meditating during my trip,  I wish i could
share with  Pierre Levy the  optimism for a Collective  Intelligence -
then suddenly  i wake up and  I'm looking at  Taring Padi's collective
painting about Suharto's holocaust in Indonesia, while the dictator is
dying in a TV show.




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Reflections%2C%20looking%20back%20and%20forth</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Local elections in a small town</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Local%20elections%20in%20a%20small%20town</link>
<description><![CDATA[I  accompanied  a friend  to  vote for  local  elections  in a  little
district  of  Jakarta, first  thing  I notice  is  that  the urns  are
separated:  one box for  men, another  one for  women  so  I'm just
wondering about the conversion rate.




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Local%20elections%20in%20a%20small%20town</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Out for a while</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Out%20for%20a%20while</link>
<description><![CDATA[My visit permit expires after 30 days, so I'll be out of Indonesia for
a while.  Most  of the time i spent to  re-organise thoughts and ideas
and studying Lisp and Scheme  languages. Asia is always very inspiring
for  studying and  the  National  Library of  Singapore  is a  perfect
location for that.




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Out%20for%20a%20while</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Back in Jakarta</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Back%20in%20Jakarta</link>
<description><![CDATA[The most  astonishing thing for  me, being back  after 2 weeks,  is to
find out that  Bono, an engineer and UNIX expert  whom I've shown d:b,
has  migrated  all desktops  of  his  company  (previously running  m$
winblurs)  to   use  it.    His  colleagues,  mostly   engineers  and
programmers,  are already  mastering  the system,  customising it  for
their needs and soon organising courses.

My  guess now  is that  dyne:3  development will  see some  Indonesian
participation :)




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Back%20in%20Jakarta</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>A little hacker meeting</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#A%20little%20hacker%20meeting</link>
<description><![CDATA[Linked  documents:   Internet   in  Indonesia,
Hacker Space Design Patterns, Hackers in Indonesia 


An  inspiring informal  meeting happened,  I'm sure  participants will
keep it in  their memory for a  while. Let's hope it is  just a start,
hopefully inspiring larger  TAZ as the hackmeeting in  Italy and Spain
and the Chaos Computer Camp in Germany.

Here you can read a transcription of our meeting.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#A%20little%20hacker%20meeting</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Staying at IKOHI</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Staying%20at%20IKOHI</link>
<description><![CDATA[While  in  Jakarta  I've  been  a  guest  in  IKOHI,  an  organisation
campaigning for the human right to not disappear, as this is often the
way military  brutality operated  in Indonesia during  persecutions in
the '60s  and more recently end  of '90s. Activists at  IKOHI are very
busy these days monitoring  how history gets (re)written on mainstream
media concerning the war crimes of recently departed dictator.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Staying%20at%20IKOHI</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Frank Zappa as antidote to censorship</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Frank%20Zappa%20as%20antidote%20to%20censorship</link>
<description><![CDATA[While being around with a  lot of interesting people during this trip,
I've been  hearing a couple  of stories about censorship  of published
artworks: it is well predictable that in all places of this world most
interesting  things  are  censored,  i  believe that  happens  in  any
establishment.

So  I've  found appropriate  showing  to  my  Indonesian friends  this
video recording of Frank Zappa on CNN Crossfire talkshow.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Frank%20Zappa%20as%20antidote%20to%20censorship</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Asian-Pacific Transmission incoming</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Asian%2DPacific%20Transmission%20incoming</link>
<description><![CDATA[Since the start of the  Transmission initiative I'm being part of this
network  of hackers  and video-makers  sharing knowledge  to implement
media-democracy  using  open source  software  and independent  online
distribution of video.

Later on this  year, among the many things  happening in Indonesia, in
Jakarta will be held  the first Asian-Pacific Transmission meeting, so
I've been invited to join  And of the Engagemedia collective and Andan
of  Ruangrupa  to visit  the  beautiful  site  of Sukabumi  where  the
initiative will be held.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Asian%2DPacific%20Transmission%20incoming</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Crackdown on &quot;Underground Culture&quot;</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Crackdown%20on%20%22Underground%20Culture%22</link>
<description><![CDATA[Right in the  period I was visiting the splendid  setup of Common Room
in Bandung, something  very sad happened: 10 people  died for stampede
in a hard-core music concert, several press sources report the fact on
international scale.

The  event  has  immediately  given  ground  for  a  campaign  against
"Underground Culture" (as several newspapers titled) where old and new
conservatives  rallied  against  the rebellious  younger  generations,
pointing the  finger at the content  of such concerts  rather than the
obvious lack of proper infrastructure.

It all sounds very familiar to me



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#Crackdown%20on%20%22Underground%20Culture%22</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>VeeJaying night &quot;Hello Disco&quot;</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#VeeJaying%20night%20%22Hello%20Disco%22</link>
<description><![CDATA[



As  a guest  performer in  the vjnumberone  crew, together  with Tommy
Surya and  Julian Abraham,  we beamed a  liveset all night  in Jogja's
most crowded club.  Amazing! I  wasn't doing something like that since
years (easy to tell by the way i fell asleep on the backstage couch).

We  used  2 projectors  and  3 computers  all  setup  from a  balcony,
arranged mixing  by switching cables  and overlapping beams  running 3
different software  in a  full cross-over of  tools, keeping  the leit
motif of spinning cubes.

I  definitely went  wireframe, but  still  not that  minimal: using  a
computer mounted microphone for a spectral analysis of ambient (loud!)
music  Fluxus 3d  engine was  perfectly in  sync, no  frame  skips, no
latency in audio capture and FFT, all running on my EEEPC.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#VeeJaying%20night%20%22Hello%20Disco%22</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The House of Natural Fiber</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#The%20House%20of%20Natural%20Fiber</link>
<description><![CDATA[Time to leave has  come for me, but dulcis in fundo  I've found a home
also on this side of the world,  and is made of natural fiber by young
artists and true friends.



For the majority  of time I've spent in Java, HONF  has welcomed me in
the best  possible way:  i feel  now part of  this extended  family of
artists gathering  together from heterogeneous  contexts to constitute
an Indonesian Media Art Laboratory.



So  the next  appointment is  the  Cellsbutton media  art festival  in
August: at  the junction between one  of the most  active volcanoes of
Planet Hearth and timeless Temples, we are planning to gather again.

J & J bet on a bright future!


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/indonesia.html#The%20House%20of%20Natural%20Fiber</guid>

</item>




  </channel>
</rss>
