<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Jaromil's Research 2008</title>
    <link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html</link>
    <description>A diary noting down FOSS and tech related research, day by day findings and curiosities, collecting future and past thoughts.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <generator>Emacs Muse</generator>

This  diary collects  research  notes taken  during  the year  2008,
linking to external news  items, documents and publications, as well
collecting texts I've written and presented around.



You  can also  download this  publication  in PDF  format for  offline
reading on your personal information device: 

Thanks go to the NIMk, employing me in research and development.


<item>
<title>RIP Harold Pinter</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#RIP%20Harold%20Pinter</link>
<description><![CDATA[Harold Pinter died, yesterday.

The last  time I've heard  him, we were  in London's Hyde park  at the
Peace march in  2003 protesting against a war  that started anyway, in
the name  of democracy.  We  were millions in  the streets of  all the
World on that day, marching against war in Afghanistan and Iraq.


But no.  Our governments joined  the war anyway.  Our soldiers are out
there  far from  their families,  and today  is Christmas,  and Harold
Pinter is dead.  And I remember  clearly now his cry for peace. I feel
how little  sense our present has  in Europe. In  the Netherlands they
don't even know why the state  joined the war in Afghanistan, they are
still trying to  understand under which pressure the  militars and the
government actually did join, who signed the papers


Harold Pinter was a  great man. He had the guts to  say things as they
are, to face babylon with its  own crimes and hypocrisy, while his own
talent and  integrity are recognised  worldwide, by a Nobel  Prize and
much more than that.

He  was  not an  elitist  even  if his  talent  made  him  part of  an
intellectual elite,  and he had never  a doubt to say  things, even if
horrible to  be said.  He admittedly could  make mistakes, but  I feel
most things  he did were  right, he was  right to the point  on things
people didn't dare to be.

Let's all spend a few hours reading his words resting in our libraries
please.  Lets meditate how many compromises are we doing in the things
we aren't  saying, in  the moderated comfort  we are all  swimming in,
with the  privilege of our  brains and what  we can understand  of the
world and what we prefer to not say, for our own interest. How much is
worth a single  life, the life of  many people, the life of  a man who
dares like Harold Pinter did.

Below some  original Pinter's  quotes that will  surely be  deleted by
revisionists:

he has  called the President of  the United States, George  W. Bush, a
"mass murderer" and  the (then) Prime Minister of  the United Kingdom,
Tony  Blair,  both "mass-murdering"  and  a  "deluded  idiot" and  has
described them,  along with past  U.S. officials, as  "war criminals."

Pinter characterized Blair's Great Britain as "pathetic and supine," a
"bleating little lamb  tagging behind [the United States]  on a lead."
According  to   Pinter,  Blair  was   participating  in  "an   act  of
premeditated  mass  murder"  instigated  on behalf  of  "the  American
people," who,  Pinter notes, increasingly  protest "their government's
actions" (Public reading from War, as qtd. by Chrisafis and Tilden)

Pinter published  his remarks to the mass  peace protest demonstration
held on 15 February 2003, in London, on his website:

"The United States is a  monster out of control. Unless we challenge
it with absolute determination  American barbarism will destroy the
world. The  country is  run by a  bunch of criminal  lunatics, with
Blair as their hired Christian  thug. The planned attack on Iraq is
an act of premeditated mass murder" ("Speech at Hyde Park").

Those  remarks  anticipate his  2005  Nobel  Lecture,  "Art, Truth,  &
Politics", in which he observes:

"Many thousands,  if not  millions, of people  in the  United States
itself  are  demonstrably sickened,  shamed  and  angered by  their
government's actions, but  as things stand they are  not a coherent
political force yet. But the anxiety, uncertainty and fear which we
can  see  growing  daily  in  the  United  States  is  unlikely  to
diminish".

where he had  foreseen Obama campaign, for a  government that now owes
to Pinter's  life all the  coherence that it  takes to finally  make a
real change. Furthermore, speaking to Europe and Latin America, Pinter
exhorted  the mostly  European audience  "to resist  the power  of the
United States," stating:

"I'd  like  to  see Europe  echo  the  example  of Latin  America  in
withstanding the  economic and political intimidation  of the United
States. This is  a serious responsibility for Europe  and all of its
citizens" (Qtd.  in Anderson and Billington, Harold Pinter 428).

And  i must  confess this  last quote  reads so  sad  considering what
Europe really is, probably that's  the bigger mistake he has ever made
in his discourse.

rest in peace, Harold Pinter.

During these holy days i'm spending  a big deal of time networking and
gathering info on the Coltan and Blood issue, a panel we'll be running
at next  Transmediale, coming  january.  I wish  to dedicate  all this
effort to Harold  Pinter today, we shall do all  our best to continue,
to continue  saying what cannot be  told, right here, in  the belly of
the  monster.  I'm  reading  things  that cannot  be  said so  easily,
thinking of him now gives all the strenght needed to continue.

rest in peace, Harold Pinter.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#RIP%20Harold%20Pinter</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Copenhagen: Ungdomshuset courtcase</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Copenhagen%3A%20Ungdomshuset%20courtcase</link>
<description><![CDATA[On Monday 22  December 2008 5 womyn and 10 men,  who were present in
the  house at  the eviction  of the  Ungdomshuset, got  sentenced to
imprisonment.  11 people  sentenced to  1 year  and three  months, 3
people to one year and one (aged under 16) to nine months!

This is an  outrageous episode for all those  who care about liberties
for the  youth to express  and self-organise.  These young  people are
criticising  capitalism,  state  repression,  religious  hegemony  and
claiming  their own social  space within  a city  that, as  many other
cities,  doesn't  offers agency  for  social  interaction  out of  the
planned schemes and the omnipresent State of Control.

As   it  is   manifest  on   their  website,   their   activities  are
non-conformed, reflecting the repression and marginalisation they face
in  developing their  own values:  rebellion for  necessity,  vegan in
response to the inhumanity of the food industry, anti-fascist to fight
back what we have been (and we are still) going through, etc. etc.

These  are young people  that decided  to develop  their society  in a
different  way,  still being  denied  to  do  so: evicted  from  their
building  ("legally"  owned  by  some church),  persecuted  for  their
beliefs (from which  we can still learn a  lot about living together),
forced  into a  system  that exploits  their  labour without  offering
anything back, not even the freedom to live together.

What the persecutors seems to  not understand is that this youth won't
give up  - and  rightfully so: since  they have  the right to  build a
different  world for themselves,  after the  "adults" have  ruined the
present one already, in the eyes of their own kids.

This conflict will just make  things worst for everyone: the "problem"
will stay (and grow with  more systemic problems) tainting the genuine
growth  of new  people and  their sincere  research for  solutions, as
their need to defend a few liberated spaces will turn into violence to
survive.




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Copenhagen%3A%20Ungdomshuset%20courtcase</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Where recycling meets design</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Where%20recycling%20meets%20design</link>
<description><![CDATA[Superuse.org looks like an "hack-a-day for designers":

Superuse  is  a  online   community  of  designers,  architects  and
everybody  else who is  interested in  inventive ways  of recycling.

Good brico attitude  and lots of neat results! In  Europe there are so
few people recycling that the aesthetic patterns of such practices are
mostly  limited to  punk and  new-age ,  but this  website  shows that
designers can move in many more directions along these lines.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Where%20recycling%20meets%20design</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Nano data centers #2</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Nano%20data%20centers%20%232</link>
<description><![CDATA[Six months later, let's have a look again at the NADA(EU-FP7) project,
mentioned earlier in  this research, funded by the  EU Commissions 7th
Framework Program (FP7).

Its aims  are well shaped  after the "P2P revolution",  nothing really
new to those  of us already working on  (deployed) distributed network
protocols and visions  as hivenetworks, olsrd, B.A.T.M.A.N., netsukuku
and of course bittorrent.

But!  NADA  plans to  patent its results.   And how?  since  in Europe
software patents  aren't legal?  we'll see, meanwhile  in the "Related
Projects ->  Security" section  on their website  is well  visible the
research  on  "trusted computing"  to  limit  liberties and  establish
monopolies rather than preserve security.

What a restrictive attitude for a publicly funded project.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Nano%20data%20centers%20%232</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Schiphol people, wij gaan!</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Schiphol%20people%2C%20wij%20gaan%21</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today  M2M  Radio  launched  an  international  press  release  titled
European Court of Human Rights admits case against Dutch ministers for
Schiphol Fire:

The European Court of Human  Rights in Strasbourg has informed Dutch
lawyer  Mr.N.M.P.   Steijnen  that   the  Court  has   admitted  the
application  against two former  Dutch ministers,  or the  State, in
relation with the  Schiphol Fire.  This fire on  the 26th of October
2005 killed  eleven detained migrants  in a detention center  on the
premises  of  Hollands  main  Schiphol  airport.   Mr.  Steijnen  is
pressing  these charges  representing committee  of non-governmental
organizations,  survivors  and  relatives  of the  deceased  against
Mr.  J.P.H. (Piet  Hein) Donner,  who was  at the  time  minister of
Justice (and today of social affairs) and against Mrs. M.C.F. (Rita)
Verdonk,  who   was  at  the   time  Minister  of   Immigration  and
Integration. They  are charged with cruel  and humiliating treatment
(Art.3 ECHR)  of both  the killed inmates  and the survivors  of the
fire.  Donner  is held  responsible  for  the  construction and  the
management  of the  complex,  while  Verdonk was  in  charge of  the
administrative  detention  of   undocumented  migrants  and  of  the
treatment  of the survivors  after the  fire.  The  European Court's
decision brings this procedure now to the international level, after
the Dutch  legal instances have decided against  prosecuting, on the
grounds that  servants of  the state cannot  be held  accountable in
person. The independent Dutch  Security Board concluded in 2006 that
the disaster  would have  been much smaller  if the  authorities had
lived up  to the  regulations. As a  consequence of this  report two
Ministers  then  resigned,  Donner  and  Mrs.  Dekker  (Housing  and
Environment). Verdonk remained in office  and is now heading her own
populist,  right-wing  party  "Trots  op Nederland"  (Proud  of  the
Netherlands).

The only one man being prosecuted in relation to the Fire will stand
to  appeal  in  the  coming   months.   The  accused  is  Ahmed  Isa
Al-J(eballi), a migrant  from Libya, who was detained  in Block K of
the Detention  Center of  Schiphol East in  order to  be transported
back to his native country. In the night of the 26th of October 2005
a fire took place in this Block, which killed eleven inmates.  Ahmed
Isa is  charged for setting  fire to his  cell by throwing  away his
cigarette butt before  falling asleep.  In 2006 he  was condemned to
three years of  confinement by the Court of  Haarlem for causing the
fire and  thus killing eleven  people and severely  wounding fifteen
others. The judge thereby endorsed the argumentation of the District
Attorney that  Ahmed Isa  consciously took the  risk of  causing the
disaster  by negligently  throwing away  his  cigarette: conditional
intent.   The technical  evidence is  highly disputed  and  is under
revision  by   an  expert  team   at  the  University   of  Lausanne
(Switzerland).   There is  serious  evidence that  the fire  started
elsewhere  in Block  K.   The  chance that  the  particular type  of
cigarette the accused was smoking  could effectively start a fire is
very  small. It  was  a roll-your-own  "shaggie"  rolled with  paper
called Blue  Rizla, known to  extinguish rapidly. Last  December two
experts, Prof. Wagenaars  en Koppen, pointed out that  the memory of
the  accused,  particularly  his   admitting  that  he  pitched  his
cigarette that very evening of the fire, is highly unreliable.  This
is  another major  blow  for the  persecutor,  comments Ahmed  Isa's
lawyer mr. Eduard Damman.

However, the fundamental argument against the ruling of the court is
a political one: even if it were true that Ahmed Isa caused the fire
then the Dutch State has done everything to make it possible for his
cigarette  to  create  a  major  disaster. Basically  the  state  is
responsible for those detained in their facilities. The building and
safety regulations had been neglected  and the training level of the
personnel was substandard.

Free Ahmed Isa = Justice for All Survivors

The cause of  justice for all survivors boils down to  the case of the
only  man that  has been  accused so  far: Ahmed  isa  Al-J(eballi). A
proper  administration of  justice is  of the  highest  importance for
their well being and indeed for their lives. Therefore M2M Radio calls
on international law experts to  monitor this case.  There are several
reasons to seek international monitoring of the upcoming proceedings:

The International dimension: the  victims of the Schiphol Fire are
citizens of at least thirty five different countries around the world.

The disaster happened in the domain of administrative law aimed at
tackling irregular migration in the Netherlands.  The Dutch government
has been criticized in many  instances both by the European Court, the
Commission for the Prevention of  Torture and Inhuman Treatment of the
European Council  and by  Amnesty International for  not living  up to
internationally established standards of rule of law and human rights.

The Dutch State is party in this case and therefore it is doubtful
if it can guarantee a fair trial.

The case of the  Schiphol Fire has severely damaged the confidence
of many citizens in the democracy of the Netherlands.

Finally,  not  only  the  accused, but  also  the  survivors  and
relatives of the dead, are suffering until this day from the physical,
material  and  psychological  consequences   of  the  fire.  A  proper
administration of justice is of  the highest importance for their well
being and indeed their lives.

To facilitate the monitoring M2M Radio will produce live coverage of
the    trial    and    parallel    sessions   on    the    internet:
m2m.streamtime.org


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Schiphol%20people%2C%20wij%20gaan%21</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Defending my Bastard Culture!</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Defending%20my%20Bastard%20Culture%21</link>
<description><![CDATA[This is  the title of Mirko  Tobias Schäfer's PhD  dissertation at the
University of Utrecht, Department for Media and Culture Studies, along
with the  subtitle "User participation  and the extension  of cultural
industries".

It is definitely worth a look (free download on Mirko's website) as it
packs together an extensive research  on the dynamics of creativity in
new media practices.




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Defending%20my%20Bastard%20Culture%21</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>RIP Thomas Reichart</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#RIP%20Thomas%20Reichart</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today  the body  of Thomas,  a photographer  coming all  the  way from
Stuttgart  to Sicily  to take  pictures of  Etna's lava  activity, was
found dead in a lava-formed pit on top of the Volcano.

His story is striking as  he died pursuing a dangerous and fascinating
dream,  leaving  us  beautiful   pictures  to  be  admired  after  his
disgraceful   death.

It is deeply touching to look  now at what Thomas could upload online.
His  passion  pushed  him over  the  limits  of  his own  body,  still
realising a beautiful net-based art piece.

What Thomas  left us online  unleashes a deep dramaturgy  for net.art,
carried  by  the ubiquitous  availability  of  such intense  pictures,
freely echoing the deep effort and passion behind them.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#RIP%20Thomas%20Reichart</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Spinoza in Amsterdam</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Spinoza%20in%20Amsterdam</link>
<description><![CDATA[I was invited  to join today's debate in  Amsterdam, about Spinoza and
the  meaning  of Freedom,  organised  by  coolpolitics.nl.  After  two
interesting lectures by Jeroen Bartels and Hans Achterhuis, the public
participated in  a debate  that saw me  sitting besides Boris  van der
Ham, Arendo Joustra and Ahmed Aynan.

It was  somehow boring to  over-discuss "freedom of speech"  topics as
publication  of  Fitna, still  I  did my  best  to  progress into  the
analysis of the Internet of Things, the future of property in a "truly
liberal"  sense and  the monopolistic  role  of the  industry in  this
regards. As  there wasn't enough space  for all the  topics that could
have been raised, I'll do my best to elaborate further here.

I argued that neo-liberism is betraying its own roots, as Adam Smith's
openness  is contradicted  by the  enclosure of  consumer  objects and
their  creative   potentials.   In  fact  I'd  love   to  complete  my
declaration stating that today neo-liberism is dead: exactly 120 years
after the birth of Harpo Marx  on 23 november 1888, one day before the
anniversary of  Spinoza's birth, neo-liberism is buried  under its own
unrealisation, failing to survive its lies, drained by a market crisis
we are all witnessing, buried by a progressive analysis on the damages
consumerism brought to our societies.

Regarding free speech and the  role of artists, topic that was debated
unfortunately also  in relation  to the youtube-collage  called Fitna,
let me quote Bansky:

"The thing I hate the most about advertising is that it attracts all
the bright,  creative and ambitious young people,  leaving us mainly
with the slow and self-obsessed to become our artists. Modern art is
a disaster  area.  Never in the  field of human history  has so much
been used by so many to say so little."

And  it was  a  pleasure to  hear the  wisdom  of an  elder among  the
audience  reminding  how pervasive  is  advertisement (and  industrial
rhetoric  I'd say)  in the  cultural debate,  a position  I  linked to
philosopher Herbert Marcuse for his One-Dimensional Man essay: this is
such an important reflection today, explicitly dealing with freedom of
desire,  a  concept  that  is  well  contextual  to  Spinoza's  corpus
teoreticus.

All in all it felt that, besides the natural tendency of the debate to
stick to  old and abused  topics, the audience also  nurtured interest
for a progressive  analysis on property and the  novel models proposed
by the  free software movement. I  was surprised by a  public that was
some  generations older  than mine  and  that can  wisely unfold  such
analysis: more  than ever  now I believe  free software  benefits from
being discussed in a  philosophical context.  As more initiatives will
be held  next year  in Amsterdam about  Spinoza I'll be  interested to
follow  the discussion, especially  when it  will focus  on everyone's
freedom in this world, the  freedom to imagination and desire, not the
smart arrogance of a few  populist politicians to offend religions and
provoke hatred.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Spinoza%20in%20Amsterdam</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Anomalous Wave of student protests</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Anomalous%20Wave%20of%20student%20protests</link>
<description><![CDATA[Onda  Anomala  is the  name  choosen  by  italian students  mobilising
against  privatisation  of schools  and  rising  prices for  education
promoted  by  the  new  decree of  Mariastella  Gelmini,  Berlusconi's
minister  for education.   The main  slogan  is strong  and can  touch
everyone's hear:

WE WON'T PAY FOR YOUR CRISIS

Progressively,  the  youth in  Europe  is  recognising the  precarious
future  that previous  generations have  left: more  young  people are
acknowledging  the results  of financial  and ecological  disasters in
their own lives - and many  know who the responsible are.

It  is a  common  thought  this crisis  being  provoked by  widespread
incompetence and corruption of the so called "neo-liberist" leaders: a
ruling cast that has substituted  ethics with personal profit, that is
now finally  declining, leaving a dramatic trail  of privatised social
services,  a deregulated  economy  in  agony and  dulcis  in fundo  an
emergency plan  to save  its own failure  stealing resources  from the
social welfare, most importantly the education field.

This is  what is  happening in  Italy, as usual  for politics  in this
country,  in  a   very  intense  and  outrageous  way   -  while  more
international  youth  movements  are  sharing this  analysis,  quickly
propagating  the uprisings  on a  wider scale.

Here is the first Anomalous wave  pamphlet in english, for you to read
and print to inform about what is happening and why.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Anomalous%20Wave%20of%20student%20protests</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Object Oriented Poetry</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Object%20Oriented%20Poetry</link>
<description><![CDATA[After its  opening last friday,  the premiere of TBT  installations is
being exhibited  in Amsterdam until  next january, where  visitors are
engaging the act of writing Time Based Poetry.

Later  in the  evening today  I've  received a  message titled  Object
Oriented Poetry, signed by Robert Elouard:


Void(Universe(OurGalaxy(OurSolarSystem(
                                        sun(

Earth(Land(Continent(Man(cardio(blodvessel(cell(molecule(atom(quark(lepton(void()))
                                nervous()
                                skeletal()
                                etc()
           Sea())

                                Moon()
           Venus()
           Mercury()
           Mars()
           Jupiter()
                                Callista()
                                Eros()
                                Etc()
           Uranus()
           Etc()
           ))))



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Object%20Oriented%20Poetry</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Late night browsing</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Late%20night%20browsing</link>
<description><![CDATA[Pretty tired of  waiting for Firefox to open up web  pages on my EEEPC
900  desktop,  a nightly  wandering  through  code  lead to  some  new
actively developed  alternative browsers,  finding out that  the fresh
options on GNU/Linux today are Midori and Skipstone.

However the HTML rendering  engines embedded are still Gecko (Mozilla)
and WebKit  (Safari): not  to be compared  with a project  like Links2
where the entire rendering engine is a new optimised rewrite.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Late%20night%20browsing</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Your very own water  (continued)</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Your%20very%20own%20water%20%2E%2E%2E%20</link>
<description><![CDATA[As previously mentioned  in this journal, NASA is  researching (as the
Russian  space agency  use to  do) on  obtaining drinkable  water from
urine.

Yesterday an  article on BBC  announced that the water  distilled from
urine did pass the first taste test at NASA.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Your%20very%20own%20water%20%2E%2E%2E%20</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Let's talk about cyber-crime</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Let%27s%20talk%20about%20cyber%2Dcrime</link>
<description><![CDATA[And guess who are the  criminals: kids hacking closed systems to claim
their own freedom, or  corporations corrupting policy makers to expand
their monopolies?

In the last  two days the situation became  clear, as several articles
opened an important  debate on the integrity of  digital policy makers
around         the         World:         it        seems         that
top Micro$oft executives have  been bullying patents on treatments for
malaria, HIV, TB, hepatitis, smallpox, and cancer. They have been also
bidding a Nigerian contractor $400,000 to retard Linux's movement into
the government sector.

And  last but not  least, they  have been  signing contracts  with the
European Community  that the  EU Council now  refuses to  make public:
Marco  Cappato,   a  member  of   the  EU  parliament,   reports  that
his  request to  divulge  was  denied as  "the  [divulging] of  [this]
information could jeopardize the  protection of commercial interest of
Micro$oft".         On        the        same        track,        the
EU  Council   refuses  to  release  the  ACTA   documents,  about  the
controversial Anti Counterfeit Trade Agreement.

Considering  the  ethical implications  behind  the  adoption of  Free
Software in the  public sector, these facts are  clearly outlining the
criminal conduct of the  Micro$oft corporation in various governmental
sectors.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Let%27s%20talk%20about%20cyber%2Dcrime</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Justice on Genova 2001?</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Justice%20on%20Genova%202001%3F</link>
<description><![CDATA[In a few days will be  pronounced the verdict for the 29 police agents
charged for violence on protestants  the night of 21-22 july in Genova
when they  broke in the Diaz  school and beat up  all people sheltered
inside, silenced the radio station  and among the others nearly killed
british journalist Mark Covell.

Mark is sitting in the  front-line of this process, which is extremely
important for Europe: demonstrating that after little more than half a
century we  are still  able to recognise  when fascism takes  over our
freedom.

I  fear a  big delusion,  especially  considering the  outcome of  the
Bolzaneto court-case  about the same  night in that prison,  where 209
people denounced having been tortured, still the court denied that was
a violation of human rights.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Justice%20on%20Genova%202001%3F</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Theora 1.0 final release</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Theora%201%2E0%20final%20release</link>
<description><![CDATA[With  great  satisfaction  by   all  developers  involved,  today  the
final 1.0 release  of Theora video codec was  announced, hinting about
the upcoming support in Firefox 3.1 and the "Thusnelda branch" quality
improvements which will be merged into the next Theora 1.1 release.

A  great day  and lots  more to  do as  finally this  100%  free video
framework  will grow  in  adoption.   Just during  these  days and  in
collaboration  with   some  piksel  and  giss.tv   developers  we  are
envisioning some serious plans and a roadmap for FreeJ, aiming to be a
portable vision mixer engine to produce Theora video streams.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Theora%201%2E0%20final%20release</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The Shallowest generation</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20Shallowest%20generation</link>
<description><![CDATA[A  very interesting article  from a  few days  ago reports  a detailed
analysis on  the progression of  occidental economy: the  past present
and future of the so called "Baby Boom" generation.

Definitely worth reading, as  i recommend reading the novels published
in "Baby Boom" by Jean Vautrin, among my favourite books.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20Shallowest%20generation</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Tactical Media files</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Tactical%20Media%20files</link>
<description><![CDATA[I was very  pleased by this news: the Tactical  Media files archive is
now online and started gathering almost 30 years of history behind the
many next5minutes and net.congestion conferences held in Amsterdam.

These events contributed  to develop and share a  critical approach to
media with  the young contemporary generation between  Europe and USA,
spawning several initiatives that referred to tactical media practices
in the fields of arts and activism.

It is  worth browsing and,  if you still  keep some materials  on your
shelf, send them on!

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Tactical%20Media%20files</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Booklaunch Internet of Things</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Booklaunch%20Internet%20of%20Things</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today was  the launch of the  new "network notebook"  published by the
Institute of Network Cultures in  Amsterdam: The Internet of Things, a
critique of ambient technology and the all-seeing network of RFID.

The  launch was photographed,  blogged and  filmed, with  a discussion
hosted  by Geert Lovink  including presentations  by Martijn  de Waal,
Eric Kluitenberg and me: here are the slides I've shown.

It is a slick and dense publication for which I'm a proud contributor,
if you're curious enough now you can freely download the notebook.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Booklaunch%20Internet%20of%20Things</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>More from FSCONS</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#More%20from%20FSCONS</link>
<description><![CDATA[More  interesting talks  given at  FSCONS are  available  on-line, I'd
recommend watching David Cuartielles  presenting Arduino (video part 1
and  part 2),  Rasmus Fleisher  on  copyright issues  and Peter  Stuge
giving an overview of Coreboot.

Also interesting Johan  Söderberg's "conflict perspective" on hacking,
opening a reflection on unionism and hacker communities.

These and more  themes discussed will hopefully emerge  soon in a book
publication gathering written contributions from the FSCONS speakers.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#More%20from%20FSCONS</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>FSCONS in Gothenburg</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#FSCONS%20in%20Gothenburg</link>
<description><![CDATA[The  Nordic Free  Society  conference in  Gothenburg  gathered a  very
interesting crowd of smart  people, genuine Free Software enthusiasts,
young influential developers, pirate  party activists and a Steve Jobs
clone.

I've  given a speech:  here are  the slides  and the  video recording,
cheers to  Yves, Valentina  and all the  Giss.tv stream team.   And of
course  a big  thanks  to the  organisation  that made  it all  happen
voluntarily,  for a big  immaterial profit  that we  all carry  in our
heads and hearts! nordic people can be very warm :)



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#FSCONS%20in%20Gothenburg</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Deported ohne ausweis</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Deported%20ohne%20ausweis</link>
<description><![CDATA[While  Riding an  18  hours long  bus trip  on  my way  to the  FSCONS
conference  in  Goteborg,  our  vehicle  was checked  by  polizei  for
passenger's passport before embarking on the ferry to Denmark.

As two  men were found without  papers, the cop told  them in english:
"end of the journey" and abducted them outside, into a police van. The
sans-papiers  had a  southern look,  black curly  hair,  somehow mixed
traits between balcan and mediterranean physiognomies.

No other  passenger in the bus  was explained where  these people were
brought and  for how long;  it was just  a clean removal,  a situation
where  everyone   was  put  on  hold,  denying   any  solidarity,  any
sentiments, any feelings, any questions.

Most people  in the  bus were  migrants, still no  one related  to the
event, looking like nothing had  just happened, as if the cops flashed
us with some short-memory deletion device.

It is  not the first  time I'm witnessing  a border arrest,  but still
every  time it  feels  closer, as  the  cop indulges  on  my worn  out
passport, prolonged to last until 2012 without biometrics.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Deported%20ohne%20ausweis</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Italian school's liberty violated</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Italian%20school%27s%20liberty%20violated</link>
<description><![CDATA[In Rome  the State  University "La Sapienza"  has been occupied  by an
assembly  of  5.000  students,  following with  a  demonstration  that
counted 10.000 on the streets.

Students  and   citizens  are  protesting   against  privatisation  of
education,  which is demolishing  the public  school system  in Italy,
under the  extreme rush of neo-liberist government.

In  this situation  of turmoil  Berlusconi declared  that  police will
intervene in  schools, while Francesco Cossiga,  Honorary President of
the  Italian Republic  and  Senator  for life,  literally  said in  an
interview:

"Maroni  should  do exactly  what  I did  when  I  was minister  for
Internal Affairs. In the first  place, he should just leave the high
school students  alone, because, just  think what would happen  if a
youngster were  to be killed  or seriously injured Leave  them be
(the  university students  - Ed).  Pull  the Police  forces off  the
streets  and out  of  the  University, then  send  in some  “agents
provocateurs” to  infiltrate the movement,  people that are  up for
anything and  leave the  demonstrators for about  ten days or  so to
ravage  the  shops,  set fire  to  vehicles  and  lay waste  to  the
cities. Then, having gained the  support of the public, the sound of
the ambulance  sirens must  drown out the  sirens of the  Police and
Carabinieri vehicles.  This is because  the forces of law  and order
should not show any pity whatsoever  and should send the lot of them
to  hospital.  Don’t  arrest  them,  after all,  the  judges  would
immediately allow them back onto  the streets. Rather, you must beat
them and also beat up those lecturers that are spurring the students
on.  The lecturers  above all.  I’m  not saying  the elderly  ones,
certainly, but  the little girl  teachers yes this is  the recipe
for democracy: put out the flames before the fire takes over ".


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Italian%20school%27s%20liberty%20violated</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Fortinet used to block dyne.org</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Fortinet%20used%20to%20block%20dyne%2Eorg</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today  I've  been doing  technical  assistance  for  the office  of  a
cultural institution  in Amsterdam  and realised the  dyne.org website
wasn't reachable  from their  network: FortiNet used  to block  it, as
their  network  appliances  are  automatically  administered  by  this
foreign corporation to censor on-line content.

Reason  of the  censorship  was "Freeware  software".   Result of  the
censorship  was that,  because of  a corporate  blacklist from  USA, a
cultural  institution  in Amsterdam  cannot  visit  the  website of  a
cultural producer  (and regularly registered foundation)  a few canals
away.

Luckily enough the problem is  gone now as FortiNet quickly reacted my
complaint to them by enabling  the browsing of dyne.org.  But how many
other cases are like that around the world?



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Fortinet%20used%20to%20block%20dyne%2Eorg</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Time Based Text 0.8</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Time%20Based%20Text%200%2E8</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today a new release of TBT is out, with some new interesting features,
among  them  a Python-GTK  graphical  interface  contributed by  Pablo
Caedes Martin.

I'm tidying up the software for the upcoming exhibition SPEAK OUT LOUD
where it will be shown in the form of an interactive installation, for
the first time since it was commissioned.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Time%20Based%20Text%200%2E8</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Apple computers and ICT pollution</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Apple%20computers%20and%20ICT%20pollution</link>
<description><![CDATA[This declaration of Apple computers  made me almost fall off the chair
today:

"Apple believes that improving  the environmental performance of our
business starts with our products."

and  so on  it  goes, with  a  press release  about how  environmental
friendly is their new MacBoorger "PRO".

This  is so  ridiculous: Apple  environmental policies  are  among the
worst in  all  the IT  market,  and not  just  for manufacturing  and
materials, but especially since  they never aloud reuse, customisation
and recycling of their products, building an economic empire on closed
branding, avoiding interoperability of components, brain-washing users
to buy new products every year.

All this  for decades  until nowadays, when  the DRM in  Iphone debate
still  unrolls  for another  crapple  gadget  that  is establishing  a
proprietary infrastructure that is not generic nor accessible.

How disgusting are now those marketing lies!



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Apple%20computers%20and%20ICT%20pollution</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Freedom not Fear</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Freedom%20not%20Fear</link>
<description><![CDATA[The 11  October has seen  several popular demonstrations raise  in the
streets of Europe, all systematically ignored by the mainstream media,
still  successful in  spreading important  reflections on  privacy and
freedom, a seminal platform for future political discourse.

The  website vorratsdatenspeicherung.de  has  a comprehensive  report,
here is the call to various places where it has been organised.

I joined the demonstration in Den Haag, but my wish was actually to be
in Sophia, where the well active  organisation set up one of the first
websites to appear online about the event.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Freedom%20not%20Fear</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title> Cloud computing debated</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#%20Cloud%20computing%20debated</link>
<description><![CDATA[Some days ago RMS gave a statement on cloud computing to a journalist of
the Guardian UK, this article followed up.

Fatima Lasay  forwarded me  her reflections on  the topic,  which I've
found  a very  interesting reflection  and commentary,  posted  on the
bricolabs mailinglist.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#%20Cloud%20computing%20debated</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Man arrested for wardriving in NL</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Man%20arrested%20for%20wardriving%20in%20NL</link>
<description><![CDATA[This  dutch news  appeared  today reporting  the  arrest of  a man  in
Voorthuizen who was sitting in his  parked car with a laptop trying to
get online from available wireless internet spots.

It's the first time i hear of such a kind of arrest.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Man%20arrested%20for%20wardriving%20in%20NL</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The Internet of Things</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20Internet%20of%20Things</link>
<description><![CDATA[The Institute of Network Cultures has launched today a new publication
(freely     available     online     and     on     paper)     titled:
The Internet of Things: A critique of ambient technology.

It consists  of a report about  many of the  discussions developed the
past year in the bricolabs network, including various contributions in
the form of a "collaborative narrative" examining what impact RFID and
other systems will have on our cities and our wider society.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20Internet%20of%20Things</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Warnet Indonesia</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Warnet%20Indonesia</link>
<description><![CDATA[As an  attempt to raise discussion  on the issue  of reconciliation in
Indonesia after the Kudeta and  following massacres in '65 and '95, we
have formed  a committee of  researchers, writers and  historians that
held on 1st october its first  evening of discussions in the Waag, the
Theatrum  Anatomicum  in  Amsterdam,   with  an  online  broadcast  by
Killertv.nl.

It  was a  successful evening,  hosting inspiring  speeches  among the
others  by Saskia  Wieringa, Heri  Latief,  Max Lane  and Yanti,  well
partecipated on-site  as well  on-line where many  Indonesians watched
the stream.

My intervention  focused on the  intense role that Internet  played in
the popular uprisings in 1995 that lead to the destitution of dictator
Soeharto  in   1998.   Here  you   can  download  the   slides  titled
Warnet Indonesia.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Warnet%20Indonesia</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Spike Lee revisionism on italian Partisans</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Spike%20Lee%20revisionism%20on%20italian%20Partisans</link>
<description><![CDATA[A  polemic  exploded  in  Italy,   moved  forward  by  the  ANPI  (the
association  of partisans  who  fought to  liberate  the country  from
fascism) regarding the facts Spike  Lee told in his new movie "Miracle
in St.Anna".   Quoting the vice-president of the  ANPI in Pietrasanta,
Giovanni Cipollini:

The declarations  of Spike  Lee are offending  us.  What he  said is
demonstrating that he willingly  realized a film without taking into
consideration  the truth  of what  really happened  in  Sant'Anna di
Stazzema.

Spike Lee has so far refused  any dialogue with witnesses of the facts
he is representing  in his fiction; the old  partisans are offended by
elements of fantasy in the story, for example when in the movie one of
them betrays  his Companeros,  a crucial moment  in the  fiction which
never really happened in history.

Another offensive point is that  the movie suggests the partisans used
the civilian population to shield themselves, supporting a rhetoric of
war that tries to shed negative light on grassroot civilian resistance
against aggression.

In solidarity with all the people  who fought and gave their lives for
my own  freedom, I feel  deluded too. I  guess this story can  go well
along with  the essay of  Rana Dasgupta about  Hollywood's revisionism
and how it is harming society and its memory.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Spike%20Lee%20revisionism%20on%20italian%20Partisans</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Avoiding ruinous compromises</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Avoiding%20ruinous%20compromises</link>
<description><![CDATA[Twenty-five years ago,  on the 27 September 1983,  Richard M. Stallman
shared a plan to create a completely free operating system called GNU.

For the  25th anniversary of the  GNU project, which  during the years
spawned a word-wide movement of hackers engaged to liberate users from
mental  slavery  and  corporate  monopolies, RMS  wrote  an  important
statement about compromises we shouldn't do, explaining why it is more
and more important to keep focus on the originating principles and how
difficult that is becoming nowadays.

It  is getting harder  as it  goes on,  as a  big share  of visibility
generated by our efforts is nowadays in the hegemony of commercial and
billion-funded "philanthropic"  ventures that are  often neglecting to
properly  represent and respect  the social  and political  aspects of
this movement, as well its grassroot nature.

This statement was very much needed, what I understand is that we must
keep in balance  and well focused on a long  term strategy to preserve
the fundamental  principles of the GNU project  alive, protecting them
from a  growing amount of manipulations,  of which a few  can still be
acceptable  and  useful to  spread  our  social  concerns in  multiple
contexts.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Avoiding%20ruinous%20compromises</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Largest bank failure in history</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Largest%20bank%20failure%20in%20history</link>
<description><![CDATA[It happened today, even if most news didn't reported much about it:

Federal  regulators seized Washington  Mutual and  struck a  deal to
sell the bulk of its operations to J.P. Morgan in what is by far the
largest bank failure in history.

We  are talking  about a  hole  of $307  billions in  assets, with  an
expected domino effect as more banks will be following.

Recently i got more  insterested in financial systems, looking forward
to the day when our generation will finally have a word on new ways to
shape economy - and seems that day is getting closer.

We all know  about the financial crisis, but  what is most interesting
is the way the mainstream media are presenting it: hiding failures (as
in the WAMU  case) and advertising all kind  of optimistic initiatives
to "save  the market", all surprisingly backed  by state intervention.
The collusion  between media  and finance leads  into a dirty  game of
misinformation.

Let me remind that it is plank 5 of the communist manifesto reciting:

Centralization of credit  in the hands of the State,  by means of a
national bank with state capital and an exclusive monopoly.

Are we really up for such regressions?


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Largest%20bank%20failure%20in%20history</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Trappist beer to keep contextual integrity</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Trappist%20beer%20to%20keep%20contextual%20integrity</link>
<description><![CDATA[With this article titled Prophet  vs profit: dilemma for brewing monks
Belgian news report the inspiring  case of the Trappist monks, brewing
a beer that is well known for its excellence.

The dilemma is that, on the  wave of their success, they should choose
between  scaling  their  production  to  industrial  level  or  remain
artisans  and  miss to  satisfy  the  growing  demand, giving  up  the
opportunity for profit.

I like their statement:

The main  reason for  refusing (to produce  more) is that  the monks
attach  enormous  importance to  a  limited  production  on a  human
scale.

Enjoying  all the  inspiring meanings  attached to  the  definition of
human scale in this and other  contexts. I just hope one doesn't needs
to be a monk to nurture such good principles in life.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Trappist%20beer%20to%20keep%20contextual%20integrity</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The Next Idea of the Artist</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20Next%20Idea%20of%20the%20Artist</link>
<description><![CDATA[Rana Dasgupta posted on nettime his new extremely interesting essay on
art history  - and how history gets  changed, and art as  well, by the
"creative  industries".   I'll quote  here  its  conclusions, while  i
really suggest to read it in its completeness.

That the great artists of  modern Western culture managed to produce
what they did, despite the danger and intensity of their effort, was
due in large part to improvised social forms built around close-knit
networks where thought and affect circulated with high velocity, and
where it  was possible  to try out  forms of  non-conventional human
relationships that would not destroy, nor be destroyed by, a life of
art.

[]

In the second  half of the twentieth century,  many of the functions
of  these  networks  were  taken  over  in  Europe  by  institutions
(government funding bodies, universities,  museums, etc) and much of
their excessive feeling was neutralised.  This was only a small part
of a  general process of the  time: the absorption  of human emotion
into bureaucratic channels, and  the emergence of a social coolness,
an  efficiency  of feeling.  []  In order  to  arrive  at such  a
standardised,  manageable conception  of  creativity, much  previous
knowledge about this field of human activity must be sacrificed.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20Next%20Idea%20of%20the%20Artist</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Cyberpunk is not dead</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Cyberpunk%20is%20not%20dead</link>
<description><![CDATA[This year was the 5th edition of the Gogbot festival, this time hosted
by the city of Enschede and focusing on the "Steampunk" theme.

I went to speak about Cyberpunk culture and how it influenced and will
influence younger  generations worldwide.   Here you can  download the
slides  titled Cyberpunk is  not dead  which are  also linking  to the
video excerpts shown.

The whole  festival was amazing,  well realized and with  high profile
content as  the Singing Tesla Coil  installation in the  middle of the
town's  square. Cheers  to PlanetArt  for  organizing it  so well  and
choosing such an interesting and visionary topic.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Cyberpunk%20is%20not%20dead</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Governments censoring Internet</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Governments%20censoring%20Internet</link>
<description><![CDATA[It  seems that  "some  United Nations  agency"  is collaborating  with
governments as China to define  methods of tracing the original source
of  Internet communications  and  potentially curbing  the ability  of
users to remain anonymous.

The news  given by CNet is  really frightening if you  think about the
dangers faced by citizens  in totalitarian, dictatorial and repressive
governments.   Those  that  are  re-designing  the  Internet  in  such
directions  are responsible  for much  more (and  worst) than  a "safe
internet". That's  really a  human rights concern  and UN seems  to be
working against those rights now.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Governments%20censoring%20Internet</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>IT wisdom in facilities</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#IT%20wisdom%20in%20facilities</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today's   spot  is   an   interesting  article   on  InfoWorld   about
Why  IT should get  in the  facilities business.

It states  that IT's emerging  challenge is to help  businesses reduce
energy usage as  prices rise, a familiar vision  for all those knowing
how  the free software  movement has  traced several  "green" patterns
with its development.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#IT%20wisdom%20in%20facilities</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Free online university</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Free%20online%20university</link>
<description><![CDATA[Slashdot reports  today that the  Stanford University will  soon begin
offering a  series of 10  free online computer science  and electrical
engineering  courses. All  the courses'  materials are  being released
under a Creative Commons license  that lets people download, study and
copy them  freely, just go grab  your knowledge, cheers to the SEE.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Free%20online%20university</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Network sync of videos</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Network%20sync%20of%20videos</link>
<description><![CDATA[It  is  now possible  to  have  multiple  sync-starters connected  via
network, scaling to virtually unlimited channels: this is the main new
feature of the latest version  of the IvySync software released today,
a free tool developed in NIMk for synchronising multiple videos to the
frame, see here the project webpage with more informations.

This achievement is a result of my R&D activity this year.




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Network%20sync%20of%20videos</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The state of scripting languages</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20state%20of%20scripting%20languages</link>
<description><![CDATA[A     few      days     ago     an      interesting     article     on
the current state of  scripting languages has been published, offering
an  useful  panoramic on  most  popular  machine  languages for  rapid
development: scripting  languages are  closer to human  languages than
programming,  what makes  them  very popular  out  of the  engineering
context, for example in media art.

To better understand the evolution  of such languages, might be useful
to confront this panoramic with an older account on the same topic, as
in      2005      was      published      another      article      on
the state of the scripting universe.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20state%20of%20scripting%20languages</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Solar powered ice maker</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Solar%20powered%20ice%20maker</link>
<description><![CDATA[An inspiring  project realized by  students at MAE  Solar Engineering,
the solar powered ice maker, in a prototype that could be developed as
an efficient alternative to refrigeration and air conditioning.

There  are  many places  in  the  south  where this  technology  could
dramatically improve the quality of people's life.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Solar%20powered%20ice%20maker</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Quebec is contested for antitrust in IT</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Quebec%20is%20contested%20for%20antitrust%20in%20IT</link>
<description><![CDATA[The   association   FACiL    "pour   l'appropriation   collective   de
l'informatique  libre"  has sued  the  government  of  Quebec for  not
considering local  free software initiatives when  acquiring IT goods,
basically violating antitrust principles.

From February to  June 2008, FACIL has noticed  sales of proprietary
software for more than 25 million dollars. These purchases were made
for  products offered  by large  multinational enterprises,  with no
regard  to  suppliers  in  Quebec.  These purchases  hurt  the  Free
Software  suppliers throughout  Quebec and  are an  obstacle  to the
development of  Quebec IT enterprises. FACIL  contests these methods
as the association believes they are illegal and unacceptable.

Nowadays it is widely known that a strategic Free Software utilization
in public administration  could create thousands of jobs  as well as a
significant decrease  in software licensing  costs.  However, Quebec's
public administration (and still many others around the World) refuses
to even consider and evaluate these options.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Quebec%20is%20contested%20for%20antitrust%20in%20IT</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Security doesn't exists</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Security%20doesn%27t%20exists</link>
<description><![CDATA[And that's yet another proof, this time coming from some of the higher
intelligence       circles        around       network       security,
disclosing a  design flaw  in the "border  gateway protocol"  (BGP) on
which most of the Internet infrastructure is relying.

You can download  the presentation PDF by Kapela  and Pilosov from the
latest  DEFCON  hackers conference,  although  it  was a  little-known
problem since a dozen years,  I remember also some security experts at
the first hackmeeting demonstrating it on Cisco routers.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Security%20doesn%27t%20exists</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Free software art</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Free%20software%20art</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today i  was happy  to find  out that Javier  Candeira, author  of the
article   Towards  a  Permanently   Temporary  Software   Art  Factory
commissioned  in  2005  by  the  software  art  factory  Readme100  in
Dortmund, has started an  interesting and hopefully growing website on
freesoftwareart.org.

I was already  planning to update and expand  the "culture" section on
dyne.org  website to  feature more  "free software  art"  and Javier's
initiative comes right  to the spot. Cheers.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Free%20software%20art</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Colpo grosso al Best Western</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Colpo%20grosso%20al%20Best%20Western</link>
<description><![CDATA[Journalists call it the  biggest cyber-theft case already an estimated
8 million people's bank and  personal information has been stolen from
the Best Western hotels databases to  be sold to russian mafia, as the
Sunday Herald scoop reports.

Wow, it almost sounds like cold war.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Colpo%20grosso%20al%20Best%20Western</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Aussie patent on pizza baked solar cells?</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Aussie%20patent%20on%20pizza%20baked%20solar%20cells%3F</link>
<description><![CDATA[Nicole    Kuepper    today    announced    the    discovery    of    a
method to bake solar cells in a pizza owen using just some nail polish
and an inkjet printer.

Sounds good :) cheers to Nicole - but please now tell the world how!

Unfortunately there is no manual: just a loud announcement with prizes
and  national propaganda, while  the article  talks about  a patenting
process  that is  going  to take  five  years before  the "secret"  is
revealed. I hope not.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Aussie%20patent%20on%20pizza%20baked%20solar%20cells%3F</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>General-purpose computation with GPUs</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#General%2Dpurpose%20computation%20with%20GPUs</link>
<description><![CDATA[The GPGPU  website introduces  the efforts of  a few people  trying to
re-use  accelerated graphic  hardware for  generic tasks,  using GPUs:
CPUs built for graphics  they compute eh.

Today     there     was      a     buzz     on     slashdot,     about
"New  Multi-GPU Technology  With  No Strings  Attached, meaning  that
another company  is trying to  break in business with  a open-hardware
"no strings attached" product.

I think there can be a  good market for Lucid Logix and hopefully some
future for the GLSL  initiative, considering that the current monopoly
on  access  to  GPUs is  in  the  hands  of  Micros  guess  who  :)
appropriating the creations of young  asian geniuses as in BSGP by Kun
Zhou - with what they call "intellectual property".

I guess  dr.Zhou believes  they are  going to make  him rich,  what he
might not grasp  is that his money comes  from limiting the legitimate
liberties of users and developers who bought graphic devices and never
had the opportunity to use them as they want.

With  a truly  open platform  for multiple  GPUs (cheaply  produced in
large numbers as components of consumer products), the computing speed
of hardware  can dramatically increase. Unfortunately  what is already
available  by  ATI and  NVIDIA  cannot  be  (yet?)  recycled  for  the
purpose.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#General%2Dpurpose%20computation%20with%20GPUs</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Talking to &quot;Pirates&quot;</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Talking%20to%20%22Pirates%22</link>
<description><![CDATA[A Very  interesting post by  Positech game developer  Cliff 'cliffski'
Harris where he resumes his experiences in talking to pirates that are
copying his games.

Some  inspiring reflections  are  emerged, where  it  seems that  most
people pirating  games are concerned  about their quality and  tend to
pay them when they are really good and innovative.

More in  general Cliff  shows a very  good attitude here:  having such
open dialogues  instead of the same old  impersonal corporate attitude
help in understanding what we can  all do better for ourselves and the
people around us.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Talking%20to%20%22Pirates%22</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Italy is Fascist?</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Italy%20is%20Fascist%3F</link>
<description><![CDATA[That's what people at Pirate Bay think, and I would say they are right.

Let me  add that there was a  coup détat in Italy  just this April
but no  one really noticed:  Senator Cusumano fainted,  interdicted to
finish  his speech  on the  crisis  of the  Government, while  several
aggressions where having place in the Palazzo Viminale.

As a  result of  that episode the  second Prodi  government (moderated
left)  has fallen  and people  where  toasting with  champagne in  the
middle of  the Parliament, which is  not exactly what  you expect from
members of the government when their institution falls in crisis.

That's it:  in Italy  a coup  is done toasting  with champagne  in the
Parliament,  then the  "nation"  is taken  over  by a  filo-industrial
police  state  that can  be  easily defined  fascist  in  most of  its
instances  and  we'll surely  see  more about  it,  as  they have  big
problems with people openly speaking on the Internet


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Italy%20is%20Fascist%3F</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Weaver Birds</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Weaver%20Birds</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today was  an important day for  dyne.org hackers and  all our network
worldwide:   we   celebrated   our   8   years   of   existance   with
an important  document outlining our  Dharma: our dreams,  visions and
activities.

Some of us symbolically climbed vulcanoes around the world, connecting
our campfires between the Etna  and the Merapi, in a magical networked
ritual.

Many thanks  go to  anyone contributing to  this document, we  like to
think of it  as an new open magna carta for  all the tribes struggling
to go in our same directions,  while it will be corrected and expanded
in the future with all the contributions we keep on receiving.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Weaver%20Birds</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The end of Internet?</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20end%20of%20Internet%3F</link>
<description><![CDATA[Among   all  these  people   selling  governmental   consulting  about
cyber-crime, none of them is really aware of the damage they are doing
to humanity  by playing with  its fears and  freedoms. If it  keeps on
like that it's easy to guess  that we might be disconnected one day by
some I-Patriot act ready to be set as Lessig suggests.

Then  we'd better  settle some  plans  before that  happens: set  your
nuclear bunker online  :)  well even without  a bomb-like event, it
might happen that ISP's go  for complete commercialisation as it seems
some are already planning in Canada.

So please i2p2 and netsukuku and more alternatives: no fooling around,
set  a  roadmap,  emergency  simulation tests  and  procedures.   It's
becoming urgent.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20end%20of%20Internet%3F</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>ISEA aftermath</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#ISEA%20aftermath</link>
<description><![CDATA[I've  spent  the last  week  and  a  half in  Singapore:  facilitating
discussion     for      the     ASEF     mini-summit      and     then
presenting the dyne:bolic nomadic OS at ISEA2008 - and it was my first
time at ISEA, a conference that goes on since more than 10 years now.

I'll  note  down  my  experience,  as  a  "7th  generation  new  media
artist"  my feelings are so far  best resumed by Bronac and by this
excellent report by Brogan Bunt, while I still hope there will be some
more discussion around, so I'll just mention two more facts.

My written  contribution is  not even present  in the  ISEA catalogue,
even if  it was selected for  publication: Mircosoft DOC  was the only
format accepted (not pdf, rtf, nor anything else) and this excludes me
because of  my objection of  consciousness to its use.   Actually this
issue is an extremely important one in several countries especially in
the south of the World, but is neglected by the ISEA organisation that
uses proprietary formats for all documents in the conference.

Another astonishing  thing was to  hear Lev Manovich giving  a keynote
that was  basically advocating  data-mining in a  fancy format.   I am
horrified to  see that the media  art scene goes that  way (and that's
it, if you pay 20k SGD  to hear such theories) when it should actually
be  one of  the few  critical contexts  in respect  to  this worldwide
tendency to keep everyone under control.

Among  the few interesting  things printed  out I've  found a  list of
"Viridian Principles 2.0" at the Luminous Green workshop mentioning as
one important Moral Principle prof.Manovich might want to acknowledge:

Every  design process  is incomplete  unless it  takes  into careful
consideration what could  be done with the product  by a dictatorial
megalomaniac  in command of  a national  economy, secret  police and
large army.

Schade!  I never enjoy to be  polemical, but the need for criticism is
urgent here.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#ISEA%20aftermath</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>RIP Georges Lapassade</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#RIP%20Georges%20Lapassade</link>
<description><![CDATA[I just found out that a few  days ago: Georges Lapassade died. I had a
very intense  dream the night he  died. I'm not yet  up for publishing
dreams and I'll  never be, but well we were a  pirate crew settling on
an island and it all looked like a squat in Amsterdam.

If  you  are interested  in  rap,  education,  youth culture,  trance,
society  and ethnographic  researches then  you can't  miss  his work.
Unfortunately most  English speakers  know little because  of language
limitations.

Anyway   here   is   what    can   be   quickly   found   online:   an
interview in  Italian (1995), a French article  on psychologie sociale
and a collection of some of his texts.

His books are really worth to read. His mind will be missed.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#RIP%20Georges%20Lapassade</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Ogg/Vorbis/Theora player in Firefox</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Ogg%2FVorbis%2FTheora%20player%20in%20Firefox</link>
<description><![CDATA[This  news made  my day,  finally  we know  that the  next version  of
Mozilla  Firefox  will have  audio  and  video  tags to  easily  embed
multimedia content made with patent-free codecs.

Now  we  should really  push  FreeJ forward  full  speed,  it will  be
javascript programmable producer for multimedia content on the web.

We are almost there ;)

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Ogg%2FVorbis%2FTheora%20player%20in%20Firefox</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The limits of university education</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20limits%20of%20university%20education</link>
<description><![CDATA[Here an  interesting article  by Carl Wieman  (2001 Nobel  in Physics)
about the need for a new model for education in universities, worth as
a relevant addition to the discussion we had in Taxi-to-Praxi.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20limits%20of%20university%20education</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Secure your blog</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Secure%20your%20blog</link>
<description><![CDATA[Cats who code have some handy tips for wordpress users to avoid having
their website defaced, worth studying if you run your own WP blog.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Secure%20your%20blog</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Why mod game consoles</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Why%20mod%20game%20consoles</link>
<description><![CDATA[A little while ago Codejunkie made some very interesting points, while
explaining how  to modify  a PSP game  console to  run non-proprietary
software.  You  can read  the post here,  among the technical  talk it
includes  some good  hints on  why we  really want  to own  every game
device we buy.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Why%20mod%20game%20consoles</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Homebrew on MP4 players</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Homebrew%20on%20MP4%20players</link>
<description><![CDATA[There is a wide range  of different mobile video players, usually very
small and cheap  (below the 50 EUR price range)  and some smart people
already found a  way to reuse them: the  spmp305x wiki reports details
and progresses.

I'll definitely  have one  around to  hack, they make  it up  for some
handy little screens  (usually 320x240 pixels) that are  now also able
to do generative video.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Homebrew%20on%20MP4%20players</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Nano data centers</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Nano%20data%20centers</link>
<description><![CDATA[The European Commissions 7th Framework Program (FP7) is working on a
project called  Nano Data Centers (NADA)  as part of  the its future
Internet initiative.

Now this is a very good plan! i just hope this will actually lead to a
working   implementation  (unfortunately  not   always  true   for  EU
projects),  but well  the people  involved seems  capable  and several
companies  are involved  too.  There  is an  article  on ComputerWorld
reporting  this  scoop  more   in  detail,  unfortunately  it  doesn't
acknowledges existing efforts in  the same direction, as hive networks
or netsukuku for instance:

NADA will seek to build  an Internet architecture that delivers data
from the edge  of the Internet using set  top boxes and Peer-to-Peer
technology, instead of  the network-centric architecture that stores
and delivers content from  data centers via Internet backbones. NADA
is proposing  a network of hundreds  of thousands of  set top boxes,
hugely popular in Europe, to be essentially split into two: one side
is  the user interface  side, the  other a  virtualised Peer-to-Peer
storage client  that stores and sends  media in the same  way a data
center would.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Nano%20data%20centers</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>More video input in FreeJ</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#More%20video%20input%20in%20FreeJ</link>
<description><![CDATA[I've finally managed to have a video input out of several webcams that
weren't supported by the Video4Linux API and most important we can now
get video out of the EEEPC embedded camera.

Libunicap is used for the task, working like a charm. Some more issues
to be solved with all  possible fourcc color-spaces around, but that's
just a matter of time and testing more cams.

If you  ever meet me  in a  coding mood and  you have a  webcam laying
around please offer it for an half-hour testing, it will help :)


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#More%20video%20input%20in%20FreeJ</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Playing the role of an immigrant</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Playing%20the%20role%20of%20an%20immigrant</link>
<description><![CDATA[Against all odds is a good  chance to experience life as an immigrant,
at least for once, in a well done game playable online.

I find  it a  good perspective, especially  considering that  the most
popular GTA4 game has specular similarities: you are an immigrant from
Albania starting  his criminal career  with the mafia contacts  of his
cousin in the new city he moves in. What is that for a stereotype?


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Playing%20the%20role%20of%20an%20immigrant</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Recycled urban architectures</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Recycled%20urban%20architectures</link>
<description><![CDATA[Thanks   to   Netwurker   Mez   for   the   link:   here   are   shown
7  adaptive reuse  architecture projects  that are  very  creative and
inspiring,  I'm particularly  amazed  by the  "house  inserted in  the
house", can't stop dreaming how villages could be resurrected this way
in the south of Italy.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Recycled%20urban%20architectures</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Finally someone blames W3C</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Finally%20someone%20blames%20W3C</link>
<description><![CDATA[I've matured a very critical opinion on W3C activity.

I actually  started with the  offer RealNetworks manager  Rob Lanphier
made  me in  2002 to  buy the  MuSE audio  streaming software  and all
dyne.org software  house, which  I promptly refused  as it  would have
meant  to close  all the  sources as  "Real Networks  doesn't supports
independent efforts".

What this  has to do with W3C?   well at that time  Mr.Lanphier was on
the W3C  board for the  "open" protocol SMIL  - a board  that, despite
being proposing  a standard protocol, counted all  members coming from
closed source companies.

That made it clear to me that W3C collaborators not only were ignoring
open source  technologies, but were  active in investing  for closing
the development of open source software competitors.

Now  a  good  insight  in  W3C's  faults is  given  by  this  article,
mentioning we should blame W3C for proprietary web developments.

It  would feel  much  better, being  an  European, to  not know  about
public funds as  the WAI-AGE paying off W3C  closed source agenda with
our tax money.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Finally%20someone%20blames%20W3C</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The siege of the Internet?</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20siege%20of%20the%20Internet%3F</link>
<description><![CDATA[This  summer the  visionary freedom  of  the Internet  is under  heavy
attack by "middle-age" institutions  and industries enforcing old laws
that limit our future and  install a climate of perpetual control over
data transferred on the internet.

A  discussion   including  people  from  Europe,   South  America  and
Middle-East  is hosted on  the bricolabs  mailinglist: while  FFII has
warned  about  the Soviet  Internet  plans  in  EU, in  Brasil  people
protests  against  a  new  internet  law  proposal  whose  dangers  are
explained (in portuguese) by the FSF in Latin America.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20siege%20of%20the%20Internet%3F</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Netsukuku discussed on reddit</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Netsukuku%20discussed%20on%20reddit</link>
<description><![CDATA[The Netsukuku project that our freaknet hacker tribe is developing was
reviewed a few days on reddit, not really a good moment for Alpt to be
busy replying questions while he is preparing his university exams :)

It is interesting to see  how certain people have prejudices accepting
a project that is made out of the well-known north-western "innovation
labs",  still they  might  consider that  as  of now  NTK  is still  a
well documented algorithm for its own kind.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Netsukuku%20discussed%20on%20reddit</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Open Source HD player</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Open%20Source%20HD%20player</link>
<description><![CDATA[The  NetFlix is  a solid-state  video player  marketed by  Roku, which
since today released  the full source code of  this interesting device
that  can  play out  several  different  formats  including HDMI  from
network video streams.

On  the other end,  it's been  a few  months I'm  hacking on  the TViX
4100SH model to get synced  video out of multiple connected boxes, but
despite  the lively community  around it  and the  fact the  system is
based on  Busybox/ucLinux, it's  SigmaTel playback chipset  (H.264 and
MPEG4 hardware decoder) is closed source.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Open%20Source%20HD%20player</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Secure, decentralized, user-to-user</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Secure%2C%20decentralized%2C%20user%2Dto%2Duser</link>
<description><![CDATA[This user-to-user could make a nice acronym as U2U :)

Anyway, i  got the scoop today  from Jeff, something  called CSpace is
out  and it sounds  like a  good plan  for a  cross-platform framework
mainly based on python

to  provide  a connect(user,service)  primitive,  similar to  the
sockets API  connect(ip,port). Applications  built on top  of CSpace
can simply invoke connect(user,service) to establish a connection.

on my  list of software to  be tried, just besides i2p and syndie.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Secure%2C%20decentralized%2C%20user%2Dto%2Duser</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>NDS homebrew for musicians</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#NDS%20homebrew%20for%20musicians</link>
<description><![CDATA[The  homebrew scene on  the nintendoDS  console unfolds  rapidly: here
createdigitalmusic.com gives an overview of NDS music apps, among them
a  very interesting implementation  of WiFi  MIDI to  remotely control
instruments.

People at Remain calm maintain an updated list of NDS music homebrew.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#NDS%20homebrew%20for%20musicians</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Foldable and throwable displays</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Foldable%20and%20throwable%20displays</link>
<description><![CDATA[More than  being a bright idea,  it is well implemented  by Johnny Lee
using tools available on the consumer  market.  I place my bet this is
envisioning the future of video on theatre stage.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Foldable%20and%20throwable%20displays</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Say NO to ACTA</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Say%20NO%20to%20ACTA</link>
<description><![CDATA[Back    in     Amsterdam    I'm    getting     worried    about    the
Anti-Counterfeiting Trade  Agreement, a  big threat for  free software
and a tremendous step backwards in media policies. Let's stop it!

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Say%20NO%20to%20ACTA</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Consumer B gone</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Consumer%20B%20gone</link>
<description><![CDATA[Tmp/lab  hackers  in  Paris  have  been releasing  this  amazing  hack
consisting  of an  MP3 file  that can  lock/unlock the  wheels  of new
generation shopping carts.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Consumer%20B%20gone</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Graffiti convention in Paris</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Graffiti%20convention%20in%20Paris</link>
<description><![CDATA[As  a small  break from  the HSF  today I've  visited  the Kosmopolite
graffiti convention in a park of Bagnolet. Very good mood.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Graffiti%20convention%20in%20Paris</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Hacker Space Festival</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Hacker%20Space%20Festival</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today I've reached the HSF2008 on  site in Paris, just in time for the
presentation  of  NUI group  on  how  to  build your  own  multi-touch
screen. And  there is  even an open  source library, to  be integrated
soon in FreeJ.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Hacker%20Space%20Festival</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Anti-corporate protests made illegal</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Anti%2Dcorporate%20protests%20made%20illegal</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today     Jamie    pointed     me     out    this     case    of     a
jailed  animal  rights activist  whose  only  crime  was to  setup  an
anti-corporate website.

A  similar case  is found  on  Indymedia Antwerpen  where an  activist
documented  the  responsibility  of  a  hunt party  firm  in  elephant
slaughter, the firm followed with a dangerous lawsuit.

Even before racist  laws, nazi regimes as the NDH  declared as a crime
the  act  of  criticising  the   state.   And  guess  what,  now  that
corporations count more than the state itself



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Anti%2Dcorporate%20protests%20made%20illegal</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>FreeJ 4 Leopard</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#FreeJ%204%20Leopard</link>
<description><![CDATA[Since today FreeJ is one  of the first FOSS applications streaming and
recording Ogg/Theora video on OSX.

Thanks to some  good time spent together with Xant  and V@ne, there is
now  a ready to  install binary  of FreeJ4leopard  that runs  on Apple
computers  with Darwin/OSX  10.4.

Only limitations  so far:  no live video  input from webcams,  no live
audio input from mic/line.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#FreeJ%204%20Leopard</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Mod chips are legal</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Mod%20chips%20are%20legal</link>
<description><![CDATA[Now  also  for   British  law,  since  an  appeal   court  ruled  that
mod chips  do not violate  copyright laws, declaring innocent  an Xbox
mod chip re-seller importing from Hong Kong to the UK.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Mod%20chips%20are%20legal</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>BBS nostalgia</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#BBS%20nostalgia</link>
<description><![CDATA[My BBS fetishism today lead to spreadpoint (or at least what's left of
it), with a  nostalgic ghost list of all  disappeared cyberpunk holes.
If you're  0ld sch00l you should  have phoned (ehrm,  boxed?) at least
one of them, eh!



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#BBS%20nostalgia</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Photoviewer hack</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Photoviewer%20hack</link>
<description><![CDATA[Hack-a-day     launches     today     some    good     ideas     about
recycling  photoviewers into video  screens, there  is also  an hacked
PSone monitor and most important an open source library called phack.

I think my next suitcase computer is going to have a screen ;)

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Photoviewer%20hack</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Homebrew your apple</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Homebrew%20your%20apple</link>
<description><![CDATA[I've just found  out about Leo4All, a modified  Darwin/OSX system with
wider hardware  support for homebrew apples.

The  minimum requirement  of  SSE3  enabled CPUs  (core  duo and  such
expensive new  stuff) is  a show stopper,  still it  opens interesting
horizons,       while      some      former       Apple      employees
think they are a clone now.

I  didn't reached  to make  it work  on my  recycled hardware,  I hope
someone does.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Homebrew%20your%20apple</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Frontiers</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Frontiers</link>
<description><![CDATA[Frontiers   scouts  and  border   crossers  is   the  topic   for  the
Sarai  Reader  07, among  the  others  two  good articles  by  Solomon
Benjamin and the No One is Illegal collective.

Tickling interests  for migrant issues, another  recent publication is
Tekno guerrilla by Fran Ilich.

All  worth reading:  migration  is  definitely an  hot  issue for  our
century, eh.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Frontiers</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Scripting in the bush</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Scripting%20in%20the%20bush</link>
<description><![CDATA[After    our    successful    coding    sessions   we    tagged    the
new  FreeJ 0.10 release,  publicly announced  and demonstrated  at the
LPM VJ festival in Roma today.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Scripting%20in%20the%20bush</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Free Software course in Art Academy</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Free%20Software%20course%20in%20Art%20Academy</link>
<description><![CDATA[I'm just out from 2 intense  weeks in Milano, where I've spent a total
of 24  hours together with  students of MA course  Digital Environment
Design in the new Academy of Fine Arts (NABA).

Here  is an  abstract and  bibliography  of the  course elaborated  on
Art, theories and techniques of Free Software.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Free%20Software%20course%20in%20Art%20Academy</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Freeframe on OpenGL</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Freeframe%20on%20OpenGL</link>
<description><![CDATA[Freeframe developers have  updated the video plugin API  to use OpenGL
and hardware accelerated shaders.  Sounds cool, the FFGL SDK is online
including sources for example implementations.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Freeframe%20on%20OpenGL</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>HACK.Fem.EAST</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#HACK%2EFem%2EEAST</link>
<description><![CDATA[It  appeared   online  a  blog  with  photos,   audio,  materials  and
interventions about the HACK.Fem.EAST exhibition in Berlin.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#HACK%2EFem%2EEAST</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Super Bertram</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Super%20Bertram</link>
<description><![CDATA[I've met Super Bertram in  Linz last year: a robotic snowpuppet living
an interesting  life roaming  around on the  back of its  inventor. It
also has  a phone on it, so  you can receive calls  from people people
that see  you in  the video  stream; it's all  open source,  made with
cheap  and  recycled  materials,  very  funny and  useful  to  connect
happenings.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Super%20Bertram</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Your very own water</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Your%20very%20own%20water%2E%2E%2E</link>
<description><![CDATA[It  might sound  gross, but  still i  consider it  a  very interesting
development on which NASA is focusing and even before them the Russian
space agency: obtaining drinkable water  from urine. Here some info on
Visionpost (italian), USA Today and Wired.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Your%20very%20own%20water%2E%2E%2E</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Yearly research reports</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Yearly%20research%20reports</link>
<description><![CDATA[I've  just finished  updating the  website on  nimk.dyne.org  about my
research  and  development activities  in  the  Netherlands Media  Art
Institute, complete with yearly reports - 3 years now, still counting.

I won't hide it is my  ambition to establish a R&D department focusing
on Media Art in the institute:  that's just an humble start, up to the
readers to judge how useful such a department can be.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Yearly%20research%20reports</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>8 years of dyne.org discussions</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#8%20years%20of%20dyne%2Eorg%20discussions</link>
<description><![CDATA[8 years  is a lot for us:  that's how old is  dyne.org. Struggling for
survival since the beginning and until now, one thing at least we made
sure in all these years, that nothing got lost.  So today I reached to
fix  the  mailinglist  web   archives,  now  fully  browsable  online,
searchable back to the origins in 2000.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#8%20years%20of%20dyne%2Eorg%20discussions</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Skype in court for GNU GPL violation</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Skype%20in%20court%20for%20GNU%20GPL%20violation</link>
<description><![CDATA[Hack-a-day         reports          about         the         upcoming
second  appeal for  a court-case  in  Germany against  Skype, for  its
violation  of GNU  GPL license  in redistributing  free software  in a
closed source product as the SMC phones.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Skype%20in%20court%20for%20GNU%20GPL%20violation</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>FreeJ going 3D</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#FreeJ%20going%203D</link>
<description><![CDATA[Definitely  the biggest  coding session  on FreeJ  ever, going  on now
since   two  weeks,   will  take   some   effort  to   round  up   the
change-log. Cherry on top:  Caedes (apricot project) got interested in
using FreeJ as a 2d renderer  inside Crystal Space and Blender, so now
we have python bindings and full opengl support.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#FreeJ%20going%203D</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Sugar fork from OLPC</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Sugar%20fork%20from%20OLPC</link>
<description><![CDATA[It is finally obvious to many that Negroponte's leadership on the OLPC
project    is   deleterious,    so    he   is    left   alone    while
several hackers  are discussing about continuing  the real development
on Sugar.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Sugar%20fork%20from%20OLPC</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>FreeJ improvements</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#FreeJ%20improvements</link>
<description><![CDATA[It's growing  fast, among the new features:  freeframe plugin support,
wiimote controller, sound parametrisation, openGL rendering and a huge
javascript api cleanup are in the making.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#FreeJ%20improvements</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>We'll move to GIT</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#We%27ll%20move%20to%20GIT</link>
<description><![CDATA[As Mr.Goil arrived in Amsterdam we started our FreeJ hacking week, but
first of all he blessed me with his knowledge of GIT.

I'm so  excited about this  new versioning system,  finally delivering
what  Subversion   promised:  now  we  can   really  challenge  widely
distributed development.

Of course git.dyne.org is now up & running.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#We%27ll%20move%20to%20GIT</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Time Based Text</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Time%20Based%20Text</link>
<description><![CDATA[Annet  Dekker has  published a  recent interview  on Time  Based Text:
another chance for revenge of literature in new media art :)

I'm receiving lots of positive feedback about it, thanks!

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Time%20Based%20Text</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Taxi to Praxi</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Taxi%20to%20Praxi</link>
<description><![CDATA[Going to the Taxi-to-Praxi workshop in London, plenty of documentation
on the next layer website.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Taxi%20to%20Praxi</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Babylon by bus</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Babylon%20by%20bus</link>
<description><![CDATA[Armin  Medosh published  the Babylon  by Bus  interview we've  made in
2006.

It's hard to make me blush, but he got almost there.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Babylon%20by%20bus</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>August baking a subtitled DVD</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#August%20baking%20a%20subtitled%20DVD</link>
<description><![CDATA[August has  just written a  practical how-to for  subtitles rendering,
with particular  attention at  the quality when  included in  DVD, see
aug.ment.org/dvd.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#August%20baking%20a%20subtitled%20DVD</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>XJadeo</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#XJadeo</link>
<description><![CDATA[Very  interesting to  meet  Robin Gareus  here  at NIMk,  while he  is
collaborating with  Lilia Pérez Romero to realize  her new interactive
installation  - he pointed  me out  his project  xjadeo: a  jack video
monitor for synchronisation over the jack transport.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#XJadeo</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>EU say no to p2p anti-piracy</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#EU%20say%20no%20to%20p2p%20anti%2Dpiracy</link>
<description><![CDATA[Europe Rejects Plan To Criminalize File-Sharing

Seems that campaigns as I Wouldn't Steal went through.

I'm  happy to  have contributed  somehow with  the Piracy  and Privacy
campaign last year.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#EU%20say%20no%20to%20p2p%20anti%2Dpiracy</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Soon in Cairo</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Soon%20in%20Cairo</link>
<description><![CDATA[Taking    off    tomorrow   for    Cairo,    will    be   active    on
workshop and screenings hosted by the Contemporary Image Collective.

While still in  Amsterdam I won't miss the  Perfect Present Continuous
screening tonight.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Soon%20in%20Cairo</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The Darkice guru</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20Darkice%20guru</link>
<description><![CDATA[At the  Territorial Phantom  opening in NIMk  I've met Akos.   We know
about  each other  by  the affinity  of  the GNU  GPL audio  streaming
software we have written, it has been striking to meet him in person.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20Darkice%20guru</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Sicurezza e Privacy</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Sicurezza%20e%20Privacy</link>
<description><![CDATA[I took the time to read through this publication by Vecna (in Italian)
about  security,  privacy  and  psychological  effects  of  terrorism:
written one year ago, still a very interesting analysis from the point
of view of a young security expert.

Now I'm looking forward to  the acts of the upcoming PRISE conference:
policies on  privacy and  security are core  issues for  Europe (which
might be later spelled as Your-Rope around my neck).


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Sicurezza%20e%20Privacy</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Politube goes GPLv3</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Politube%20goes%20GPLv3</link>
<description><![CDATA[Kuros  announces the release  of politube.org  website code  under the
GPLv3 (Free) license under the software name Tubix and it's written in
Ruby.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Politube%20goes%20GPLv3</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The Wrath of the Apple Tribe</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20Wrath%20of%20the%20Apple%20Tribe</link>
<description><![CDATA[In two interesting recent threads here and here slashdot geeks discuss
the "Church of Apple" and its zealot users.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20Wrath%20of%20the%20Apple%20Tribe</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Paralingua</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Paralingua</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today's       good       finding       is       one       of       the
most arcane-like generational language enginesmeaning  "Alienate  ungenial  go   gangrene."  or  "In  an  eager,
negligent analogue." ever seen online.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Paralingua</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Hacker Space Fest</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Hacker%20Space%20Fest</link>
<description><![CDATA[The /tmp/lab launches a call for papers for the first HSF:

The  goal of this  festival is  to bring  together people  from many
cultural  and technological  backgrounds and  from  different Hacker
Spaces and Autonomous  zones in France and Europe  (and from beyond,
if they can attend) to share and show what's going on.

Easy going, no  big sponsors or people lecturing the  masses, I bet it
will bring together  an interesting round of people,  as the spirit of
the /tmp/lab echoes the independent and autonomous way hackers like to
do things, looking at perspectives in art and creativity.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Hacker%20Space%20Fest</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Video graffiti and veejaying</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Video%20graffiti%20and%20veejaying</link>
<description><![CDATA[It was 2003  when at the first Piksel  conference Fukuchi Kentaro show
us how to paint on a wall using a laser pen, a projector and a webcam.

Shortly after,  the Graffiti  Research Lab made  it funky and  hit the
streets with the Laser Tag.

Now another  Tag Tool is stepping  on the scene, open  in software and
hardware, soon presented at Breakpoint 2008 - and I bet we'll see more
after that

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Video%20graffiti%20and%20veejaying</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Dirac ready for production</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Dirac%20ready%20for%20production</link>
<description><![CDATA[The Schrödinger project  has announced that it has  made available the
world's first high performance implementation of Dirac.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Dirac%20ready%20for%20production</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>RFID travel cards</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#RFID%20travel%20cards</link>
<description><![CDATA[The british Oyster card cracked, as reports Bruce Schneier and various
other sources.   Meanwhile the Guardian reports MI5  plans to datamine
the whole public transportation database (not just ask single routes).

As proximity to  suspects can be verified in  relation to anyone, this
will result in proliferating  more suspects, which also multiplies the
possibilities for false positives.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#RFID%20travel%20cards</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>PAD.MA video archive opens</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#PAD%2EMA%20video%20archive%20opens</link>
<description><![CDATA[PAD.MA is an online  archive of densely text-annotated video material,
primarily  footage and not  finished films.  The entire  collection is
searchable and viewable online, and is free to download.

The  PAD.MA project  is  initiated  by a  group  consisting of  three
organisations    from   Bombay:   Majlis,    Point   of    View   and
Chitrakarkhana/CAMP,     plus    oil21.org    from     Berlin,    the
Alternative Law Forum from Bangalore.

More  than a  good  initiative:  there is  even  some interesting  new
code. Jan reports:

Pad.ma  is  build  with  TurboGears,  the  site is  using  a  lot  of
javascript, some  jquery, data is stored  in mysql and  search is done
via solr.  GStreamer, mod_annodex  and several other Ogg related tools
are used for the video backend.

the code  is gpl  and can be  found at  https://wiki.pad.ma/browser or
https://wiki.pad.ma/wiki/Source

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#PAD%2EMA%20video%20archive%20opens</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Secret Rabbit improvements</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Secret%20Rabbit%20improvements</link>
<description><![CDATA[Erik       de      Castro       Lopo       updates      us       about
improvements of his  Secret Rabbit Code for audio  resampling.

It's good news,  as this new release will refine  audio quality of the
majority of GNU/Linux audio applications around: his library is widely
adopted by free software developers.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Secret%20Rabbit%20improvements</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Online profiling and privacy</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Online%20profiling%20and%20privacy</link>
<description><![CDATA[An  interesting  article came  out yesterday  on the  New  York Times,
providing a comprehensive survey on "consumer profiling" and privacy.

Graphs are interesting, I just wonder what makes Yahoo so evil.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Online%20profiling%20and%20privacy</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Apricot open game</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Apricot%20open%20game</link>
<description><![CDATA[The Blender  community strikes back with  a new project,  an open game
that looks very promising: Apricot.

Regarding Blender  games, Caedes has been  hacking for a  while now on
the integration of Blender and Crystal Space.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Apricot%20open%20game</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Digital games and poetry</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Digital%20games%20and%20poetry</link>
<description><![CDATA[Nestography  is   truly  enjoyable  digital   poetry,  especially  for
nostalgic  gamers. Some  game stereotypes  are deeply  rooted  in '80s
culture, I'm sure those who have  grown up playing in those years will
feel the tickling. The artist writes:

The problem  with video games is  that most of them  are trying very
hard to  engage you  without making you  feel anything []  .  The
problem with me  and video games is  that I want them to  love me as
much as I love them and they  can't, so I have to fill in the blanks
myself. - Adam Mathes


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Digital%20games%20and%20poetry</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Facebook censorship</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Facebook%20censorship</link>
<description><![CDATA[The  social  networking platform  Facebook  does  apply censorship  of
contents referring to its competitors.

I posted  a link to Yuwie:

Yuwie is a new social networking website that plans to pay its users
(sharing with them  the income of advertisement) and  does not claim
any  ownership rights  on the  materials uploaded.

As  more social  networking tools  are coming  up, I'm  wondering if
we'll stay lazy and owned by facebook, or move

which was  automatically removed  from the post  as soon as  i pressed
submit.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Facebook%20censorship</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Butchered From inside 14-dev-08</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Butchered%20From%20inside%2014%2Ddev%2D08</link>
<description><![CDATA[A new  issue of  the Italian  hacker's e-zine is  out, with  the title
"Weaponize your SELF", you can download it from here.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Butchered%20From%20inside%2014%2Ddev%2D08</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Sub-200$ GNU/Linux laptop</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Sub%2D200%24%20GNU%2FLinux%20laptop</link>
<description><![CDATA[While Sony openly complains about the EEEPC market breaker, here we go
with a new sub-200$ model: the Elonex.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Sub%2D200%24%20GNU%2FLinux%20laptop</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>New uses for old CRT monitors</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#New%20uses%20for%20old%20CRT%20monitors</link>
<description><![CDATA[As people  switches to LCD flat  screens, we have loads  of them lying
around: here are some ideas on what to do with old monitors.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#New%20uses%20for%20old%20CRT%20monitors</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>More EEEPC hacks in tmplab</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#More%20EEEPC%20hacks%20in%20tmplab</link>
<description><![CDATA[Here  we go  with Philippe  Langlois re-launching  my post  with hacks
on-going at tmplab in Paris:

OLPC Sugar on EEEPC
Backtrack3 on EEEPC
Sugar Xubuntu on EEEPC


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#More%20EEEPC%20hacks%20in%20tmplab</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Progresses on EEEPC hacking</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Progresses%20on%20EEEPC%20hacking</link>
<description><![CDATA[After extensive  testing in  my own daily  usage, the  "dyneee" kernel
release is  ready for public. I'm  just trying to  upload binaries and
sources (58MB  in total)  from hotspots in  Yogyakarta not  so easy
indeed.     Once    completed   it    will    all    be   online    on
ftp://ftp.dyne.org/eeepc

This is just  a start (the kernel actually)  for dyne:ee GNU/Linux (or
dyne:eee?). Main improvements on EEEPC factory default kernel include:

Wifi monitor mode (for wireless wardriving, kismet etc.)
Highmem RAM (to make full use of >1GB RAM extension)
SquashFS (allows use of read-only compressed filesystems)
CFQ scheduling and 300Hz operation (improves usage speed)
DM-Crypt (supporting encrypted filesystems with cryptsetup)



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Progresses%20on%20EEEPC%20hacking</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Wifi, VoIP and security news</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Wifi%2C%20VoIP%20and%20security%20news</link>
<description><![CDATA[Alberto Escudero-Pascual  announces the  release of second  edition of
book  on VoIP  and wireless  in  developing regions,  two free  online
resources are on voip4d.org and wndw.net.

Meanwhile  Jacob Appelbaum disclosed  his collective  research project
with       alumni       of       ITP       Princeton       University:
Cold Boot Attacks on Encryption Keys.

After all, it was worth to bike through all Jogja to get online today.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Wifi%2C%20VoIP%20and%20security%20news</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The Linux-Libre kernel</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20Linux%2DLibre%20kernel</link>
<description><![CDATA[Jeff Moe (BLAG GNU/Linux developer) writes:

The official "vanilla" Linux kernel from Linus that gets distributed
on kernel.org has non-freehttp://www.fsf.org/licensing/essays/free-sw.html software in it. [] After talking to
Jaromil from dynebolic, looking at the gnewsense approach (which has
to remove additional non-free  blobs that ubuntu adds), and debian's
approach I felt a single clean source tarball would be of benefit to
everyone  who wants  a truly  Free Linux  kernel.  This  new cleaned
kernel source has been dubbed "linux-libre".

Yep,  someone gotta  do  it.  Future  d:b  releases will  be based  on
the Linux-Libre kernel.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#The%20Linux%2DLibre%20kernel</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Who needs Vi$ual Basic</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Who%20needs%20Vi%24ual%20Basic%2E%2E%2E</link>
<description><![CDATA[when there is Gambas? A FOSS visual programming environment that is
simple, well documented, translated  in many languages, working on all
platforms and most important: free.

Today was out a new version.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Who%20needs%20Vi%24ual%20Basic%2E%2E%2E</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Property and heuristics</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Property%20and%20heuristics</link>
<description><![CDATA[More     slashdot     threads    coming     up     on    the     topic
Facebook, Google, and Intellectual Property.

Some time ago  i wrote on the bricolabs  mailing-list, after wondering
about a possible new search engine architecture:

[] the  possibility is open for a  campaign against "illegitimate
indexing"  claiming the  rights to  index your  own data  instead of
letting a third-party monopoly like google doing it (which right now
we all let, because we need to exist) []

something like:  i will  not be data-mined!  or go data-mine  your own
garden! :)

The issue of  DRM in libraries should be related  by the question: who
has the right to index public libraries? And here we go with the local
DRM  Elimination Crew  having a  successful demonstration  out  of the
Boston Public Library.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Property%20and%20heuristics</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Why GNU/Linux doesn't spread</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Why%20GNU%2FLinux%20doesn%27t%20spread</link>
<description><![CDATA[Quoting a comment by Migraineman:

Luke is  sitting alone at his  computer. He nervously  inserts a linux
Live CD  into the disk drive  and reboots. His  roommate, Chad, enters
from the kitchen.

Chad: Whatcha doin', Luke?
Luke: [nervous] Nothing!
Chad: Looks like you're installing linux.
Luke: It's just a Live CD.
Chad: You know, I've been into linux for years now.
Luke: Really? I'm just 
Chad: Yes?
Luke: God, I can't believe I'm saying this  I'm  I'm a little dual-boot curious.
Chad: Oh. Let me show you how to properly set the boot parameters on that Live CD you've got
(cue the "bow-chicka" music )



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Why%20GNU%2FLinux%20doesn%27t%20spread</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Economie 0 conf</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Economie%200%20conf</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://incident.net/theupgrade/economie0/conferences.htm

Should have  been interesting even  not being there I've  manage to
virtually introduce two friends:

21:00            Philippe Langlois
22:00            Hans Bernhard (UBERMORGEN.COM)



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Economie%200%20conf</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Hivenetworks launches street radio</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Hivenetworks%20launches%20street%20radio</link>
<description><![CDATA[Hive Networks street radio setup is out!

Hive is a  new concept that promotes "narrate  and publish" approach
to  employment   of  ever  advancing   computing  and  communication
technologies.   Assuming the  progress in  microelectronic (embedded
systems, DSP, etc), presence of public spectrum, and advance of open
source,  hive  is looking  into  the  emergence  of narrative  based
networks, functions of which  are defined by underlying platform, be
it   social  network,   (non)government  initiative   or  commercial
enterprise.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Hivenetworks%20launches%20street%20radio</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Art of Rent or *cough*cough* squatting?</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Art%20of%20Rent%20or%20%2Acough%2Acough%2A%20squatting%3F</link>
<description><![CDATA[Seems that urban planning discussions are coming up in the public this
year in Europe - finally!  - I wonder if any squatter will be talking
to masses.. Momo? :)

First was Amsterdam  at De Balie where this  interesting conference by
Nader Vossoughian about Otto Neurath Information and the Global Polis

(psst. psst. I have a secret passion for Austrian architects, sshh..)

Then soon the Art of Rent is happening in London.

Meanwhile a spectacular gentrification tragedy is going on in Istanbul,
for the gypsy neighbourhood of Sulukule.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Art%20of%20Rent%20or%20%2Acough%2Acough%2A%20squatting%3F</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Fun ways to use a webcam</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Fun%20ways%20to%20use%20a%20webcam</link>
<description><![CDATA[HasciiCam   is  featured   as  a   funny  webcam   software   tool  in
this article on Linux.com.

Reduce you image  to ASCII - By using  HasciiCam in conjunction with
an  ordinary webcam,  you can  stream a  text representation  of the
camera input in various ways. For example, you can set up a Web page
that reloads every second or  so.  That consumes less bandwidth than
an actual image, though  of course it's not exactly high-resolution,
but it is fun to watch. HasciiCam also lets you output single frames
into text files to create ASCII images.

Mmh.  Should really find the time to update that software eh.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Fun%20ways%20to%20use%20a%20webcam</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Frustrating build systems</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Frustrating%20build%20systems</link>
<description><![CDATA[Over and over  again, still should fix things  in freej's build system
(rusty autoconf/automake), which takes even longer than writing actual
code for  it.

I recall a mail where Graham Todd suggested me waf, should really have
a look at it soon or later.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Frustrating%20build%20systems</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Chinese Professor Sues Google</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Chinese%20Professor%20Sues%20Google</link>
<description><![CDATA[A Chinese professor is suing Google and Yahoo for removing all mention
of him in China.

"Google and Yahoo, of course, have  agreed to play by local rules in
China, upsetting many.   Legally, it would seem like  this suit has
little chance  of success  - but  I doubt that  he cares  about the
legal result. What  this actually does is to  call attention to his
plight - and on that front, it's clearly a successful strategy."



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Chinese%20Professor%20Sues%20Google</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Semantic networking to the masses?</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Semantic%20networking%20to%20the%20masses%3F</link>
<description><![CDATA[Some  people says  in  2008 we'll  witness  the rise  of semantic  web
services  and the  commitment of  Reuters to  tag the  world  seems to
confirm this prediction.

This top  down semantic  web approach suggests  the Quillian  model is
relegated to bottom-up and therefore easily neglected (oioioi!)

So far I kind of like Morla as a client-side application to let anyone
edit RDF files easily.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Semantic%20networking%20to%20the%20masses%3F</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>MIT plans for a new tcp/ip</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#MIT%20plans%20for%20a%20new%20tcp%2Fip</link>
<description><![CDATA[I've    Found     some    juicy    documentation,     mirrored    here
http://korova.dyne.org/i0.ieee.pdf

Porbably   It   would   be   productive   to  get   in   touch   about
http://netsukuku.org




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#MIT%20plans%20for%20a%20new%20tcp%2Fip</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>d:b soon on Das Computer Magazin</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#d%3Ab%20soon%20on%20Das%20Computer%20Magazin</link>
<description><![CDATA[com!  - Das Computer-Magazin would like to put the free-/ test-version
of Dynebolic 2.5.2 on covermount-CD.   It will be distributed with the
special issue "Security" of com!

Suppatoll!   There  is  a  Rijndael-256  hashed  SHA256  mechanism  to
automatically encrypt user's home in there.




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#d%3Ab%20soon%20on%20Das%20Computer%20Magazin</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Two AI Pioneers, Two Bizarre Suicides</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Two%20AI%20Pioneers%2C%20Two%20Bizarre%20Suicides</link>
<description><![CDATA[Slashdot reports the suicides quoting an article on Wired, but what is
most interesting is  the discussion thread.

Many creative people living in  capitalist societies are keen leave or
in the worst case suicide  as they "lack business sense": someone that
shouldn't be forgotten is peer to peer software developer Gene Kan and
the troubled life story of Phil Katz.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Two%20AI%20Pioneers%2C%20Two%20Bizarre%20Suicides</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Study says google distorts reality</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Study%20says%20google%20distorts%20reality</link>
<description><![CDATA[An  interesting study  has  been published  about  google monopoly  on
heuristics of information.

A  research team  led  by  Prof. Hermann  Maurer,  chairman of  Graz
University's Institute  for Information Systems  and Computer Media,
argues that Google is turning  into a new version of George Orwell's
"Big Brother"  - creating unacceptable  monopolies in many  areas of
the worldwide web.

Not only  online, but  also in  real life: most  of my  hacker friends
received offers to be assimilated. And me too, in December 2007 I said
no to Google  asking me an interview for  a software engineer position
at  Google  Search in  Europe.   I  thought  that even  accepting  the
interview would have meant data-mining my brain.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Study%20says%20google%20distorts%20reality</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Who owns Facebook?</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Who%20owns%20Facebook%3F</link>
<description><![CDATA[A  recent  article  was  published   by  the  Guardian  UK  about  the
"futurist" philosopher and venture capital behind Facebook:

The  real face  behind Facebook  is the  40-year-old  Silicon Valley
venture capitalist and futurist philosopher Peter Thiel.

A  philosophy graduate  from Stanford,  in 1998  he co-wrote  a book
called The Diversity Myth, which  is a detailed attack on liberalism
and  the  multiculturalist  ideology  that  dominated  Stanford.  He
claimed  that the "multiculture"  led to  a lessening  of individual
freedoms.  While a student  at Stanford,  Thiel founded  a rightwing
journal, still up  and running, called The Stanford  Review - motto:
Fiat   Lux  ("Let   there  be   light").  Thiel   is  a   member  of
TheVanguard.Org,  an internet-based  neoconservative  pressure group
that was set up to  attack MoveOn.org, a liberal pressure group that
works on the web. Thiel calls himself "way libertarian".

There are only three board  members on Facebook, and they are Thiel,
Zuckerberg and  a third  investor called Jim  Breyer from  a venture
capital  firm  called  AccelPartners  []   who  put  $12.7m  into
Facebook in April  2005. On the board of such  US giants as Wal-Mart
and  Marvel Entertainment,  he  is  also a  former  chairman of  the
National Venture Capital  Association (NVCA).  [] Facebook's most
recent round of funding was led by a company called Greylock Venture
Capital,  who put in  the sum  of $27.5m.  One of  Greylock's senior
partners is called Howard Cox,  another former chairman of the NVCA,
who  is also  on  the  board of  In-Q-Tel.  What's In-Q-Tel?   Well,
believe  it  or not  (and  check out  their  website),  this is  the
venture-capital wing of the CIA. [] In-Q-Tel's first chairman was
Gilman  Louie,   who  served   on  the  board   of  the   NVCA  with
Breyer. Another  key figure in the  In-Q-Tel team is  Anita K Jones,
former  director of  defence  research and  engineering  for the  US
department  of defence,  and -  with Breyer  - board  member  of BBN
Technologies."


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#Who%20owns%20Facebook%3F</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>FOSS and Art, content and tools</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#FOSS%20and%20Art%2C%20content%20and%20tools</link>
<description><![CDATA[I've been  writing a  long mail on  the Spectre discussion  list about
freedom and licensing of tools  and art.

The FOSS  movement is about  software tools: as many  other creative
tools, the importance  to be free (as in speech, not  as in beer) is
related to the autonomy and  independence of productive use - access
to media production means - possibility to create local economies.

It is a  captious error to relate the social need  of FOSS (and more
in general for an idealistic total freedom in reproducing production
means) to the strategy of  total freedom in content, especially when
freedom is  not a social  priority, but eventually a  viral strategy
for emerging statements.

Not  even   the  Free  Software  Foundation  enters   the  merit  of
distribution of art and cultural production, where a similar freedom
as  the  one  advocated  with  FOSS could  render  the  economy  not
sustainable anymore.

On the contrary, in case of  tools that are sensible to the people's
communication,  to the  expression of  their creativity  and  to the
circulation of culture, there is the need for a neutral, transparent
and modifiable framework of production shared by all.

If you consider  the case that a graphic  designer using proprietary
software  might find  it  difficult to  show  and reproduce  her/his
creations, you understand why the need for FOSS is urgent.

On the contrary, until just a few decades ago, it was much easier to
build  or borrow  a brush  and the  distribution of  a  painting was
mostly bound to logistical problems  and not licensing issues of the
canvas.

Unfortunately in the field  of cultural production nowadays there is
very  little public  support  for people  building  free and  shared
creative  infrastructures, while  there  is a  big  waste of  public
resources for  the statements of fewer  people affording proprietary
means for their cultural production: no wonder why the nature of the
project  opening  this discussion  is  antagonistic,  while it  also
sympathises with open source practices.

Together with my contribution to the Content in Context publication it
might be worth to reformulate all this into a new expiration..


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2008.html#FOSS%20and%20Art%2C%20content%20and%20tools</guid>

</item>

  </channel>
</rss>
