<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Jaromil's Research 2009</title>
    <link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html</link>
    <description>A diary noting down FOSS and tech related research, day by day findings and curiosities, collecting future and past thoughts.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <generator>Emacs Muse</generator>

Almost every  day I  dedicate 2 good  hours to research:  nothing in
particular,   just   looking   around   for   inspirations,   tools,
publications and what not.

Thanks go to the NIMk employing me in research and development.

This diary  is still  in fieri: some  links are scattered  and still
lacking comments, while  it will grow complete over  time, you might
be also interested to read the research diary 2008.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#20091215</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Deforestation satellite monitoring</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Deforestation%20satellite%20monitoring</link>
<description><![CDATA[An interesting  concern raises up from  an entry posted  on the Google
developer's blog:  monitoring deforestation is now  possible thanks to
wide access  to satellite  imagery.

This  pleasant  situation still  leaves  unanswered  questions on  the
influence  of  popular  perception   on  corporate  governance  -  and
massacres of  indigenous societies, coldly  put. But let's turn  for a
moment our attention to something  else: what is exactly "pleasant" in
this  situation?   what lies  behind  this  novel  enthusiasm for  the
universally available monitoring of anti-social behaviours?

Arguably the essence  of our enthusiasm lies in  the opportunity for a
ubiquitous  feedback  on   issues  commonly  considered  of  universal
importance - at the reach of everyone connected to the Internet.

I really love it, not just related to forests, but to a new image of a
world suddenly  becomes reachable, if not desirable,  when compared to
modern architectures of centralised control.

So why aren't we able to access the cameras in our streets? who should
be  entitled to  watch our  cities? considering  that  satellites were
available to a military elite  already since years and they never used
them to monitor deforestation


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Deforestation%20satellite%20monitoring</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>English Shellcode</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#English%20Shellcode</link>
<description><![CDATA[Thanks Shammash for pointing  out this witty paper: English Shellcode,
an  effort to  interpret  code into  English  language which  suggests
developments far  beyond its initial  focus on security  research.

The abstract recites:

History  indicates  that the  security  community  commonly takes  a
divide-and-conquer  approach to  battling malware  threats: identify
the essential and inalienable  components of an attack, then develop
stack protection  and NOP  sled detection. It  comes as  no surprise
then  that  we approach  shellcode  detection  and  prevention in  a
similar  fashion.  However,  the  common belief  that components  of
polymorphic shellcode (e.g., the  decoder) cannot reliably be hidden
suggests a  more implicit and  broader assumption that  continues to
drive  contemporary  research:   namely,  that  valid  and  complete
representations   of  shellcode   are  fundamentally   different  in
structure  than  benign payloads.  While  the  first  tenet of  this
assumption is philosophically undeniable (i.e., a string of bytes is
either shellcode  or it is not),  truth of the latter  claim is less
obvious  if there  exist  encoding techniques  capable of  producing
shellcode with features nearly indistinguishable from non-executable
content.  In this paper,  we challenge the assumption that shellcode
must  conform   to  superficial  and   discernible  representations.
Specifically, we demonstrate a technique for automatically producing
English   Shellcode,  transforming   arbitrary   shellcode  into   a
representation that  is superficially similar to  English prose. The
shellcode is completely self-contained (i.e., it does not require an
external loader and  executes as valid IA32 code)  and can typically
be generated  in under  an hour on  commodity hardware.  Our primary
objective in this  paper is to promote discussion  and stimulate new
ideas  for thinking  ahead  about preventive  measures for  tackling
evolutions in code-injection attacks.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#English%20Shellcode</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Defective By Design update</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Defective%20By%20Design%20update</link>
<description><![CDATA[A  mail-out  by the  FSF  today provided  a  nice  round-up about  the
DRM-free campaign this year:

2009  was the year  that music  DRM died.   But when  Apple's iTunes
store  went DRM-free  on music,  we celebrated  the  victory without
buying the hype:  Apple still uses DRM on  virtually everything else
they sell (movies, TV shows, games, audiobooks, applications, and of
course hardware) - itunes-drm-free

Ebooks and ebook  readers took off this year, and  so did the threat
of DRM on books.  When Amazon deleted copies of George Orwell's 1984
from hundreds  of people's ebook readers, we  collected thousands of
signatures   from  readers,   authors,   public  intellectuals   and
librarians demanding an end to ebook DRM - amazon1984

At the  same time, we praised  and promoted the work  of authors and
publishers who  do the  right thing and  keep their  books DRM-free,
like Harlequin's new publishing  house Carina Press, or the hundreds
of publishers who tagged  their work "drmfree" - carina-drm-free and
blog

Through all this, Defective by Design  is proud to be the only voice
saying  loud and clear  that there's  no such  thing as  "better" or
"friendlier" DRM.  No matter how many  devices it works  on, or what
"features" it includes  to trick people into accepting  it, DRM robs
us of our basic rights and insults human curiosityit needs to go.

If  you believe  that  the technology  we  use should  be free  from
arbitrary restrictions, the best way  to put that belief into action
is by becoming an FSF member.

FSF activity  for users and developers rights  really was determinant,
all doe  we still miss to  give artists better  answers and directions
out of babylon.

We're all doing our best. Next  weekend in Barcelona I'll take part in
a          panel           about          video          distribution:
TOPOLOGÍA, INNOVACIÓN Y POLÍTICA CULTURAL.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Defective%20By%20Design%20update</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>:</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#%3A</link>
<description><![CDATA[Carsten Agger on nettime
http://somethingmanky.blogspot.com/
http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2009/dec/05/climate-change-carbon-offset-copenhagen

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#%3A</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Internet of Things workshop</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Internet%20of%20Things%20workshop</link>
<description><![CDATA[Apparently with great  success, the first workshop of  the IoT Council
was held  in Bruxelles as a  Lift! event, seeing  the participation of
several EU  officials, rapidly capped to 100  participants already two
weeks in advance.

Council is a  loose group of professionals with  different ideas and
opinions. We sometimes differ and  will probably clash. We prefer to
host the full range of opinions on what will be a small avalanche of
disruptive innovations.  We do have  something in common  though. We
have  been  through  the  full  range  of  emotions  and  conceptual
breakdown  that   comes  with  grasping  the   territory,  the  full
logistical, business,  social and philosophical  implications of the
Internet of Things.

The  outcomes of  our  workshop Tools  for  mediation in  the IoT  are
resumed by this Human / Tech Mediation mind-map.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Internet%20of%20Things%20workshop</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Open Source business models</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Open%20Source%20business%20models</link>
<description><![CDATA[The latest Open Source column  on ZDNet presents the following article
by Dana Blankenhorn & Paula Rooney regarding business models:

Critics are always claiming open source lacks a business model.

In  fact it's proprietary  software that  is lacking  in imagination.
They have only one business model:

EULA  Ware: Give  me money.   Now go away.  It doesn't  work? Go
away.  You want  your money back? Read your EULA,  and go away. You
want to see the software? Go away.

This has the virtue of  simplicity.  People pay and you really aren?t
required to  give them anything.  But it lacks  a certain je  ne sais
quoi

Don't know  what that  is? You must  work for a  proprietary software
company.  (Go away.)

Telling people  to pay you and  go away worked for  an amazingly long
time. It sounds  like it shouldn't.  It sounds a  bit like theft. But
software is a  miracle, and for decades EULA Ware  was the only model
there was.

Open  source companies, on  the other  hand, they  have to  use their
imagination.  They  can't feed  people EULA Ware,  so they  must make
money in other ways:

Support Ware: Pay us money and we'll support the software. We'll
answer your questions. Or we'll try to. Over the phone, on the Web,
whatever. Pay  us enough  and we'll come  over. Red Hat  likes this
business model.

Product  Ware : The  software is free,  you just buy the  box it
runs in. Android phones use  this. So do some network routers. It's
number two, but with a bullet.

Cloud Ware : Our software is  in the clouds now. Pay us for what
it  does. The  money goes  into the  cloud. Later  it will  rain on
us. SugarCRM likes this business model.

Project Ware  : Need  something done?   We'll do  it  with open
source.  Pay us for our work, and pay us for the project. IBM makes
a ton on this business model.

SaaS Ware : Our software is SaaSy. You can rent it, by the hour,
by   the   month,  by   the   user.    This   is  wildly   popular.
Zoho uses it. So do many other companies.

Ad  Ware : This is  a free version  of SaaS Ware. You  don't pay
anything, the advertiser pays instead. Heard of The Google? This is
their primary business model. ZDNet also uses this business model.

Sugar Daddy  Ware : Our software has a  sugar daddy. Firefox has
Google. Eclipse  has IBM. Open Office  has Sun, or it  did. So just
use the stuff. Daddy will provide. We believe in daddy.

Foundation Ware : Our software  has a foundation. It has lots of
sugar  daddies.  Want to  be  one? Linux  runs  this  way. So  does
Apache. Not to mention Wikipedia.

Beg Ware : Please give us  money. We know you don?t have to. But
give us  money anyway.  Lots of little  projects use  this business
model. Or pretend to.

Tchotchke Ware  : Wanna  buy a  t-shirt? How  about  a bumper
sticker? A pen?

Let's Make a Deal Ware : The programmers who wrote the software
support  it out  of their  own pockets  until they  can  figure out
something.   Wordpress started  this  way.  So  did  Drupal. Go  by
Sourceforge and you?ll find tons of folks still using this business
model.

The great thing  about open source is you don't have  to use just one
business  model.  You  can mix-and-match  as  you see  fit.  You  can
change. You can go to a more profitable model and buy a suit, or fork
the code and go down the stack.

This is what  freedom is about. It's about  having choices. You don't
have to  go to Sand Hill Road  to get into the  software business. If
they tell  you to go away, go  open source and in  time maybe they'll
call you.

Then you can tell them to go away.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Open%20Source%20business%20models</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Corpus building for minority languages</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Corpus%20building%20for%20minority%20languages</link>
<description><![CDATA[A  bit  of  curiosity  about  the state  of  ispell  dictionaries  and
independent work done in language research today lead to An Crúbadán a
web  crawler doing  automatic development  of large  text  corpora for
minority languages.

It has been around for a  while, wondering if it's also thanks to this
research  that Google  today offers  an amazing  range  of translation
possibilities between languages.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Corpus%20building%20for%20minority%20languages</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Stubnitz: free Amsterdam?</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Stubnitz%3A%20free%20Amsterdam%3F</link>
<description><![CDATA[A  petition is  out  to free  the  historical Stubnitz  boat from  the
neo-prohibitionist  wave hitting  the city  of Amsterdam.   This  is a
paradox for such an historical  free culture harbour in Europe, but we
must admit  that Mokum A is  showing signals of decline  since a while
now.

For centuries  Amsterdam was  proud of being  a tolerant  city.  Its
recent vertrutting undermines this.

MS Stubnitz, 'the  ship of 100 subcultures', is  a representative of
the diverse  and tolerant cultural spirit of  Amsterdam.  For unjust
reasons  the ship  has  been shut  down  by the  City of  Amsterdam,
leaving this  independent cultural hot-spot  and its crew  in limbo:
unable to operate the ship  and unable to leave Amsterdam.  The very
survival of the project is in imminent danger.

Please join  our protest in support  of the Stubnitz,  its crew, and
Amsterdam's onttrutting. *This event  will take place at Dam Square,
this Friday,  13 November  2009, from 15.00  till 18.00h.   A public
discussion on "vertrutting" and  "onttrutting" will take place at de
Balie, this  Saturday, 14 November, from 20.30  till 23.00h. Details
of the program will be announced on tolerantamsterdam.jjmdo.com.

Please   support  the   Stubnitz   by  signing   the  petition.

Details on the illegitimate closure  of the Stubnitz can be found in
the document Bezwaargronden" (in Dutch).

*Save the Stubnitz from capsizing!*

What  basically happened is  that police  smuggled a  dozen undercover
cops into a Saturday night party  held at the Stubnitz, the boat being
part  of  the  NDSM  cultural  evening  program,  an  industrial  area
converted to  art and  entertainment, subsidised by  creative industry
funds.

The  silent cops  took just  notes during  the party,  emphasising the
"drug  abuse"  happening.  The  day  after,  their anonymously  signed
memorial depicted  the boat as a  place of perdition for  the youth of
Amsterdam, justifying its seizing.

If you  know Amsterdam you know  how ridiculous this is,  a trick that
could be played on a vast number of public places on a Saturday night,
nevertheless  the  cultural  and  political  significance  of  the  MS
Stubnitz seems  a defined target for the  prohibitionist powers taking
over our city. Ai! Amsterdam.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Stubnitz%3A%20free%20Amsterdam%3F</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Memorable Mindfck code</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Memorable%20Mindfck%20code</link>
<description><![CDATA[Just found that Ku-ma-me posted some time ago an exquisite exercise of
recursively polymorphic  code in ruby  (Quine): it can  be interpreted
cascading across 12 languages



# ruby
l=92.chr;eval s="s=s.dump[r=1..-2].gsub(/("+l*4+"){4,}(?!\")/){|t|'\"+l*%d+\"'%(t
.size/2)};5.times{s=s.dump[r]};puts\"# python\\nprint(\\\"# perl\\\\nprint(\\\\\\
\"# lua"+l*4+"nprint("+l*7+"\"(* ocaml *)"+l*8+"nprint_endline"+l*15+"\"-- haskel
l"+l*16+"nimport Data.List;import Data.Bits;import Data.Char;main=putStrLn("+l*31
+"\"/* C */"+l*32+"n#include<stdio.h>"+l*32+"nint main(void){char*s[501]={"+l*31+
"\"++intercalate"+l*31+"\","+l*31+"\"(c(tail(init(show("+l*31+"\"/* Java */"+l*32
+"npublic class QuineRelay{public static void main(String[]a){String[]s={"+l*31+"
\"++intercalate"+l*31+"\","+l*31+"\"(c("+l*31+"\"brainfuck"+l*64+"n++++++++[>++++
<-]+++++++++>>++++++++++"+l*31+"\"++(concat(snd(mapAccumL h 2("+l*31+"\"110"+l*31
+"\"++g(length s)++"+l*31+"\"22111211100111112021111102011112120012"+l*31+"\"++co
ncatMap("+l*32+"c->let d=ord c in if d<11then"+l*31+"\"21002"+l*31+"\"else"+l*31+
"\"111"+l*31+"\"++g d++"+l*31+"\"22102"+l*31+"\")s++"+l*31+"\"2100211101012021122
2211211101000120211021120221102111000110120211202"+l*31+"\"))))))++"+l*31+"\","+l
*63+"\""+l*64+"n"+l*63+"\"};int i=0;for(;i<94;i++)System.out.print(s[i]);}}"+l*31
+"\")))))++"+l*31+"\",0};int i=0;for(;s[i];i++)printf("+l*63+"\"%s"+l*63+"\",s[i]
);puts("+l*63+"\""+l*63+"\");return 0;}"+l*31+"\");c s=map("+l*32+"s->"+l*31+"\""
+l*63+"\""+l*31+"\"++s++"+l*31+"\""+l*63+"\""+l*31+"\")(unfoldr t s);t[]=Nothing;
t s=Just(splitAt(if length s>w&&s!!w=='"+l*31+"\"'then 501else w)s);w=500;f 0=Not
hing;f x=Just((if x`mod`2>0then '0'else '1'),x`div`2);g x= reverse (unfoldr f x);
h p c=let d=ord c-48in(d,replicate(abs(p-d))(if d< p then '<'else '>')++"+l*31+"\"
."+l*31+"\");s="+l*31+"\"# ruby"+l*32+"n"+l*31+"\"++"+l*31+"\"l=92.chr;eval s=\"+
(z=l*31)+\"\\\"\"+s+z+\"\\\""+l*31+"\"++"+l*31+"\""+l*32+"n"+l*31+"\""+l*15+"\""+
l*7+"\")"+l*4+"n\\\\\\\")\\\")\"########### (c) Yusuke Endoh, 2009 ###########\n"
</stdio.h>

 ruby QuineRelay.rb > QuineRelay.py
 python QuineRelay.py > QuineRelay.pl
 perl QuineRelay.pl > QuineRelay.lua
 lua QuineRelay.lua > QuineRelay.ml
 ocaml QuineRelay.ml > QuineRelay.hs
 runghc QuineRelay.hs > QuineRelay.c
 gcc -Wall -o QuineRelay QuineRelay.c
  ./QuineRelay > QuineRelay.java
 javac QuineRelay.java && java QuineRelay > QuineRelay.bf
 beef QuineRelay.bf > QuineRelay.ws
 wspace QuineRelay.ws > QuineRelay.unl
 unlambda QuineRelay.unl > QuineRelay2.rb




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Memorable%20Mindfck%20code</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>ICT labour issues</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#ICT%20labour%20issues</link>
<description><![CDATA[Yesterday  Adobe  Systems  Inc.   fired  approximately  680  full-time
positions worldwide.

Meanwhile today  in Italy the ICT  company Eutelia Spa  is occupied by
its  employees on  strike  after not  receiving  their payments  since
months. Something that quickly escalated  as the owner of the company,
known         for          his         right-wing         connections,
organised a "private raid" to force the striking employees out. Nevertheless
the occupants resisted and are well determined to keep the place until
they'll have their rights respected.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#ICT%20labour%20issues</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The Anomalous Wave hits the Northern shores</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20Anomalous%20Wave%20hits%20the%20Northern%20shores</link>
<description><![CDATA[With thousands  of students protesting  in Austria and Germany,  it is
now clear  that the Anomalous Wave advances  inexorably across Europe:
it  crosses languages  as well  political and  economical differences,
uniting a generation of young  people increasingly aware of the rights
they are being negated and the future they are being stolen.

The "Unsere  Uni" movement both  in Austria and Germany  is blossoming
with various initiatives, a grass-root participation in youth protests
that can be hardly found in social-democratic-land and dulcis in fundo
lots   arguments   and   reasons   for  being   hungry   against   the
commercialization   of   culture.     Here   below   the   Allgemeiner
Forderungskatalog from Austrian students:

Antidiskriminierung:

Wir fordern antidiskriminatorische Betriebsvereinbarungen und
Anti-Diskrimninierung als Grundkonsens in allen Bildungseinrichtungen.

Das so genannte Behindertengleichstellungsgesetz muss in allen
Institutionen des Bildungswesens umgesetzt werden. Wir fordern
barrierefreies Studieren, Lehren und Lernen. D.h. beispielsweise
die Verfügbarkeit von Dolmetscher_innen zur Übersetzung in
Gebärdensprache sowie infrastrukturelle Maßnahmen für Menschen mit
besonderen Bedürfnissen, Bsp. Barrierefreie Räume und Lifte;
Wir fordern eine 50-prozentige Frauenquote in allen
Arbeitsbereichen des Bildungswesens auf allen Ebenen;
Wir fordern Quoten zur Förderung von Migrant_innen in allen
Arbeitsbereichen des Bildungswesens auf allen Ebenen;
Wir fordern Maßnahmen gegen Diskriminierung von LGBTQ-Personen
(lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender/transsexual, queer) und
weiteren Angehörigen systematisch diskriminierter Gruppen in allen
Arbeitsbereichen des Bildungswesens auf allen Ebenen;
Wir fordern gleiches Recht auf Mobilität und Bildung unabhängig von
Staatsbürger_innenschaft; Z.B.: Keine doppelten Studiengebühren von
Drittstaatsangehörigen sowie die Anerkennung von akademischen
Titeln aller Länder.

Demokratisierung der Universitäten:

Unser Ziel ist die demokratische Organisation der Universitäten. Dazu
gehört eine Demokratisierung der Verwaltung in einer Form, die
Professor_innen, Studierende, das wissenschaftliche und
nicht-wissenschaftliche Personal gleichberechtigt an der
Entscheidungsbildung beteiligt.

Wir fordern eine demokratische, selbstverwaltete Organisation der
Universitäten.
Wir fordern eine gleichberechtigte Einbeziehung aller vier Kurien:
Studierende, Mittelbau, Professor_innen und allgemeines
Universitätspersonal.
Wir sprechen uns gegen die Dominanz von Rektorat, Unirat und
Ministerium aus.
Wir bestehen auf der Zusammenlegung des Ministeriums für Unterricht
und Kunst und des Ministeriums fur Wissenschaft und Forschung.
Wir fordern die Abschaffung des Universitätsrates.
Wir fordern die Beschneidung der Befugnisse des Rektorats bei
gleichzeitiger Aufwertung demokratisch legitimierter Gremien.
Wir fordern die Abschaffung von quantifizierenden
Kontrollmechanismen wie Leistungsvereinbarungen und
Wissensbilanzen.
Wir fordern Budgettransparenz. D.h. die Offenlegung aller
Finanzaktivitäten und die demokratische Mitbestimmung bei der
Budgetverteilung.
Wir fordern die Rücknahme der ÖH-Wahlrechtsreform von 2004 und die
Wiedereinführung des direkten Wahlmodus.
Selbst-organisierte studentische Räume müssen geschützt und
unterstützt werden. Die derzeitigen Besetzungen zeigen die
Notwendigkeit des Austauschs und der Vernetzung in autonomen
Räumen.

Keine Ökonomisierung von Bildung:

Wir fordern den freien Hochschulzugang und die Abschaffung
ökonomischer Kriterien für den Zugang zu Bildung, welche den
strukturellen Rassismus und die soziale und ökonomische
Ungleichheit aufrecht erhalten, d.h. die Abschaffung aller
Studiengebühren und die Aufhebung aller weiteren finanziellen
Zugangsbarrieren im Bildungsbereich und zwar unabhängig von
Staatsbürger_innenschaft, Alter und Dauer des Studiums.
Schluss mit Unterfinanzierung, Wettbewerbslogik und Elitenbildung
im Bildungsbereich, d.h. keine Privatisierung und kein Ausverkauf
öffentlicher Einrichtung und Güter.
Die Qualität von Bildung und Lehre soll nicht durch
Zugangsbeschränkungen, sondern durch ausreichende Finanzierung im
Bildungssektor gewährleistet werden.
Wir fordern die Abschaffung prekärer Dienstverhältnisse im
Bildungsbereich sowie in der gesamten Arbeitswelt. D.h. keine
a-typischen Beschäftigungsverhältnisse wie freie Dienstverträge,
zeitlich befristete Verträge, Werkverträge etc. Die systematische
Prekarisierung von Lehrenden und Forschenden hat Vereinzelung,
Verunsicherung, Demotivierung und Konkurrenzdenken zur Folge.
Wir fordern die Ausfinanzierung aller Bildungseinrichtungen.
Wir fordern die Finanzierung von Forschung und Lehre in einem
Ausmaß, das die Beschaffung von Drittmittel nicht notwendig macht.
Wir reklamieren das Streikrecht für Student_innen und
Schüler_innen.

Selbstbestimmtes Studieren:

Abschaffung des Selektionsinstruments der Studieneingangsphasen
(STEPs) inklusive ihrer Knock-Out-Prüfungen.
Schluss mit den Voraussetzungsketten.
Freie Wahlfächer statt Erweiterungscurricula.
Abschaffung der intransparenten Anmeldesysteme.
Abschaffung der Deadlines für Sozialförderungen.
Die Beendigung des angefangenen Diplomstudiums muss gewährleistet
sein. Dazu bedarf es eines entsprechenden Lehrangebots und fixer
Äquivalenzlisten sowie der Aufhebung der bestehenden
Übergangsfristen.
Aufrechterhaltung aller bestehenden Diplomstudiengänge.
Gewährleistung der Anrechenbarkeit von Lehrveranstaltungen und
Abschlüssen im In- und Ausland.
Freie Zugänge zu allen Studiengängen.

Außerdem sprechen wir uns aus:

Gegen die Einführung der Zentralmatura.
Gegen ein autoritäres Beurteilungssystem in Schulen – Sitzenbleiben
abschaffen.

Geschichtliche Aufarbeitung:

Wir fordern die Erhaltung, die Förderung und den Ausbau kritischer
und emanzipatorischer Forschung und Lehre.
Wir verlangen die Restitution aller im Zuge der Shoa geraubten
Güter, die sich in „Besitz“ der Universitäten sowie anderer
staatlicher Einrichtungen befinden.
Wir bestehen auf der geschichtspolitischen Auseinandersetzung, mit
der Teilhabe der Wissenschaft und ihrer Institutionen, an
Kolonialismus, Faschismus und Nationalsozialismus.

Wir fordern freie Bildung für alle!

Wir fordern nicht nur einen Stop der Ökonomisierung der Bildung!

Wir fordern einen Stop der Ausbeutung in allen Lebensbereichen!



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20Anomalous%20Wave%20hits%20the%20Northern%20shores</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>RFID nest attack implemented</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#RFID%20nest%20attack%20implemented</link>
<description><![CDATA[Researchers    at   Nethemba    released   a    few   days    ago   an
implementation  of the  nest  attack on  Mifare  Classic cards.

We have analysed Czech/Slovak  most used public transport and access
smart  cards  (Bratislava  public  transport  card,  University/ISIC
cards,  parking  cards, Slovak  Lines  cards  etc)  based on  Mifare
Classic technology.  Using various technologies and thanks to public
available academical papers, we have demonstrated the possibility of
gaining all  access keys used  for the card content  encryption.  We
have  also verified  that these  keys can  be subsequently  used for
complete reading,  altering and  cloning the cards  that can  pose a
serious threat for affected transport companies.

Fairly well  packaged, this software progressively  discovers the keys
closing the blocks on the RFID cards, starting from at least one known
key  (commonly found,  as mentioned  by Roel  Verdult in  his "Classic
Mistakes" lecture) using the "Nested Authentication Attack" documented
by  the  paper  "Wirelessly   Pickpocketing  a  Mifare  Classic  Card"
published by scholars of the Radboud University in Nijmegen.

Theoretically this  is nothing  so new, nevertheless  this is  a fully
working implementation (and  fast, thanks to libNFC) that  can let you
crack Mifare  chips using  a 30$ cheap  touch-a-tag without  more tech
skills than compiling a small C  code. Tried on the dutch OV-chip card
today: it took less than 2 hours  to find all the keys of the card and
read out all its sectors. Wide open, quite impressive.

Nethemba's head of  research Pavol Lupták will soon  present in person
his findings at the upcoming Confidence 2.0 in Warsaw.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#RFID%20nest%20attack%20implemented</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The Ghetto Biennale</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20Ghetto%20Biennale</link>
<description><![CDATA[Definitely  the most  interesting  Biennale of  contemporary art  I've
heard of  this year,  at least judging  from the artist's  line-up and
surrounding statements:

"The  artists  use all  the  detritus  of  a post-industrial  global
economy  which uses  Haiti as  a  dumping ground.   They return  the
compliment,  creating astounding  bricolages  and assemblages  which
express  both the despair  and the  seemingly endless  creativity of
Haiti and Vodou. I have  visited their ateliers on Haiti's Grand Rue
on several occasions  over the last four years. I  have had a chance
to  see their  sculptures  as  they were  being  wrought from  their
desperate materials  in a scrap yard  on this wreck of  a street, in
this wreck of a city, in  this wreck of a country.  Saying all that,
I would also have to add  that, like Haiti, their sculptures seem to
express  the   boundless  creative  energy  of  a   people  who  are
simultaneously  the economically  poorest, and  artistically richest
culture in the New World."  ( Professor Donald Cosentino, World Arts
and Cultures, University of California, LA )

The Ghetto  Biennale, a  Salon des Refuses  for the 21st  century will
open  its doors  this year,  exhibiting among  the others  our beloved
hacker  stars   Nancy  Mauro-Flude  and  Jessie   Darling,  plus  more
interesting artists  like for instance  Ace Lehner and  Crow Cianciola
with their witty critical project called OINGO, about NGO abuse:

Our project  looks to the  ghetto biennale as a  counter exhibition,
disrupting  conventional art  scene exclusions,  as well  as  a bold
conversion of  global power systems, centers of  art production, and
cultural  transmission.  As  U.S.   artists proposing  to travel  to
Port-au-Prince, Haiti  to participate in  the Ghetto Biennale  it is
important to us  to be part of a  critical dialogue about globalism.
There are approximately 10,000  NGO's operating in Haiti, all backed
by the interests and finances of the US, France and Canada.  Many of
these NGOs  are immersed in agricultural  production.  The resulting
farms  are  part and  parcel  of  the  global industry  of  economic
assistance.  We  are interested in utilizing  tangerines and oranges
from  farms  that  have  become  part of  the  Haitian  agricultural
landscape through the presence of US funded NGO's.

Among the  other things  found in the  documentation of  this Biennale
there is  this fascinating warning  for those submitting to  the call:
"Artists should be  aware that Haiti has only a  50% literacy rate and
text heavy projects could be problematic for the local audience".


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20Ghetto%20Biennale</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The e-reader race</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20e%2Dreader%20race</link>
<description><![CDATA[In the  last few hours Amazon's  stock markets made  a remarkable leap
(approximately  +26% in  less than  24 hours),  on the  hype  of their
e-reader and the opening market of e-paper press.

It sounds quite logical as  Christmas approaches the western world and
the  e-readers   place  themselves  as   a  perfect  new   gadget  for
yuppies. Nevertheless it is a  bit too early to draw conclusions about
who    is     going    to     win    the    e-reader     market,    as
the Nook tablet  is coming up as well the  Asus dual screen EEE-reader
which is already rumored to be the cheaper and best.

And while  Amazon's Kindle deletes the  books from the  hands of their
customers, these other cheaper models seem to come free from DRM.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20e%2Dreader%20race</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Free Culture Forum</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Free%20Culture%20Forum</link>
<description><![CDATA[I'm honoured to be one  of the participants in the international Forum
on Access  to Culture  and Knowledge in  the Digital Age  organised by
Exgae, Networked  Politics and  Free Knowledge Institute  in Barcelona
from October 29 to November 1, 2009.

The Forum will be a major international meeting of the most relevant
world-wide  organizations   and  individuals  who   are  engaged  in
reflecting   on  the   social   and  economic   challenges  to   the
dissemination of culture and knowledge in the digital age.

While   governments  around  the   world  discuss   legislation  and
self-regulation,  the Forum will  articulate the  valuable proposals
that are  emerging from civil  society and find ways  of harmonising
the  recognition  of  creativity,  innovation  and  investment  with
people’s right to access  knowledge in a sustainable and cooperative
world.

The Forum  will be a space  in which to lay  down concrete proposals
and         articulate        the         work         of        the
more than 60 experts invited to participate.

The  Forum   continues  the  work  carried  out   by  civil  society
organizations  at  the Ministerial  Conference  “Forum for  Creative
Europe” organised as part of  the Czech Presidency of the Council of
the European Union in March this year (see attached abstract).  This
enterprise is  supported by the European  Commission’s Education and
Culture  Committee,  which  will  continue its  involvement  through
Official Observers at the Barcelona event.

Full  program  is on  fcforum.net,  Another  interesting  text is  the
Exgae paper  at the Forum for a  Creative Europe as part  of the Czech
Presidency.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Free%20Culture%20Forum</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>JAHTARI, RASTASOFT et al.</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#JAHTARI%2C%20RASTASOFT%20et%20al%2E</link>
<description><![CDATA[Tonight  it's show  time, with  an alchemy  between Reggae  Riddim and
8-bit, free software development  and Rastafari redemption. The gig is
hosted  by the Worm  in Rotterdam  and co-organised  with Moddr  - the
coolest hackerspace in the city.

Liberation  from mental slavery  in software  and hardware,  chips and
tunes.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#JAHTARI%2C%20RASTASOFT%20et%20al%2E</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Rich countries cut food aid</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Rich%20countries%20cut%20food%20aid</link>
<description><![CDATA[The      Guardian       newspaper      yesterday      reported      an
impressive  declaration  by the  head  of  UN's  World Food  Programme
stating that in a near future  several millions of people will be lost
to  malnutrition,   riots  and  political   destabilisation,  as  rich
countries  have  minimized  aid  funding  for  food  rations  in  poor
countries.

As extreme as it sounds, this  projection could lead to a reality well
defined  by earlier  analysis as  that  of the  Club of  Rome and  MIT
researchers. From the article:

This could be the "loss of a generation" sayd Josette Sheeran, head of
the UN's WFP, feeding aid food to nearly 100 million people a year "We
are facing a silent tsunami []  a humanitarian disaster".

Quoting some parts of the article:

The US, by  far the world's biggest contributor to  food aid, has so
far pledged $800m less than in 2008; Saudi Arabia has paid only $10m
in 2009  compared with  $500m in  2008; and the  EU has  given $130m
less.  Britain's promise of $69m this year is nearly $100m less than
2008, and, if nothing more is given, will be its lowest contribution
since 2001.

[..]

World food supplies are under increased strain this year following a
succession of  droughts, typhoons, floods and  earthquakes that have
destroyed crops in  Africa and south-east Asia. But  human needs are
also  greater because  the financial  crisis has  led  to widespread
unemployment.  In  addition, the remittances  from foreign nationals
living in  rich countries  to their families  at home are  20% lower
than last year.

Last month the UN said that the number of hungry people in the world
had increased by more than 150 million in a single year to more than
one billion. Aid agencies last  week warned of severe food shortages
in southern India after heavy floods damaged hundreds of millions of
dollars' worth of crops.

[]

This  is the  worst food  crisis  since the  1970s. We  will lose  a
generation. Children will never recover," said Sheeran.

More than 40 million people  could be affected by the WFP's enforced
scaling back  of its food rations.  Countries most likely  to be hit
include Bangladesh, where the budget is  likely to be cut by as much
as  50%, and Kenya,  where similar  cuts will  worsen the  plight of
millions of extra people made destitute by a long drought.

[]

"We are  making hard choices  over who to  feed.  We are  very aware
that  as we  dismantle  [feeding  programmes] it  may  take out  the
underpinning  of society  and leads  to  political destabilisation,"
said Sheeran.

"We are  very concerned  about the large  budget shortfall  faced by
WFP,  which means  the  programme has  to  cut the  food rations  to
millions  of people  who  rely  on this  assistance  for their  very
survival," said Fred  Mousseau, Oxfam's humanitarian policy adviser.
"This will translate  into more child deaths, with  more than 16,000
children already dying from hunger-related causes every day."

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Rich%20countries%20cut%20food%20aid</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>GNU Debugger 7</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#GNU%20Debugger%207</link>
<description><![CDATA[A new  version of an  important GNU tool,  completing the set  of core
applications necessary for software  development , has been released a
few days ago: the GNU Debugger (GDB) version 7.

A remarkable  improvement of this  new version is the  possibility for
debugging, so that  one can step backwards after  a break-point in the
execution flow.  This evidently implies a re-factoring of the internal
architecture of  GDB, finally achieving  a feature already  present in
other proprietary products.

In  software  development,  the  debugger  is  a  vital  tool  letting
programmers  dissect and observe  the execution  flow of  their source
code, inspecting the contents  of variable memory at certain positions
and at the occurrence of specific states.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#GNU%20Debugger%207</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Re-Imagining the City</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Re%2DImagining%20the%20City</link>
<description><![CDATA[In occasion of  a FreeJ workshop we've held in  De Balie Amsterdam, we
were      invited       among      the      audience       of      the
International Amsterdam  Film Festival an  extremely interesting panel
called Re-imagining the City.

The   projects  presented,  mostly   dealing  with   architecture  and
participative  citizenship,  are all  worth  a  look:  Gecekondu is  a
research  on gypsy  buildings built  over night,  Model Citizens  is a
framework  for   collective  planning   of  a  neighbourhood   by  its
inhabitants,   Lima  2427   is  a   creative  response   to   the  bad
administration     of     city     developments    in     Peru     and
The  Cook,  the  Farmer, his  Wife  and  their  Neighbour is  a  local
experiment  in  grass-root  building   of  a  public  space  with  the
inhabitants of the Geuzenveld-Slotermeer multi-cultural outer district
of Amsterdam.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Re%2DImagining%20the%20City</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Hotmail passwords leaked</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Hotmail%20passwords%20leaked</link>
<description><![CDATA[Time  is  proving that  hackers  were  right  criticising the  ongoing
centralisation of  communication infrastructures in the hand  of a few
mega-corporations  and  their  monstrous  server  conglomerations,  as
Internet grew into its "consumerist age".

This      is     the      time     of      hotmail      indeed,     as
as thousands  of passwords were  leaked online, exposing users  to the
black market of tapping, making their privacy an unfortunate victim of
industrial error.

What happens commonly is also the habit of using the same password for
various  Internet service accounts,  so that  this security  breach is
potentially   affecting  the  integrity   of  other   on-line  service
industries.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Hotmail%20passwords%20leaked</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Intersquat meeting</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Intersquat%20meeting</link>
<description><![CDATA[These days  an international meeting  of squatters is taking  place in
France  called Intersquat,  mostly  bound to  the  French and  Italian
experiences of squatting.

Still far  from being completed  with a more  international dimension,
the initiative is hopefully a  good start to represent the various and
inter-connected cultural activities of squats in Europe.

Also in  the Netherlands  is found a  valuable heritage  of squatters,
with people and places that  have been recognized for fighting endemic
phenomenons  of  house market  speculations  and  letting artists  and
migrants develop outside of the constraints of the capitalist system.

Just these  days the  Dutch Parliament hosts  an hot  discussion about
abolishing  squatting,  which  is  currently "protected"  by  granting
squatters the right for a regular court-case about their occupation of
private  property. The  documentary  Table,  bed and  chair  is in  my
opinion one  of the best explanations  of how this all  works, done by
many of  the friends  we have in  Amsterdam :)  we also showed  it for
curious hackers at HAR2009 in our village.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Intersquat%20meeting</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Abbenay Hackerspace Stockholm</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Abbenay%20Hackerspace%20Stockholm</link>
<description><![CDATA[The  global  Hackerspace  movement  is  rapidly  bouncing  initiatives
between USA and Europe this year, last but not least this new squatted
space in Stockholm called  "Abbenay", resisting to threats of eviction
and, what's  most important, making a  good point about  its reason to
exist. Here below a call of the hacker occupants which openly asks for
a  dialogue with  all players  involved,  including the  owner of  the
building:

The Abbenay  hacklab opened early  this month in Stockholm,  where a
housing crisis is at full blow.

We are set up in a place that was squatted downtown by Kommando Carl
Bildt since late August, called AK4. The house was empty since June,
and there was no plans to use it until one year and a half.

Unfortunately,  squats   are  very   unusual  in  Sweden,   and  the
discussions  with  the  landlord  and  the  city  of  Stockholm  are
extremely  difficult, even though  many newspapers  speak positively
about AK4.  The place currently  sets a record for the country, with
a life  time of one month  (and counting) while  most squats usually
get raided by the police in a few days.

We  are  however  facing  an  imminent eviction  threat  and  police
pressure has been significantly  increasing lately - with civil cops
coming very often to take pictures of the house and sirens waking us
up early in the morning.

This call is  asking you to contact the landlord  to show support to
the  hacklab  and  the  squat.  So  far, he  has  been  very  closed
minded. He only proposed that we leave the place and talked about an
expensive and abusive rental contract.   It was about a much smaller
office, and according  to which we would not be  allowed to sleep in
the premises,  we would  not be allowed  to host concerts,  cafes or
parties, etc.

The landlord is  Fredrik Winberg; he is the CEO  of Cementa AB, part
of HeidelbergCement  Global with a  revenue of 15 billion  euros per
year. He also runs the Biteam AB company.  We do not believe that he
or any  of his fellows will  turn poor should we  definitely get the
house  in Stockholm,  and we  think that  his behavior  is basically
motivated by  the capitalist idea  that the right to  stay somewhere
must always be paid for.

We hereby ask  you to contact him to expose  your views on squatting
and hackerspaces in  order to give him a  more comprehensive view on
the  subject   than  what  he   could  have  had  as   a  capitalist
entrepreneur. His contact email is fredrik.winberg at cementa.se and
he can be reached by phone at  +46 (0)708 25 68 04 (NB: this contact
information is available from the WWW).

We do  not give  a "copy and  paste" email  to send him,  since mail
bombing  would   probably  not   be  effective  and   only  increase
tensions. Also, please do not  be aggressive nor engage in any other
activity (defacing etc.) which would not lead anywhere.

Thank you,
The Abbenay Hacklab


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Abbenay%20Hackerspace%20Stockholm</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Sourcemap</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Sourcemap</link>
<description><![CDATA[Sourcemap,  "a collective  tool for  transparency  and sustainability"
developed at the MIT medialab has entered the public beta stage.


Simply  put: We believe  that people  have the  right to  know where
things come from and what they are made of.

Sourcemap is a platform  for researching, optimizing and sharing the
supply chains behind a number of everyday products (more info).

Looks like  an early attempt  for a quantitative analysis  tool within
the Internet of  Things framework, has a good  potential especially in
industrial  production  distributed  in  urban  areas,  still  doesn't
differs much  from previous  consumer association's initiatives  and I
believe its limits will be analogous. Still, an interesting initiative
and of course very well marketed. The mission reads like:

When  you invite  people  to an  event,  buy the  ingredients for  a
recipe,  or design  the  parts of  a  product, your  choices have  a
significant impact.

Some things  have vast supply  chains that stretch across  the world
while others are completely regional. Understanding the reach of our
sourcing   is  fundamental   to  improving   economic,   social  and
environmental conditions.

Sourcemap is a tool for  producers, business owners and consumers to
understand the impact of supply chains. Our site is a social network
where anyone can  contribute to a shared understanding  of the story
behind  products.  You  can  simulate the  impact of  manufacturing,
transporting, using and throwing  away products using our Life-Cycle
Assessment  calculator. This  web-based tool  uses linked  data from
geological and  geographic resources.  Each 'Sourcemap'  can be used
to help market socially- and environmentally- conscious products and
to buy carbon  offsets.  Supply chains published on  the site can be
embedded  in external  websites, printed  onto product  packaging or
linked  through QR  codes readable  by  camera phones.  As the  site
grows, suppliers  will be able  to contribute their products  to the
Sourcemap database, providing a geographic catalogue of materials

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Sourcemap</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>European Security Research</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#European%20Security%20Research</link>
<description><![CDATA[Living in an  European community where migrants and  asylum seeker are
captured in the jungle, there  are things I'd feel better not knowing:
the       1.4      billion       EUR       fund      assigned       to
European Security Research (FP-7 2009)  to move "towards a more secure
society  and increased industrial  competitiveness", whit  45 projects
declaring  to  fight  "more  terrorism, organised  crime  and  natural
disasters".

The  picture coming  out is  that of  a society  of fear  and control,
waging wars overseas and hunting  refugees at home, in a de-humanizing
spiral of projects like "Automatic Detection of Abnormal Behaviour and
Threats  in  crowded Spaces"  (ADABTS),  or  the  "BeSeCu" project  to
investigate cross-cultural  and ethnic differences  of human behaviour
in  crisis situations.   In the  100 pages  document linked  above are
found  key-phrases like  "monitor security  down to  the neighbourhood
level"  and "intelligent  information  system supporting  observation,
searching   and  detection   for   security  of   citizens  in   urban
environment", titles  like "IDetecT 4ALL" or  "SAMURAI", projects like
"TALOS" to develop unmanned patrol vehicles for border controls.

A  Kafkian  feeling  is  given  by reading  this  document,  while  it
represents a  succulent documentation to understand  the imaginary and
dialectic  of  European fears:  migration  and  terrorism are  closely
related, war threats can be  hidden everywhere, urban public space and
border  zones are  at high  risk, even  private spaces  are dangerous,
everything can be used against everyone.  I have no doubts this is the
scenario  of  a  collective  paranoid  mind, as  well  for  a  growing
generational conflict,  see the Freedom Not Fear  protests against the
surveillance mania.

Last but not least, all countries involved are actually European, with
two  exceptions:  Turkey  and Israel,  over-militarised  Mediterranean
countries  definitely  not   complying  with  European  standards  for
human-rights, still  receiving more security funds.   Should we wonder
how such advanced technologies will be deployed there?

Better not.   I'd feel  much better not  knowing all this,  maybe this
should  be the next  step of  Europe to  keep the  mental peace  of it
citizens:   seamless   control  and   secreted   plans  for   security
research. This  is the  sad paradox for  a governance that  can either
despotically and silently hide  an explosion of fear or democratically
and transparently implode in paranoia.

NeoConOpticon  -  The  EU  Security-Industrial Complex  is  a  related
publication  by  Ben Hayes  (Statewatch  and TransNational  Institute)
dealing with the issues I'm mentioning here. The colophon recites:

Despite  the  often  benign  intent  behind  collaborative  European
"research"   into  integrated   land,  air,   maritime,   space  and
cyber-surveillance  systems, the  EU's  security and  R&D policy  is
coalescing  around   a  high-tech  blueprint  for  a   new  kind  of
security. It envisages a future  world of red zones and green zones;
external borders  controlled by military  force and internally  by a
sprawling  network  of physical  and  virtual security  checkpoints;
public spaces,  micro-states and "mega events"  policed by high-tech
surveillance systems  and rapid reaction  forces; "peacekeeping" and
"crisis  management" missions that  make no  operational distinction
between the  suburbs of  Basra or the  Banlieue; and  the increasing
integration of  defence and national security functions  at home and
abroad.

It is  not just a  case of "sleepwalking  into" or "waking up  to" a
"surveillance  society", as  the Britain's  Information Commissioner
famously warned, it feels more like turning a blind eye to the start
of  a new  kind  of arms  race, one  in  which all  the weapons  are
pointing inwards. Welcome to the Neo-ConOpticon.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#European%20Security%20Research</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>GSM finally opening up</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#GSM%20finally%20opening%20up</link>
<description><![CDATA[This   year  at  HAR2009   i  had   the  occasion   to  try   out  the
Open  Source GSM  Network set  up in  a tent  nearby our  village.  It
worked, even with my 2nd hand phone which is more than 6 years old, it
was amazing to see such  backward compatibility and the huge potential
it has for developing countries.

As Alberto  puts it, we've been waiting  over 20 years to  make such a
phone call :) while Alejo is already setting something up in Colombia,
the  OpenBTS project  seems to  be the  main  reference implementation
running on USRP base stations.

This truly is a ground-breaking  development, despite the fact it took
too  long  to  come,  mostly   because  of  "security"  seals  on  GSM
communication protocols to endure the business of state monopolies.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#GSM%20finally%20opening%20up</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Hackmitin México</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Hackmitin%20México</link>
<description><![CDATA[Here below the call for the first hackmeeting of Mezo-America

The smoke signals are clear: RASTASOFTWARE Tribes are United!

De vuestra querida presencia, hackers do México!

CALL 4 NODES LLAMADA A LA PARTICIPACIÓN v.1.0


..:: conocimiento | tecnología | poder ::..
..:: compartir | construir | resistir ::..


9-11 Octubre 2009, México DF - http://espora.org/hackmitin


Este mensaje es  una invitación a participar en  la construcción del
Hackmitin  2009  para  seguir  tejiendo  una red  de  actividades  y
encuentros en torno al Hacktivismo, el Ciberespacio, la telemática y
sus dimensiones tecnopolíticas. Una red que se materializará durante
un intenso  fin de semana  autogestionado y libre,  en el ZAM  de la
calle Xola (Ciudad Monstruo, México DF) del 9 al 11 de Octubre.

Como ya sabrás, el HM es un encuentro participativo y gratuito en el
que  la dicotomía  organizador/asistente se  diluye en  el  deseo de
autogestionar el encuentro  colectivamente.  Entendemos el Hackmitin
como  una  red de  actividades  autoorganizadas (talleres,  charlas,
mesas  redondas,  exposiciones,  posters,  etc.) que  hemos  llamado
nodos.      Puedes       sumarte      proponiendo      nodos      de
trabajo/actividad/difusión.    Cualquier   persona   es   libre   de
coordinar, presentar, difundir un nodo dentro del Hackmitin: ÚNETE a
La RED.

Este  será el  primer  "Hackmeeting" que  realizamos  en México,  un
experimento con vocación  de permanencia a través de  la creación de
distintos Hacklabs y  de repetir el año que viene,  quien sabe si de
nuevo  en  la otra  ciudad  monstruo  o  en cualquier  otro  estado,
dependerá de  las fuerzas  e ilusiones que  veamos, pero esto  ya no
tiene  freno  decenas  de  hackers y  hacktivistas Mexicanos  nos
ponemos a trabajar  para crear y hacer crecer  nuestra comunidad, de
manera autogestionada, igualitaria, horizontal y, sobre todo, libre.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Hackmitin%20México</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Get greener with Carbon-Colonialism</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Get%20greener%20with%20Carbon%2DColonialism</link>
<description><![CDATA["Non  Governmental  Organisations"  hit  the market  of  managing  the
balance of  carbon emissions  with a "good  old colonialist  taste" it
seems.

As  reported  by  IPS  news,  the  "Forests  Absorbing  Carbon-dioxide
Emissions  Foundation" (FACE),  a Dutch  organisation involved  in the
voluntary  carbon  market,  has  generated controversy  as  indigenous
people in the Mount Elgon region  have been displaced to clear the way
for tree-planting projects.

Under carbon  trading programmes, companies  that release greenhouse
gases can either reduce their emissions  or buy the right to keep on
polluting, by paying for emissions-reducing projects somewhere else.

The United  Nations considers carbon markets an  efficient system to
guide  investments toward cutting  greenhouse emissions.   The Clean
Development Mechanism (CDM) established by the Kyoto Protocol allows
two types of forestry  offsets: reforestation of previously forested
areas and  afforestation, that is, planting new  trees where forests
have not existed for over 50 years.

Carbon trading is divided  into two separate markets: the compliance
market  - as provided  for under  the CDM  and the  European Union's
Emission  Trading  Scheme,  mandatory  programmes worth  32  billion
dollars last  year -  and the much  smaller voluntary  carbon offset
market.

Voluntary  carbon offsets  involve individuals,  companies  and even
governments  to pay for  projects to  mitigate their  greenhouse gas
emissions. These projects range  from wind farms and other renewable
energy  sources,   to  efforts  to  reduce   methane  released  from
landfills, to forestry.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Get%20greener%20with%20Carbon%2DColonialism</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Squatting in Prague</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Squatting%20in%20Prague</link>
<description><![CDATA[Indymedia  reports  violence and  police  repression against  hundreds
people in Prague, spontaneously willing to liberate an abandoned space
to put it in function for the community as a squatted social center.

Their declaration of intention follows:

This house  has been  chosen for several  reasons: it's  empty since
many  years, neglected  and  left to  disrepair.  Even the  smallest
reparation works has not been done  and the roof is then broken with
water coming in.  On the other hand, door and  windows are very well
walled up, so that nobody can live in here.

According to an auction report,  this house would be "an ideal place
to  build luxury  appartements  and commercial  spaces", that  means
another  victory  of  profit  and  not  the one  of  real  needs  of
inhabitants of the city, who  can see emerging luxury houses, but no
affordable  housing,  like  if  the  need  for  it  would  not  even
exist.  This  particular house  is  constantly  secured against  all
those, who don't  have a place to stay, because  it's there to serve
to  the rich  and for  the commercial  purpose, which  is  a process
happening  in the  whole  center of  Prague.  And it  is becoming  a
display window, deprived of any  sign of everyday life of those, who
can't afford the expensive housing and who don't go shopping in posh
stores.

The building  of the former  bathhouse dating back  to 1932 is  in a
complicated situation: the estate  agents, who own the house, cannot
dispose of  it, because it's  probably in a bad  financial situation
and the house is now used  as a guarantee. The house went in auction
in 2002, but unsuccesfully. It could  then fall into much of a worse
state in the  next few years or it can become  a cultural and social
space,  different  from the  uniform  Prague  centre.  A place  that
wouldn't serve only to those, who would live in there, but to a wide
public, who miss something specific in the town centre

Several  people  are arrested  and  injured  after  the attempt,  more
information flows via the website of the Milada collective.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Squatting%20in%20Prague</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Harder better faster HTTP</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Harder%20better%20faster%20HTTP</link>
<description><![CDATA[This autumn bring some interesting  new code for serving data on-line,
as two  new web-servers  enter a space  that has been  occupied almost
exclusively by Apache  for the last decade: Tornado  Web is the python
daemon used  at Facebook to  serve pages, released  open-source, while
nginx is a mythical Russian  implementation, also a small HTTP daemon,
very popular in the bot-net and embedded scenes.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Harder%20better%20faster%20HTTP</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>GTK Flow canvas</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#GTK%20Flow%20canvas</link>
<description><![CDATA[Just noticed this  new GTK widget: FlowCanvas, by  Dave Robilla who is
investing  his  valuable  experience  in making  this  shared  toolkit
component. His  previously named  OM-synth application was  sporting a
sexy patch panel already some years ago.

Code looks clean and well documented, we'll give it a go on top of the
new FreeJ engine.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#GTK%20Flow%20canvas</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Digital distractions</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Digital%20distractions</link>
<description><![CDATA[Web  2.0, mobile device  integration with  online services  and social
networks  brought   an  almost  overwhelming   load  of  distractions:
especially if compared to how browsing the Internet was ten years ago,
we are now constantly distracted by the connections available.

It's probably worth to look closer  into it from a psychology point of
view,    meanwhile    there    is    this    funny    graph    of    a
hierarchy  of digital  distractions depicting  the behaviour  of those
whom we call "IPhone and Martini  people" - no offence intended if you
are one, it's just such an obvious and neo-kitsch stereotype


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Digital%20distractions</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Geek Hero comic</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Geek%20Hero%20comic</link>
<description><![CDATA[This on-line  comic strip  is awesome: Geek  Hero comic  by Salvatore
Iovene,  it really hooks  up well  on the  kind of  irony of  the most
popular  xkcd, elaborating  in  an intriguing  way  on geek's  ethical
issues at work.

I'd recommend following this  comic strip to all computer programmers,
for entertainment and educational purposes.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Geek%20Hero%20comic</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Anti Advertising Agency</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Anti%20Advertising%20Agency</link>
<description><![CDATA[This is so cool: the Anti Advertising Agency, something Anne Elizabeth
Moore is  also involved - and  well, she is  so awesome you know  :)

The Anti-Advertising Agency co-opts the tools and structures used by
the advertising and public relations industries. Our work calls into
question  the purpose and  effects of  advertising in  public space.
Through constructive parody and  gentle humor our Agency's campaigns
will ask passers  by to critically consider the  role and strategies
of today's  marketing media as  well as alternatives for  the public
arena.   Our work  will de-normalize  "out-of-home"  advertising and
increase awareness  of the  public's power to  contribute to  a more
democratically-based outdoor environment.

I'm wondering if they  already surfed on Julian Oliver's collaboration
The Artvertiser,  he recently posted  some new demonstration  video of
the 0.2 version.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Anti%20Advertising%20Agency</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Hacking RFID</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Hacking%20RFID</link>
<description><![CDATA[Checking out a  "Touchatag" USB device bought at  HAR2009, is a decent
RFID reader (ACR122U), supporting ISO 14443  Type A & B cards - MIFARE
cards  (Classics, DESFire) and  Topaz NFC  Tags. A  low authentication
layer is  the SAM, implemented with  a GSM SIM sized  card holding the
unique ID of the reader.

The SAM or Secure Access Module  is an additional feature in a Smart
Card Reader  that can  enhance the level  of security in  your Smart
Card based application.  Normally card authentication is implemented
in PC or application level.  However with the presence of a SAM, key
diversification and mutual authentication can be implemented between
card  and  reader which  means  that the  PC  will  not perform  the
authentication but it will be done  via card to reader and reader to
card authentication making your system more secure and less prone to
hacking.

So I'm  finally owning something  to study RFID passports.   There are
collections of  government released MRTD public keys  on jmrtd.org and
rfidiot.org,  but  I  still  didn't   hack  enough  to  use  them  for
authentication.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Hacking%20RFID</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>WEB WEB BOY</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#WEB%20WEB%20BOY</link>
<description><![CDATA[Please  don't ask  me  this  journal  entry is  obnoxious for  most
readers and is  going to link a website heavy  on javascript that will
make  your browser terribly  slow down

anyway it is too cute and hilarious geeky nifty to be left out of this
journal: I'm talking about o--o WEB WEB BOY !


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#WEB%20WEB%20BOY</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title> Hacking at Random</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#%20Hacking%20at%20Random</link>
<description><![CDATA[Every 4  years in the  Netherlands is held  one of the  biggest hacker
camps in  Europe: this year it was  the time for Hacking  at Random in
Vierhouten, which  hosted about  3000 people for  4 days on  a camping
field 70km away from Amsterdam.

The event  was full of presentations, debates  and workshops exploring
recent  issues in technical  and social  aspects of  hacking cultures,
made possible  by passionate volunteers  who worked day and  night, as
well international guests of renewed fame.

As of today all the public  talks held at HAR are freely available via
the  website  www.rehash.nl,  gathering  an overwhelming  quantity  of
information that  can keep you busy  for days catching up  on what you
missed wether you have been there or not.

Most interesting  panels include  a presentation and  a debate  on the
Wikileaks project,  a panel  discussion on copyright  issues involving
BREIN, MPAA and  Pirate Bay activists, various updates  on privacy and
cryptography  technologies,  a scary  and  hilarious  overview on  how
insecure  are SSL certificates,  workshops on  lockpicking techniques,
reflections on governmental and corporate policy procedures as well on
labour  dynamics in  ICT and  open source  development and  much, much
more.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#%20Hacking%20at%20Random</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Incoming FreeJ 1.0 release</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Incoming%20FreeJ%201%2E0%20release</link>
<description><![CDATA[Together with various developers  and contributors and about 30 people
in the audience, we had quite  some fun yesterday in the FreeJ release
party,  celebrating the  new upcoming  release of  our GNU  GPL Vision
Mixing software, sponsored by the Dutch fund Digitale Pioniers.

We've used 15k EUR (plus a  5k EUR worth of facilities and hosting) to
support a team  of a dozen developers over a period  of 9 months. Most
of us  are living in Europe, so  this money was more  an incentive for
volunteering rather than an income,  but it served motivating the team
to achieve concrete results in an established time frame.

The  activity  is  resumed  in   the  git  log  and  visible  in  this
code swarm video:  it triplicated in volume between  November 2008 and
August  2009. We  have  major  enhancements of  the  engine thanks  to
talented coders  involved: Xant, Shammash, Robin and  Caedes among the
others.

In  brief now  FreeJ became  a library  with language  bindings, fully
cross-platform,  providing applications  with a  low-latency streaming
engine that can  be scripted in javascript and  controlled from Python
or  Ruby. A  couple of  new  graphical interfaces  are being  actively
developed,  mostly to  demonstrate  the possibilities  offered by  the
engine, like the Carbon version for OSX 10.5 and the script console in
PyGTK.   On  the  web  front  we  also  had  major  enhancements  like
integration with video RSS feeds (tested on DMMDB and Plumi CMS).

Lots  more can  be  done  from now  on:  broadcasting applications  of
various kinds, besides more debugging and adjustments on streaming: as
soon as Ogg/Vorbis/Theora playback is a stable implementation in HTML5
browsers we will  finally get rid of proprietary  technology in online
video streaming ;)

We will soon tag a 1.0  release, still conscious of known bugs we plan
to fix during the 1.x lifetime which should last one or two years. The
wide outreach given by OSX  and Debian packaging will help stabilizing
the engine and maybe gather some community funding.  Many TV companies
have contacted us so far about  collaborations, this is a good time to
make plans, we can adapt this new 1.0 framework to different needs.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Incoming%20FreeJ%201%2E0%20release</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Classics archive on-line</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Classics%20archive%20on%2Dline</link>
<description><![CDATA[A good  resource for classic  literature since long time  already, the
The Internet Classics  Archive maintained at the MIT  counts up to 441
texts of classic literature, mostly translated from ancient Greek.

I'm often feeling nostalgic for  such kind of readings, somehow a very
distant  prose from  what we  are used  to read  nowadays,  still very
inspirational if one knows where to look.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Classics%20archive%20on%2Dline</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Clean energy stocks</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Clean%20energy%20stocks</link>
<description><![CDATA[I'm not  really a  stock market guy  myself, mostly because  the whole
thing is  about exploitation of  labour which is  completely alienated
from  people's life,  a game  played  by armies  of mindless  egoistic
yuppies.

Still  it  is  interesting  to follow  market  analysis  commentaries,
especially when written by people with good experience on how decision
making  reacts to technological  innovation: Occidental  societies are
running on  "gov-less" systems where  the stock market  tendencies are
actually a valuable resource to interpret their rationale.

Here  is  a recent  article  on the  so  called  clean energy  economy
analysing with  good detail what  are the actual choices  of financial
capitals on emerging stocks, in the middle of these years' crisis.

Trying to read in between the lines, a resonating term as "smart grid"
is hinting the possibly collective nature of new startups.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Clean%20energy%20stocks</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Plumbercon</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Plumbercon</link>
<description><![CDATA[Attended Plumbercon in Vienna, mostly populated by hackers from Europe
and  USA,  animating  a  dense  series  of  talks  during  2  days  of
conference.

Worth  noting is  the presence  of Mitch  Altman with  a  new enhanced
version  of his  TV  B-Gone, the  Toool  lock-picking research  group,
various technical  "black hat"  presentations on systems  security and
forensics;  dulcis in fundo  a "science  rock-star" talk  quoting some
interesting projects like Theo Jansen's Strandbeesten.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Plumbercon</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Paper data storage</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Paper%20data%20storage</link>
<description><![CDATA[Paperbak is  a free software able  to store in an  efficient way (well
benchmarked  by this  article on  codinghorror) data  on paper,  to be
retrieved  later by  scanning the  paper and  processing it  back into
digital.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Paper%20data%20storage</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>HackIt 2009 - don't Panic</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#HackIt%202009%20%2D%20don%27t%20Panic</link>
<description><![CDATA[Out of the 11th hackmeeting held in Italy, a video documenting it came
out:  HackIt2009 -  don't Panic.   It is  mostly in  italian language,
collecting very good statements on  hacking, with a gallery of figures
that animated the community since its birth.

Having  participated  to  the  growth  of  this  community  since  the
beginning, and learning  a lot from it, it was touching  to see it.

This "digital  community" is coagulating  since more than a  decade in
the hackmeeting  gathering, held  in liberated squatted  places around
Italy, without a fixed organiser committee, in a truly spontaneous and
grass-root   spirit.    It   won   an   honorary   mention   for   the
Digital Communities award of the Ars Electronica Festival this year.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#HackIt%202009%20%2D%20don%27t%20Panic</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Generation M</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Generation%20M</link>
<description><![CDATA[An  interesting article  came out,  worth noting  - despite  being yet
another manifesto -  its title is Generation M  and describes well the
thoughts of a generation I'm also feeling part of.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Generation%20M</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Zero for Owned</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Zero%20for%20Owned</link>
<description><![CDATA[The hacker  e-zine ZFO came  out with its  5th issue "Summer  of Ham",
gaining lots  of popularity for the groundbreaking  publication of all
the "personal digital life" of  Kevin Mitnick and Dan Kaminsky, famous
showbiz hackers and security consultants,  hacked in a pretty lame way
in their very home.

The issue is really funny to  read, but you need to have some sysadmin
and  coding  knowledge  to  catch  the fun:  it  actually  realizes  a
wonderful  piece  of  literature  in  machine-language,  developing  a
narrative  exploring the  files of  the two  hacked-hackers  and their
techniques  to  keep  secure   their  websites,  and  those  of  their
customers.

Very nice to  see that someone is breaking  the ice of representation,
this is not an act of  terrorism rather than pure poetry declaring the
fact that Security doesn't exists and those selling it by the pound or
waving  it  at blinky  conferences  in  Las  Vegas are  just  decadent
puppets.

Here  below  an interesting  excerpt:



                                           |
                                       \       /            _\/_
     Industry check                      .-'-.              //o\  _\/_
                                    --  /     \  --           |   /o\\
  ^^~^~^~^~^~^~^~^~~^~^~^~^~^~^~^~^~^~^-=======-~^~~^^~~^~^~^~|~~^~^|^~`
     We don't talk to police                                        |
       We don't make a peace bond

The security scene  is fucked. You have Dan  Kaminsky lecturing you on
how DNS poisoning  will destroy life as we know  it. You have Matasano
harvesting talent  and critiquing everyone,  and then Ptacek  can only
announce  the release  of....a graphical  firewall  management client.
There's kingcope  killing bugs and dropping  weaponized exploits while
making no  other contribution  except putting a  smile on the  face of
kiddies. There's  iDefense and their competitors  selling exploits and
only doing  research in how to  make more exploits.  There's Jeff Moss
running a  conference under the hideous  misnomer "Blackhat Briefings"
where the same researchers search  for glory and present the same shit
year after year. There are people who just live press release by press
release. And on top  of it all, somehow you STILL have  not got rid of
Kevin Mitnick.  The industry cares  about virtualization one  year and
iPhones the  next, every  year forgetting the  lessons it  should have
picked up in the last.

If you are just someone looking to  pay a fair price to not get owned,
you find  out quickly  that none  of these people  exist to  help you.
Very few people in this  industry have their income model based around
actually making you  more secure. At best, some of  them have it based
around convincing you that you are better off.

The  very concept  of "penetration  testing" is  fundamentally flawed.
The problem with  it is that the penetration tester  has a limited set
of targets they're allowed to attack, while a real attacker can attack
anything in order to  gain access to the site/box.  So if  a site on a
shared host is  being tested, just because site1.com  is "secure" that
does NOT in  anyway mean that the server  is secure, because site2.com
could easily be  vulnerable to all sorts of  simple attacks.  The time
constraint is another problem. A professional pentester with a week or
two to spend on a client's network may or may not get into everything.
A real  dedicated hacker making the  slog who spends a  month of eight
hour days WILL get into anything  they target. You're lucky if it even
takes him that long, really.

Those things should all be  very obvious, but whitehats still make the
mistake of discounting them. Look at Mitnick. Every time he gets owned
he blames his host or his  DNS provider. If he's getting owned through
them, that's still his fault.  Choosing a host is a security decision,
it's  just like  choosing a  password. If  you choose  a weak  one you
expose yourself.  It's still your fault.

It's   the   same   with   outsourcing   the   development   of   your
security-critical code.  Mitnick could get  someone else to make him a
flashy website,  and then blame them  when it is full  of file include
vulnerabilities.  People do this  all the  time, indirectly,  by using
ridiculous  CMS  or  blog  software.  As  an  easy  example,  look  at
Wordpress.  Even easier,  look  at Wordpress  in  2007.  Horrid.  When
considering Wordpress, a blackhat starts reading the PHP, shudders and
giggles, and then laughs at the idea  of ever using it on one of their
servers. A whitehat never gets  that far apparently, they just install
it  and  get  owned.  I  simply  fail  to  see  how  leading  security
researchers run  all kinds  of code that  is blatantly  dangerous. Are
they really that bad at reading code? Or do they just not care much if
their passwords end up on  Full Disclosure? If it's the second option,
why is that?  Why can these people make a living selling security when
they make such bad choices? How do they maintain legitimacy? They take
less responsibility for getting owned than do the people who they sell
services to.

There's a popular term for people who don't read code.
We call them script kiddies.

You cannot outsource  blame. You HAVE to take  responsibility for your
mistakes, whether they are mistakes in your code, mistakes in code you
are using, mistakes by your host,  or mistakes in who you trust. These
are all  security choices.  Learn to control  this shit. Learn  how to
read code.  A lot of the  time it only  takes a very shallow  audit to
realise that the code is crap and  is bound to have bugs. In a smarter
world,  security professionals get  paid to  stop people  from getting
owned. End of. These is no limit to the scope of an audit.

Are you professional  types really this out of touch?  I see all these
papers about how to protect yourself from these super-fucking-advanced
techniques and exploits that very few people can actually develop, and
most hackers will NEVER USE. It's the simple stuff that works now, and
will continue to work years into the future. Not only is it way easier
to dev for  simple mistakes, but they are easier to  find and are more
plentiful.

The  whole concept  of full-disclosure  has backfired.  It  will never
work. It's some slashdot hippie pipe dream. Even you dumbass corporate
types should recognize this. If  you're constantly giving away all the
vulnerabilites you  find, for *FREE*  mind you (and what  other industry
does that?), and the vulnerabilites  get harder and harder to find and
exploit, it will  get harder and harder for you all  to do your "job".
Frankly, I'm  surprised that the non-disclosure  movement didn't start
in  the security industry  in the  first place.  In a  way it  did, by
default.   With full-disclosure,  the security  industry is  all about
show and  gloat, it is not about  fixing anything. A lot  of bugs have
been fixed  from it, but it comes  with the price of  an industry that
likes to cripple itself. Projects  run by teams of trained monkeys are
always eager to add more bugs to replace those that have been fixed.

We hate  the industry because  it is full  of shit. There are  so many
trolls like Kaminsky who just  desperately search for anything new, to
get  attention.   So  many  talentless  buffoons trying  to  scam  the
planet.  A   lot  of   the  actual  talent   out  there   is  severely
misapplied. It's  an industry  tied to news  and not  results, because
very few  of you can  even attain results.  When you can't,  who's the
wiser? Your  customers can  hardly tell if  you have really  made them
more  secure  or  not.   Sometimes  there  are  superficial  benefits,
sometimes there aren't. How do you convince the customer that they are
more ZF0-safe than  before, if they were never  targetted and probably
never will  be? And you all lack  the legitimacy to really  do the job
you should anyways. We can only expose so many frauds, the rest of you
can pretend you have changed something.

Very few whitehats  actually go out there and  provide a service where
they make people more  secure. Not just for a day or  a month. Are you
genuinely fixing  the underlying design and logic  flaws that generate
security problems for your clients or customers? If you actually clean
up every exposed security flaw  they have, will they still be "secure"
in six months or a year?

We could go on. Just in general, the industry is failing.
Flat out failing.
You cannot even protect yourselves.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Zero%20for%20Owned</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Farming under Fire</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Farming%20under%20Fire</link>
<description><![CDATA[Certainly  this  year   will  be  remembered  as  one   of  the  worst
humanitarian disasters  willingly caused by the  Israeli Defence Force
in  Palestine, including  bombing  of schools,  hospitals  and of  the
United Nations headquarters in Gaza.

Still as of  today the situation doesn't gets  better: as denounced on
the  website farming under  fire, farmers  are denied  from harvesting
their crops  by continuous provocations  and aggressions by  the bully
militias  of  IDF.   The  situation  seems to  escalate  pretty  fast,
following the incursion  of Abassan Jedida which injured  at least one
farmer and killed a donkey.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Farming%20under%20Fire</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Drug decriminalization in Portugal</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Drug%20decriminalization%20in%20Portugal</link>
<description><![CDATA[An  interesting  book titled  "Drug  Decriminalization  in Portugal  -
Lessons for Creating Fair  and Successful Drug Policies" was published
recently this year, written by Glenn Greenwald.

On  July 1,  2001, a  nationwide law  in Portugal  took  effect that
decriminalized all  drugs, including  cocaine and heroin.  Under the
new   legal  framework,   all  drugs   were   "decriminalized,"  not
"legalized."  Thus, drug possession  for personal use and drug usage
itself  are  still  legally  prohibited,  but  violations  of  those
prohibitions are deemed  to be exclusively administrative violations
and are removed completely from the criminal realm. Drug trafficking
continues to be prosecuted as a criminal offense.

The  objective of the  book is  to provide  an account,  complete with
empirical   metrics,   about   the   changes   occurred   after   drug
decriminalization in Portuguese society.  The conclusions are quite an
impressive lesson for future drug policies in Europe:

More  significantly,  none  of  the nightmare  scenarios  touted  by
pre-enactment decriminalization  opponents - from  rampant increases
in drug usage among the young to the transformation of Lisbon into a
haven for "drug tourists" - has occurred.

The   political   consensus  in   favor   of  decriminalization   is
unsurprising in  light of the  relevant empirical data.   Those data
indicate that  decriminalization has had  no adverse effect  on drug
usage  rates in  Portugal, which,  in numerous  categories,  are now
among the lowest  in the EU, particularly when  compared with states
with      stringent      criminalization     regimes.       Although
postdecriminalization usage rates have  remained roughly the same or
even  decreased  slightly  when   compared  with  other  EU  states,
drug-related pathologies - such as sexually transmitted diseases and
deaths due to drug usage  - have decreased dramatically. Drug policy
experts attribute  those positive trends to the  enhanced ability of
the  Portuguese  government  to  offer  treatment  programs  to  its
citizens  - enhancements  made  possible, for  numerous reasons,  by
decriminalization.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Drug%20decriminalization%20in%20Portugal</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Graph visualization</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Graph%20visualization</link>
<description><![CDATA[Just  found out  (thanks Itzhack)  a new  graph  visualization library
called Prefuse:

Prefuse is  a set  of software tools  for creating  rich interactive
data  visualizations.  The   original  prefuse  toolkit  provides  a
visualization framework for the Java programming language.

Meanwhile I've made myself fluent using both Graphviz and Ditaa.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Graph%20visualization</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Amazon's strings on your property</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Amazon%27s%20strings%20on%20your%20property</link>
<description><![CDATA[A     very     worrying      news     came     out     today     about
Amazon deleting  purchased books from Kindles. This  is very worrying:
strings attached to  purchased books in digital form,  so far that you
don't even control the deletion of texts on your own device.

It  is very  ironical that  this happened  first with  George Orwell's
masterpieces "1984" and "Animal Farm".

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Amazon%27s%20strings%20on%20your%20property</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Gypsies under siege in Belgrade</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Gypsies%20under%20siege%20in%20Belgrade</link>
<description><![CDATA[Belgrade's art  collective drugascena takes  part in Universiade 2009
with  a  strong statement  against  "intensifying  racist measures  of
Belgrade authorities in Roma settlements near Belville in Block 67":

Members of Druga Scena and friends will be permanent guests in these
Roma  settlements from  the opening  of Universiade,  Wednesday July
1st.  During   Universiade,  and  in   cooperation  with  ghettoized
residents  of settlement,  we  will organize  a  number of  informal
meetings,  art  workshops  and  cultural  programs,  culminating  in
cultural show and press conference on Wednesday July 8th

On June 16th 2009, a  wired fence was built around Roma settlements,
while security  and police “guard” it on  external side. Recently,
wire was covered  by promotional banners of Universiade  in order to
hide  Roma people behind  it.  In  addition, police  patrol operates
along the wire fence inside this settlement! Residents are forbidden
to  leave the  settlement, to  walk  the streets  near Belville,  to
gather  materials from  surrounding dumpsters  (which is  their only
source of  income). These  measures have limited  the right  to free
movement  and  the  right  to   work  for  residents  of  this  Roma
settlement.

Belgrade authorities  have ignored the  problems of Roma  people for
more than decade  including refusal to provide them  with basic life
conditions. Now they went  step further in discriminating our fellow
citizens,  using  the  security   measures  for  Universiade  as  an
excuse. By  building the wired fence around  settlement and imposing
police surveillance - city authorities have shown that they actually
don't want  to deal  with improving life  conditions of  people, but
just  improve media  image of  this city.   The main  goal  of these
measures is  to hide  the "shame" -  poverty and misery  Roma people
live in, from international guests and public.

We will not let humiliation  of our fellow citizens, nor forging the
reality. The true image of Serbia consists of images of Belville and
Roma settlements next to each other, the corruption on highest level
and  fired  workers, privatization  of  University and  Universiade,
sports event that  turned out to be more  important than human lives
and dignity.  We  demand that wired fence around  Roma Settlement in
Block  67 is removed  IMMEDIATELY, as  well as  to start  working on
finding appropriate ways to improve life conditions of the residents
of the most vulnerable settlements in the city.

No to ghettos in our neighborhood  for the "benefit of city"!  No to
Universiade  against human  dignity!  No  to authorities  that value
capital over  life of people and  use racist strategies as  a way of
management!

We invite all  interested colleagues from cultural scene  to join us
and help  realization of  cultural programs, art  workshops, cooking
actions, movie projects.

signed:  Drugascena,  Platform of  Belgrade  independent cultural  and
activist  scene.    Quite  a  powerful  blow  to   the  city  council,
considering  this critical standing  point is  published today  on the
main web-page of Universiade (and on nettime, BTW).


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Gypsies%20under%20siege%20in%20Belgrade</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Satellite navigation threatens local knowledge</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Satellite%20navigation%20threatens%20local%20knowledge</link>
<description><![CDATA[BBC  published   today  an   interesting  article  about   fears  that
Sat-nav  systems are starting  to erode  local knowledge.   It doesn't
really sound  like primitiveness, rather  than a worrying  argument on
how people  driving on sat-nav  ignore their surroundings and  loose a
certain  sense  of awareness  and  decision  making while  navigating.
Apparently this is not yet the case, as most frequent travelers aren't
relying much on their navigation device. Joe Moran writes:

We still don't  quite trust the electronic voice to  get us where we
want to  go. Since before even  the arrival of the  car, people have
worried  that maps  sever  us  from real  places,  render the  world
untouchable,  reduce it  to a  bare outline  of Cartesian  lines and
intersections.  Sat-nav  feeds into  this  long-held  fear that  the
cold-blooded modern world is  destroying local knowledge, that roads
no longer lead to real places but around and through them.

Local  knowledge is  an extremely  important feature  for any  kind of
self-motivated operation around a certain neighbourhood, especially if
planned outside  the given  schemes of an  architecture; but  it seems
that sat-nav  users are acquainted at loosing  information (and power)
over their surroundings, a new  sort of alienation.  Still we must say
that maps  of terrains at high  detail, similar to  those now employed
for bicycle navigation,  were once harder to find,  mostly provided as
military grade information.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Satellite%20navigation%20threatens%20local%20knowledge</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Society of the Query</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Society%20of%20the%20Query</link>
<description><![CDATA[The Institute of Network Cultures announces a new upcoming conference,
which  will  be presumably  followed  by  an interesting  publication:
Society of the Query to be held in Amsterdam on 13 - 14 November 2009.

In this  query driven society,  The Society of the  Query conference
seeks to  analyze what  impact our reliance  on resources  to manage
knowledge  on the  Internet  has on  our  culture. The  theory of  a
semantic  web  lurking around  the  corner  revives  the "human  vs.
artificial  intelligence" debate.  The  centralizing web  demands to
critically  question the  distribution of  power, the  diversity and
accessibility of  web content, while promising  alternatives for the
dominant   paradigm  surface   in  peer-to-peer   and   open  source
initiatives.  Finally,  the question  arises what role  politics and
education,   after   having    invested   substantially   in   media
intelligence, can play in the creation of an informed users' group.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Society%20of%20the%20Query</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Atari game sources</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Atari%20game%20sources</link>
<description><![CDATA[Great  news  for  retro-computing  geeks!  the  historical  game  firm
Atari has  released the sourcecode  of some of their  legendary games,
among them  Dig Dug,  Centipede, Joust and  Pac Man. They  were kindly
donated to  a so  called "Atari Museum",  while this move  arose great
interest by retro-computing collectors.

In an  official release,  Atari has quoted  that the purpose  of the
release  is to give  potential developers  insight into  the Atari's
gaming platform  so they  may possibly build  upon the  7800 series.

One step forward  towards the recognition of the  importance of museum
preservation of our digital past.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Atari%20game%20sources</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Hackerspace festival account</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Hackerspace%20festival%20account</link>
<description><![CDATA[Back from  tmp/lab in Paris, here is  a short account of  just some of
the interesting things  found among the talks. The  whole festival was
amazing -  I'd even say legendary  - and surely won't  be forgotten by
its  participants. It  challenged everyone  in the  making,  since the
place that hosted  it was in a really bad  condition, it required some
practical skills and good cooperation by all people present.

Food was really good.  It was delicious and nutrient.  Kudos to JNM of
craslab.org  and all  the volunteers  who  helped.  Big  kudos to  the
farmers who brought  us a 400EUR worth of  biological food (old-school
farming,  very  tasty  and  healthy)  that fueled  the  whole  5  days
festival.   Look up  the french  AMAP  networks, they  are an  awesome
alternative to the food industry  crisis.  There are times when even a
5 star catering can make you hug a toilet after two days of conference
food; considered  the conditions  and the tools,  this was  some magic
"heros feast" spell  casted twice per day, with  vegetarian dishes for
everyone, still filling up the diet very well.

Now  let's go  through the  content of  HSF: I'm  gathering  here some
interesting links  to things presented,  still sorry that  this humble
account won't cover all the interventions deserving it.

The Gaming Platform  Libre was a delight for those of  us who dream of
game  development on free  platform and  I must  admit I  wasn't aware
myself of the  many things being said, even  if usually researching on
the  topic.   The YASEP  platform  was  presented  (Yet Another  Small
Embedded Processor) and its instruction set explained, all accompanied
by these slides presented by Laura Bécognée and Yann Guidon.

A well  known cryptographer, Karsten  Nohl, has illustrated  in detail
the procedure  of reverse engineering integrated circuits  as RFID: it
was  quite  an  experience  to  hear  such a  talk  by  the  one  that
reverse-engineered  the  MiFare  -  CRYPTO1  :)

Among the  tools Karsten  mentioned a software  I didn't  knew before:
Degate  helps you  explore ICs,  matching logic  gates on  the imagery
given  by graphical  templates and  assisting you  in  tracing circuit
paths.

More on  the blinky side  of life was  the presentation of  Kiniou who
demonstrated  how  to import  Open  Office  presentations in  Blender,
taking  advantage of  a  3d environment  to  show your  slides. He  is
publishing this and other stuff on the website knokorpo.fr.

The Syn2Cat hackerspace crew from Luxembourg was present all the time,
animating  a blinkful space  in the  HSF as  well giving  an inspiring
presentation  of their  activities,  well oriented  to animate  public
spaces,  art  environments and  to  leverage  the political  discourse
around  civil   liberties.   Among  their  code  pearls   there  is  a
port of  LaserTag software on  GNU/Linux (finally!!)  and  their early
experiments with Clutter.


At the  core of  the theoretical  discussion in HSF  there was  a very
interesting presentation  of EGPL, a general public  license that lets
authors "exclude"  certain uses for  their creations. Under  the motto
"Creative  Uncommons License"  (acronym  CUL) and  the  symbol (*)  it
unfolded  extremely  interesting insights  on  licensing, ethics,  the
pitfalls of Creative Commons license  and in general a deep reflection
on  the use  values of  creations. I've  actively participated  to the
debate trying  to defend  the total freedom  granted by  classical GNU
licenses,  still   I  must  admit  that  the   EGPL  arguments  aren't
superficial as it might seem on  the first glance and, until a certain
degree, they might even be implementable.

From the  Swedish hackerspace  Forskningsavd a young  phreaking genius
named      Kugg     came      to      present     his      experiments
interfacing Arduino boards to phone networks: developing the so called
Optoshield  and,  *dulcis in  fundo*,  releasing  his  new creation  the
Arduino  Phoneshield -  all HSF  participants got  the  opportunity to
download the circuit  scheme of this new shield,  soon to be available
on  the webshop  of blushing  boy.  Feels  like back  to the  roots :)
the phreaking scene will never die.

During the  whole festival, the indefatigable  tmp/lab hacker lekernel
ran  several  workshops:  how  to make  bio-diesel  (in  collaboration
Gaëtan),  Milkymist  (an  hardware   Vj  platform  built  with  FPGA),
DIY Vacuum tubes  amplifier and at last an  half day hands-on workshop
on FPGA Verilog development. The guy is a mental Volcano eruption.

Another   good  interdisciplinary   presence  in   the   festival  was
Milovann Yanatchkov: this visionary  architect uses only free software
for  his work,  with  good  and original  results.   His workshop  was
entitled after Paul Graham's book  "Hackers and Painters" and ended up
illustrating the early concept of  perspective in Paolo Ucello as well
his experiments with Fluxus 3D live coding engine..

Dulcis in fundo there  were several interesting lightning talks, among
them the nomadic hacker  Meinhard gave three interesting presentations
also pointing out this interesting anonet.org initiative, which sounds
new to me. As well  Robin Gareus outlining his new development project
at  the University of  Paris: theartcollider,  something that  will be
very  interesting   for  all  of  us   experimenting  with  Ogg/Theora
streaming.


Feeling sorry  to have missed it  all? well you should  since this HSF
was really  legendary, until  the next  comes up: see  you in  2010 in
Istanbul!



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Hackerspace%20festival%20account</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Tor helps</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Tor%20helps</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://yro.slashdot.org/story/09/06/29/1230216/The-Technology-Keeping-Information-Flowing-in-Iran


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Tor%20helps</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>India making the wrong step</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#India%20making%20the%20wrong%20step</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://yro.slashdot.org/story/09/06/28/1538221/India-To-Put-All-Citizen-Info-In-a-Central-Database

Issues on census and the Tsunami


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#India%20making%20the%20wrong%20step</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Augmented reality (now for real)</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Augmented%20reality%20</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://www.iema.net/news/envnews?aid=18913

The Evolution of Google


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Augmented%20reality%20</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The Walnut Tree</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20Walnut%20Tree</link>
<description><![CDATA[


My head foaming clouds, sea inside me and out
i am a walnut tree in Gulhane Park
an old walnut, knot by knot, shred by shred
Neither you are aware of this, nor the police

I am a walnut tree in Gulhane Park
My leaves are nimble, nimble like fish in water
My leaves are sheer, sheer like a silk handkerchief
pick, wipe, my rose, the tear from your eyes
My leaves are my hands, I have one hundred thousand
I touch you with one hundred thousand hands, I touch Istanbul
My leaves are my eyes, I look in amazement
I watch you with one hundred thousand eyes, I watch Istanbul
Like one hundred thousand hearts, beat, beat my leaves

I am a walnut tree in Gulhane Park
neither you are aware of this, nor the police


(Nazim Hikmet, 1 July 1957, Balcik)

Thanks Ozge for this sweet dedication.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20Walnut%20Tree</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Hackerspace festival #2</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Hackerspace%20festival%20%232</link>
<description><![CDATA[Just  touched base  at the  tmp/lab in  Paris, getting  ready  for the
second edition of the  hackerspace festival, which raises already high
expectations this  year, as it has  been noticed even  by slashdot.

On the first edition we had about 50 registered participants, counting
up to 200 people attendance during the whole 3 days; this year we have
200 registered participants, so we'll see how it goes.

I'll be  facilitating a round-table  on ICT disaster recovery  as well
taking part to a debate on the future of hackerspaces.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Hackerspace%20festival%20%232</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Deforestation doesn't make people rich</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Deforestation%20doesn%27t%20make%20people%20rich</link>
<description><![CDATA[A recent academic study on economical growth in deforested areas shows
that the benefits of this business are short-lived and unsustainable.
"Boom-and-Bust Development Patterns Across the Amazon Deforestation Frontier"
is  the title of  this research  that was  undertaken by  academics in
Cambridge, Montpellier and Lisbon.

The  idea that  forests are  worth more  alive than  dead  is commonly
advocated by natives, but for  decades we assisted to their massacres,
last  but not  least the  recent slaughter  in Peru.  Apparently those
corporations making a business  on deforestation are too short sighted
and maybe even a bit sadistic, let me add.

Another study titled "The economics of ecosystems and biodiversity" is
running through its  first phase in Europe, as if  there would be more
evidence     needed      after     disasters     like      that     in
the deforestation of Malawi,  Indonesia, the well known Amazonian rain
forest and many others.

I'm feeling kind of stupid  in reporting all this. What really matters
is the  amount of  time that  the World needed  so far  to acknowledge
these  results: that  time  is directly  proportional  to the  urgency
motivating  the actions  of networks  like  E.L.F.  -  so wouldn't  be
better to  seek common ground and  start a peace  process, rather than
persecuting  the  so   called  "eco-terrorists"  and  keeping  current
policies?



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Deforestation%20doesn%27t%20make%20people%20rich</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Big company doesn't always win</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Big%20company%20doesn%27t%20always%20win</link>
<description><![CDATA[An        interesting       article       came        out       titled
The Lies  Of The Copyright Industry,  commenting on the  outcomes of a
recent "World Copyright Summit".

Released on the same day and by the same author, another publication
is worth noting:

The End Of Microsoft Money: Big Company Doesn't Always Win stating
how smaller companies are often more innovative and effective at
taking on big companies.

Let me just state that there is a clear connection visible between the
two issues.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Big%20company%20doesn%27t%20always%20win</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Word clouds</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Word%20clouds</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today I was having a look in an appealing technology for text analysis
so far neglected  in my research, mostly because of  lack of time: the
so called "word cloud".

Rendering  a word  cloud implies  a fairly  complicated  algorithm for
"packing", which  in recent  implementations explores the  presence of
vertical words and different colors.

For  a  while  the  state-of-the-art implementation  has  been  closed
source, implemented by  Wordle as an online service  running in a java
applet. But a  refreshing announcement comes at hand  here, offering a
code   that    can   be    evaluated   in   Ruby    language,   thanks
Nina Jansen's cloud publication.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Word%20clouds</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Brain-computer interface,</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Brain%2Dcomputer%20interface%2C</link>
<description><![CDATA[The          Brown          university          announced          the
second round  of BrainGate development,  a new clinical  trial towards
the ultimate goal of helping patients with spinal cord injury, stroke,
muscular dystrophy,  amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)  or limb loss
turn  their thoughts into  actions, restoring  independence, mobility,
and communication.

BrainGate, an  investigational technology being  developed to detect
brain  signals and  to  allow  people with  paralysis  to use  those
signals to  control assistive devices,  is about to begin  a second,
larger  clinical  trial.  The   system  is  based  on  neuroscience,
engineering and computer science research at Brown University.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Brain%2Dcomputer%20interface%2C</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>N2N peer 2 peer at layer 2</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#N2N%20peer%202%20peer%20at%20layer%202</link>
<description><![CDATA[Just  found a very  interesting attempt  to implement  a peer  to peer
network protocol on the Layer Two: N2N by the ntop folks.

In a nutshell, as OpenVPN  moved SSL from application (e.g.  used to
implement  the https protocol)  to network  protocol, n2n  moves P2P
from application to network level.

The  main   n2n  design  features   are:  asymmetrically  encrypted,
community  based,  NAT and  firewall  traversal, interoperable  with
other networks.

Sounds yummie, thanks Shammash for the pointer.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#N2N%20peer%202%20peer%20at%20layer%202</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The global lies are dissolving</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20global%20lies%20are%20dissolving</link>
<description><![CDATA[Recently there is more emerging  of truth than usual around stories of
oil exploitation in lands owned  by natives, from Nigeria to Amazonia,
might be the positive effect of a globally connected society.

The essay Peak Oil, Sustainability  and the Problem of Freedom by Kurt
Cobb suggests  this wave of  rationality reaches widely and  deeply on
how  our societies  are  articulated, elaborating  on  the concept  of
Freedom.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20global%20lies%20are%20dissolving</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Hands off the Internet in Canada</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Hands%20off%20the%20Internet%20in%20Canada</link>
<description><![CDATA[The CRTC (Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission)
has  released its  2009 new  media decision  on  Internet regulations,
rejecting  to  limit  the   liberties  offered  by  digital  networks,
basically taking an hands off approach. Here below a quote:

"Regulatory  intervention would get  in the  way of  innovation and
that a compelling case was not made that additional support through
an ISP levy was needed." []  "The Commission is of the view that
parties advocating repeal of the exemption orders did not establish
that  licensing undertakings  in  the new  media environment  would
contribute  in  a material  manner  to  the  implementation of  the
broadcasting policy set out in the Act."

Here the full text of the document.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Hands%20off%20the%20Internet%20in%20Canada</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>A scientific approach to economy</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#A%20scientific%20approach%20to%20economy</link>
<description><![CDATA[The New Scientist came out today with an interesting article profiling
possible scientific approaches to economy.

It's been a while I'm  planning to drive experiments with evolutionary
algorithms  on different scenarios  of economic  administration, maybe
using the Acovea engine. Anyone interested?

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#A%20scientific%20approach%20to%20economy</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The state of Video CoDecs  </title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20state%20of%20Video%20CoDecs%20%20</link>
<description><![CDATA[Here  a  very interesting  interview  with  Dan  Marlin, developer  of
Matroska and  Xvid, one  of the pioneers  in modern  video compression
systems:  small industries  all  around the  World producing  embedded
video  devices  and software  benefit  of  the  free and  open  source
software that Dan and his team released.

This  and more seminal  video codec  developments are  at risk  on the
non-free      market      ground      of     software      monopolies:
Micro$oft plans to  block third party codecs in  Windows media player,
which  sets the  base for  yet another  anti-trust  court-case against
Redmond's falling giant.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20state%20of%20Video%20CoDecs%20%20</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Shell finally facing reality?</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Shell%20finally%20facing%20reality%3F</link>
<description><![CDATA[Anyone remember Saro Wiwa? He  is the victim of Shell oil corporation,
a  martyr for  the many  unpunished aggressions  to the  ecosystem and
people of Nigeria for which Shell is guilty.

While people is  calling justice for the Ogoni tribes  in front of the
human                 rights                tribunal                in
New York,  where the court-case against  Shell is being  held, some of
the current  Shell functionaries and managers are  leaving the company
(and their responsibilities?)

Dutch   newspaper   NRC   is   one   of   the   few   daily   tabloids
reporting   news    on   the    topic,   updating   us    also   about
the recent explosion of violence  in the Niger delta connected to this
court-case.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Shell%20finally%20facing%20reality%3F</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>dyne:II in Mexico Monster City</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#dyne%3AII%20in%20Mexico%20Monster%20City</link>
<description><![CDATA[Vlax writes:

Heyall / hola

in  the context  of the  Latin American  Free  Software Installation
Festival (aka  FLISOL), the Mexico's Monster  City Espora.org's crew
presented  the dynebolic  II  distro and  the  Spanish version  user
manual, recently completed.




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#dyne%3AII%20in%20Mexico%20Monster%20City</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The slackers had it right after all</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20slackers%20had%20it%20right%20after%20all</link>
<description><![CDATA[Here a brilliant article that came out earlier this year on the Boston
Globe:  So  maybe  the  slackers  had  it right  after  all  by  David
Scharfenberg (tanks Aldert),  giving a voice to a  whole generation of
people  that consciously  decided  to  slack rather  than  race for  a
career.

The  author quotes  also "Generation  X", a  book by  Douglas Coupland
unfolding   an  interesting   narrative  spiced   by  the   irony  and
disenchantment of  skilled IT professionals born between  the '70s and
the  '80s.

Still  what i  find most  representative  of this  generation are  the
"peculiar intimate doubts" found in writings by Jonathan Alex Gold.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20slackers%20had%20it%20right%20after%20all</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>House of Commons washes hands</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#House%20of%20Commons%20washes%20hands</link>
<description><![CDATA[An  interesting signal  from London  where the  corruption  of several
Members of Parliament (mostly caused by alienating and disproportional
cast  privileges) is  causing the  resignation of  a minister  and the
expulsion of two members, while two Lords are investigated.

It       seems       to        have       started       with       the
Daily Telegraph publishing  MP's expenses, an investigative journalism
operation that costed 150k GBP to the tabloid. My heartfelt thanks for
the investment.

Interesting how media in UK is free to document all this and even play
a  role in  promoting the  investigations: quite  a different  code of
deontology in respect to what turned Italy in a media dictatorship.

In  the "Mani Pulite"  Italian episode  in the  early 90's  media also
played an  important role  until they could,  while the  operation was
mostly lead by  magistrates; they soon had to  leave their jobs, while
some became politicians like Di Pietro. Craxi for example had to leave
for  his  villa  in  Hammamet  (Libia),  while  the  highest  cast  of
politicians  still  welcomes  his   dynasty  today:  Craxi's  son  and
daughter.  In  fact nothing really  changed until today: the  wages of
Italian members of Parliament are  the higher in all Europe, double as
those of UK members.

I wonder  if British MP's  also have a  "plan B" ready in  an offshore
villa


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#House%20of%20Commons%20washes%20hands</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Benchmark of serialization tools</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Benchmark%20of%20serialization%20tools</link>
<description><![CDATA[A     short    article     came    out     with    results     of    a
benchmark on serialisation tools  as java, json, protobuf, xstream and
others.

It provides a good evaluation at first glance, with small charts about
their  performance  in  tasks  as object  creation,  serializaton  and
deserialization.

My choice for  a overall winner is JSON, which  i repute well reliable
for deployment,  considering it is  free, has a vast  community behind
and a flexible implementation in javascript language.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Benchmark%20of%20serialization%20tools</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>A pattern in prime numbers?</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#A%20pattern%20in%20prime%20numbers%3F</link>
<description><![CDATA[This  recent theory (some  kind of  "hot water  discovery", as  it was
unnoticed  for long)  has  shaken the  imaginary  of geeks  worldwide:
a  new pattern  seems to  be found  in prime  numbers.  Mathematicians
stated  that  the  prime  number   sequence  can  be  described  by  a
generalization of  Benford's law, as  the frequency of  higher decimal
cyphers in  the leading digit  of prime numbers follows  a logarithmic
decay.

Somewhat unexpectedly, the leading digits aren't randomly or uniformly
distributed. Besides providing insight  into the nature of primes, the
finding could also have applications in areas such as fraud detection,
stock market analysis and cryptography.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#A%20pattern%20in%20prime%20numbers%3F</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Positions in Flux</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Positions%20in%20Flux</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today  I've taken  part in  the Positions  in Flux  symposium  held in
Amsterdam   in  occasion   of  the   30  years   anniversary   of  the
Netherlands Media  Art Institute, formerly known as  Montevideo / Time
Based Arts.

Rather than a panoramic on projects I'm conducting, still easy to find
online for those interested, I've taken the occasion to share thoughts
on the current perception of  Free Software and Open Source philosophy
in  art, along  with some  overdue criticism  of the  Creative Commons
hollow hype, as well of the Creative Industries and their systematised
processing of art for the global market.

Even if not  obvious, I believe the dynamics  of these two phenomenons
are  related; among  the  references quoted  in  the intervention  are
Benjamin                          Mako                          Hill's
Towards a Standard of Freedom: Creative Commons and the Free Software Movement
and        Florian        Cramer's        post       on        nettime
The Creative  Common Misunderstanding, while the  vigorous critique of
the   creative   industries    stands   on   Rana   Dasgupta's   essay
The Next Idea of the Artist (Art, music and the present threat of creativity).

Here below a short transcript:

"Open Source" doesn't mean free  access, nor open space or open air;
it  presumes a  seamful  approach to  design  as a  response to  the
increasing  reliance  on technology  and  its  accessibility; it  is
interactive    without    prescribed    boundaries,   following    a
combinatorial,  generative approach  to development;  it is  peer to
peer as no producer can  control further interaction patterns; it is
grassroot as creations are born out of initiative and cohesion based
on needs felt and understood in first person by community members.

About  Creative Commons,  its  motto "Some  rights  reserved." is  a
relatively  hollow  call: the  slogan  factually  reverses the  Free
Software and  Open Source philosophy  of reserving rights  to users,
not  copyright  owners, in  order  to  allow  the former  to  become
producers themselves.

The  dis/appropriating loop of  creativity must  be recursive  to be
fruitful: not only production means belong to the people using them,
further creations should  be free to be recombined.   rights must be
granted focusing on people interacting, not just those providing the
interactive infrastructure.

Unfortunately there is a diffuse lack of perception for alternatives
offered by the  Open Source and Free Software  approach over current
profit models.

As a present  problem, also deriving from the  lack of understanding
of  the  importance  of  grass-root  creativity,  top-down  cultural
management is  patronising art production:  mass-media aesthetics of
an  entirely sanitised and  efficient creativity,  of the  sort that
will  not rely  on unstable  people  and can  therefore be  globally
rationalised.

That the great artists of  modern Western culture managed to produce
what they did, despite the danger and intensity of their effort, was
due in large part to improvised social forms built around close-knit
networks where thought and affect circulated with high velocity, and
where it  was possible  to try out  forms of  non-conventional human
relationships that would not destroy, nor be destroyed by, a life of
art.

Seen  from an  historical perspective,  In  the second  half of  the
twentieth century  many of the  functions of creative  networks were
already  taken over  in Europe  by institutions  (government funding
bodies,  universities, museums,  etc)  and much  of their  excessive
feeling was  neutralised.  This was only  a small part  of a general
process  of   the  time:  the  absorption  of   human  emotion  into
bureaucratic channels,  and the emergence  of a social  coolness, an
efficiency of feeling.

At this stage  in the twenty-first century, we are  in the middle of
another  large-scale  restructuring   of  ideas  of  creativity  and
culture.  As  one of  the most significant  generators of  image and
value, creativity now has become  a critical resource for the global
economic engine. What creativity is,  and how it can be systematised
and  circulated,  are  therefore  urgent questions  of  contemporary
capitalist organisation.  As cultural  producers are thrust into the
full intensity  of globally dispersed,  just-in-time production, new
images  of creative  inspiration and  output are  required  that sit
tidily within the systematised processes of the global market.

Creativity   must  be   rendered  comprehensible,   transparent  and
rational: there can  be none of the destructive  excesses evident in
the  lives of  many of  the  greatest artists  of European  history.
Creativity must  circulate cleanly and quickly, and  it should leave
no dirty remainder.

For  what interests  Hollywood, and  the market  in general,  is not
creativity as  a complex human  process, weighed down in  bodies and
relationships and empty days, but creativity as an abstraction, free
of irrationality  and pain, and light  enough to hover  like a great
logo above the continents.

Perhaps,  as  the  logic  of systematised  production  occupies  the
terrain of human  creativity more completely, we will  reach a stage
where we surrender all knowledge about this troubling domain, and it
will  become entirely  alien  to us.   Perhaps  one day  we will  be
terrified  of  what  explosive   dangers  might  rise  up  from  the
creativity of human beings.


Heartfelt thanks  to all  my colleagues at  NIMk for  having organised
such an interesting symposium which  has seen among the guest speakers
Wafaa  Bilal,  Marcus Neustetter,  Femke  Snelting  and Renée  Turner,
Marcos Garcia and Joasia Krysa.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Positions%20in%20Flux</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>European Telecom Package</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#European%20Telecom%20Package</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today the EU Parliament rejected the Telecom Package while passing the
138  amendment:  the controlled  regime  that  Sarkozy and  Berlusconi
wanted to establish  in Europe is far from  complying with the current
decision.

Still there  will be  a 3rd  reading of the  package later  this year,
while the Opennet coalition is actively campaigning against those that
want to lock up the Internet, see Blackout Europe.




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#European%20Telecom%20Package</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Prosthetics with HONF in the fablab</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Prosthetics%20with%20HONF%20in%20the%20fablab</link>
<description><![CDATA[Four researchers  from the House  of Natural Fibers in  Yogyakarta are
visiting     Amsterdam     during     these    days,     running     a
workshop  on prosthetics  in  the Fablab,  envisioning new  affordable
possibilities in development of  artificial limbs, which are currently
sold at exorbitant prices.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Prosthetics%20with%20HONF%20in%20the%20fablab</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>RIP Fravia</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#RIP%20Fravia</link>
<description><![CDATA[Leaving  us  a beautiful  swansong,  frankly  announcing his  imminent
death, Fravia passed away today and will be missed by many.

He has  been the  most influential reverse-engineer  of our  times, in
fact  considered to  be the  father of  reverse-engineering  in modern
age. And  not just  an "engineer",  he has produced  a vast  amount of
documentation, reflections and texts  collected since the early Usenet
times.

Fravia left us  a search engine for all documents  he gathered, plus a
comprehensive documentation on how to use search engines "beyond their
surface". His  knowledge base collection, as unconventional  as it can
be seen  from an  academic point  of view, it  is an  extremely actual
corpus for contemporary studies on digital heuristics.

Rest in Peace Fravia  sperando  il prossimo giro avvenga su di un
pianeta con meno imbecilli.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#RIP%20Fravia</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Riots in Istanbul</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Riots%20in%20Istanbul</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today  is May Day  and anniversary  of the  Taksim Square  massacre in
1977,  when  extreme  right  wing  snipers  opened  fire  on  May  Day
demonstrators in Istanbul, killing 34 people.

Just a few days ago the Turkish parliament passed a law making May 1 a
national  holiday again.  It was  taken  off the  public holiday  list
following a military  coup in 1980.

Still,  there is  very  little coverage  on  the media  about what  is
happening  in Istanbul  today: an  unnatural silence,  while  even the
Istanbul   Indymedia   website    is   defaced   by   some   religious
fundamentalists.

This                           recent                          article
Deepening Crisis,  Growing Resistance: Workers in Turkey  gives a good
overview on the  situation, while the following press  agency is all I
could find so far about the current riots:

ISTANBUL (AFP)Several  hundred May Day  demonstrators clashed with
police in central Istanbul Friday  in battles which saw water cannon
fired and  several arrests made.   Turkish riot police  staged three
charges against  hundreds of demonstrators in the  Sisli district of
the  city who  had hurled  rocks  at security  forces, according  to
correspondents at  the scene.  Several thousand union  and left wing
activists took part in the annual protest.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Riots%20in%20Istanbul</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Minix plans more development</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Minix%20plans%20more%20development</link>
<description><![CDATA[ITWorld  reports  that  Prof.   Andrew  S.   Tanenbaum  of  the  Vrije
Universiteit van  Amsterdam received a trust by  the European Research
Council for the  development of Minix a legendary  implementation of a
micro-kernel OS.

Tanenbaum's minimalist approach is long  time inspiring, be it just in
the  name of his  system, which  used to  run from  a floppy  disk and
require very  little memory.  I enjoyed studying  in its  early times.
A discussion about the event follows on Slashdot.

I'd be interested to hear what are the plans for the Syllable hackers.
The next  generation of Minix  will be developed  by a core team  of 6
people funded with 2.5m EUR over a period of 5 years.




]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Minix%20plans%20more%20development</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Geocities falling?</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Geocities%20falling%3F</link>
<description><![CDATA[Geocities was the first place on the Internet where anyone could get a
free  website, hosting  several thousands  of websites  made available
before  the third millennium  (mostly all  decorated with  that cheesy
look that some of us nostalgically smile at).

Later  bought by  Yahoo,  the  company is  now  dropping the  service,
letting a huge piece of Internet's history fall away as a trail of its
financial  crisis.

While the Archive Team is busy saving Internet pre-history, let me add
that Geocities is the first  world-wide implementation of what we call
"social networks"  and web-2.0 nowadays:  even if the interface  was a
simple FTP upload of HTML  pages, the social dynamic configured itself
as a (very chaotic) social web of people going public on the net.

Still I'll  honestly conclude that  Geocities hosted some of  the most
horribly designed pages that ever appeared on the Internet, but that's
a part of history we can learn from, right?

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Geocities%20falling%3F</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The Narcysist P.H.A.T.W.A.</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20Narcysist%20P%2EH%2EA%2ET%2EW%2EA%2E</link>
<description><![CDATA[The Narcysist released his new music video P.H.A.T.W.A.

It makes it up for a  good laugh, expressing well the feeling of youth
in multi-ethnic societies about police repression.

Paranoid controls on pedestrians since  9/11 didn't made it any better
(and bomb attacks have been all  over anyway) while the raise of false
positives  generated quite  a bad  feeling  against those  who try  to
"protect the citizens".



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20Narcysist%20P%2EH%2EA%2ET%2EW%2EA%2E</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>A &quot;cyber-attack&quot; on a city</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#A%20%22cyber%2Dattack%22%20on%20a%20city</link>
<description><![CDATA[Now this  is something one could really  call "cyber-crime", wondering
if the word  will get to the right hears: while  the policy makers are
too busy persecuting kids writing  viruses, they are not even aware of
the risks involved in building centralised information architectures.

Here
Bruce Perens took his time to describe and warn about the situation in Morgan Hill
when a few weeks ago unidentified attackers climbed down four manholes
and cut eight fiber cables serving the city.

That attack demonstrated a  severe fault in American infrastructure:
its  centralization. The  city of  Morgan  Hill and  parts of  three
counties lost 911 service, cellular mobile telephone communications,
land-line  telephone,  DSL internet  and  private networks,  central
station fire  and burglar alarms,  ATMs, credit card  terminals, and
monitoring of critical utilities. In addition, resources that should
not  have  failed,  like  the  local  hospital's  internal  computer
network, proved  to be dependent on external  resources, leaving the
hospital with a "paper system" for the day.

Scary stuff,  especially considering the military  intelligence is too
busy developing futuristic warplanes and worrying about who stole them
the plans for their new super-secret toys.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#A%20%22cyber%2Dattack%22%20on%20a%20city</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>GPU Grid</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#GPU%20Grid</link>
<description><![CDATA[Great project: GPUGrid, finally someone did it!

Wishing it will grow in compatibility with more video cards.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#GPU%20Grid</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Eucalyptus</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Eucalyptus</link>
<description><![CDATA[Eucalyptus is  the "Elastic Utility Computing  Architecture" of choice
for  Ubuntu Server  9.04,  with full  compatibility  with the  "Amazon
Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2)".

That's now a serious competitor for Google App Engine, offering a less
proprietary approach at first glance.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Eucalyptus</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Manifesto of Post-Futurism</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Manifesto%20of%20Post%2DFuturism</link>
<description><![CDATA[Even if  i don't really like manifestos,  this text by BiFo  goes in a
good  direction  declaring  the  Death  of Futurism  and  laying  down
directions for the Post-Futurist movements to come.

Among all the points made, the numbers 9 and 10 read good:

We want to ridicule the idiots  who spread the discourse of war: the
fanatics of competition, the fanatics of the bearded gods who incite
massacres,  the  fanatics  terrorised  by the  disarming  femininity
blossoming in all of us.

We demand  that art  turns into a  life-changing force.  We  seek to
abolish  the separation  between poetry  and mass  communication, to
reclaim the power  of media from the merchants and  return it to the
poets and the sages.

Just  a doubt  about who  are the  sages,  this might  be a  bit of  a
controversy, along with other parts  of the text which sound like from
the middle-ages. I sense a lack  of peer to peer attitude overall, but
well it's  already a very good  step forward from  silence; I've never
been 100% happy with "post-" movements anyway.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Manifesto%20of%20Post%2DFuturism</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Cluster computing in javascript</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Cluster%20computing%20in%20javascript</link>
<description><![CDATA[This is potentially one of  the most interesting projects of the year,
"map reduce in the browser became very popular among geeks already in
march this  year.  As a result,  it received lots  of contributions.

Very smart people, exemplar design  of such a website and its contents
and a very powerful project.





]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Cluster%20computing%20in%20javascript</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Exoskeletons going for sale</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Exoskeletons%20going%20for%20sale</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://www.hplusmagazine.com/articles/robotics/i-am-ironman


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Exoskeletons%20going%20for%20sale</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Free market bulldozed in Lagos</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Free%20market%20bulldozed%20in%20Lagos</link>
<description><![CDATA[Speaking of  what really is free  market, some 7.000  traders in Lagos
(we're  speaking   of  official  members  of   the  Freedom  Merchants
Association of Awodi-Ora Estate, Mile  2 Oke) have seen their premises
bulldozed away by State agents and militars on February this year.

The story  is that of a  big injustice, made even  more significant if
taken as a brutal metaphor  of what happened in the "neo-liberist era"
to small business initiatives.

Refraining question: what the financial crisis is about?



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Free%20market%20bulldozed%20in%20Lagos</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>RIP Dave Arneson</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#RIP%20Dave%20Arneson</link>
<description><![CDATA[RIP http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dave_Arneson


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#RIP%20Dave%20Arneson</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>6 april movements</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#6%20april%20movements</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today is the 6th  of april, a date marking the birth  of a movement in
Cairo which  mostly coordinates and  grow online, with a  fixed yearly
appointment  on the  streets,  see  the blogs  in  English and  Arabic
languages; and since i really can't keep it inside, let me add more.

We're  living in a  peculiar period,  just before  the "Epiphany  of a
Catastrophe":  it  is a  period  in  which  those who  foresee  what's
happening can be persecuted, lynched, imprisoned, exiled.

An metaphor  is offered  by the earthquake  which stroke  Abruzzo last
night,  for  which a  polemic  now  started:  the geologist  Giampaolo
Giuliani who predicted the disaster was called to court for "procurato
allarme", calling a  crime his act of giving an  alarm that could have
saved the lives of many.

Im not sure what do you think about the last tumults in London City, i
guess you have heard, a man was killed by police it seems, for sure he
was  the  last  person  that  they wanted  to  beat  down   factory
occupations started in Paris (deja vu?!)  with kidnapping of managers,
also  in London  a  factory was  occupied  by its  workers, the  story
unfolds on London Indymedia webpages. Way better initiatives for fired
workers, compared to those in USA (one dumped by IBM?! what a hot geek
gossip)  who opened  fire in  NYC killing  13 immigrants,  and another
fired-gunman the day after. I mean just yesterday. Quite some shocking
news, excuse me the tone.

As  time is accelerating,  we are  also.  Online  is possible  to keep
yourself  updated,  its getting  more  participative  thanks to  fluid
exchanges of  ideas and  views.  You can  even be persecuted  for your
public opinion - expressed by a simple click - just joining a group on
facebook.

I was visiting Cairo exactly one year ago, on 6 of april, when factory
workers  in the  nearby "industrial  town" of  Mahalla went  to engage
police in the street with sword  fights. have you heard of that? There
are times when, for as much as  we have heard and seen in the past few
years and predictably going to  see more, military intelligence had to
strike the  situation to  an end.  I  just wonder  how it is  going to
happen  today, when  the most  powerful intelligence  is media.

And  most importantly,  how long  it all  has to  occur before  we can
really  represent  the  state of  things?  is  it  the Epiphany  of  a
Catastrophe?

where are thou Orson Wells! with your martians to make us humble??!


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#6%20april%20movements</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>OpenGL in HTML</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#OpenGL%20in%20HTML</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://blog.vlad1.com/canvas-3d/


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#OpenGL%20in%20HTML</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>London.c</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#London%2Ec</link>
<description><![CDATA[londra riots, factory occupations



/*
 * Requiem for Peace (and one dead man in London.c)
 *
 * Cycle 78, year 26 (Ji-Chou), month 3 (Wu-Chen), day 7 (Ding-Chou)
 *
 * (A)m*dam(jrml)
*/

int moment = 0;

int justice = 7;

void *anger = "
  There was a  pause, and an eerie silence, just before  he did it.  A
  green  scarf  masking  his face,  the  man  held  a large  piece  of
  scaffolding  above  his   head  and,  surrounded  by  photographers,
  eyeballed  the unprotected window  of the  Royal Bank  of Scotland's
  branch on Threadneedle Street.
";

void *exception = "
  In that  split second, one voice  amid thousands in  the crowd broke
  the silence.  - Don't do  it -  she screamed -  He did -  This isn't
  violence -  retorted another voice in  the crowd - We  paid for this
  building.
";

unsigned int moment;
unsigned int imacy;
unsigned int cause;
bool represented;

extern void *wave;
extern void *street;
extern void *justice;
extern int death;

while(protest) {

  for(moment=0; moment < justice; moment++) {

    wave = malloc( sizeof( anger ) );

    // wave is filled with people
    democracy[moment] -> reclaim(wave, street);

    try {


// check if they smile


      represented = reality(moment);

      if(!represented) throw(exception);

    }

    if( moment[wave] == death ) {

      // One protester at the scene said the man was in his 30s and died
      // of natural causes, the  Press Association news agency reported.

      imacy  = moment[wave]; // zoom in

      cause  = natural(imacy); // the cause is just an index

      /* Alok,  currently  in Exchange  Square,  would  like to  thank
         Muriel for  lending him  her pen when  his run out.   He says
         there are around 150 people  out in sympathy with the man who
         died and 70 police. */
      imacy -= democracy[cause] -> individual(justice);

      rip(imacy); // the man was there to protest, but he is no more

    }


// RFC-G20


    if( !listen(moment) ) {
      justice--; // will affect globally
    }

  }

  catch(void *e) {

    printf((char*)exception);

    // Once they  had broken into the bank,  however, the protesters
    // did not quite know what to do.

    printf("justice is %u", justice);
    printf("anger address is %p (out of bounds?)", anger);
    printf("it seems they are still smiling.");
    // seen before, anyway we send the warning

  }

 } // street protest ends, but the wave will hit more shores

/* this code won't compile alone, it is part of a larger software. */





]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#London%2Ec</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Untitled</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#20090330</link>
<description><![CDATA[++ http://www.boingboing.net/2009/03/30/scavengers-manifesto.html
http://www.trashwiki.org


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 00:00:00 CEST</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#20090330</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>:</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#%3A</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://33bits.org/

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#%3A</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Untitled</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#20090326</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2009/mar/26/anticapitalism-protest-recession-g20


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#20090326</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Cyber-politics in China</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Cyber%2Dpolitics%20in%20China</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://chinadigitaltimes.net/2009/03/left-and-right-in-chinese-cyber-politics/

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Cyber%2Dpolitics%20in%20China</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Dyne:bolic at school</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Dyne%3Abolic%20at%20school</link>
<description><![CDATA[Just found out that Uncle Paulie is showing dyne:bolic to his classes,
documenting and coordinating his activity into this blog, hopefully it
served the purpose of introducing  pupils to GNU/Linux.

Our  dyne:bolic live/CD  works  quite straightforward  for the  simple
tasks it  has to accomplish; the  dyne:II core hasn't  been updated in
the past  2 years, we  could even argue  that's a feature :)  still we
support old  computers, provide a simple and  consistent interface for
GNU users and the simplest procedure installation ever :)

Later on  this year there  will be some  news about the future  of our
dyne operating  system ;) meanwhile keep  an eye on  pure:dyne and its
active  development crew,  rowing high  to  the goal  of a  multimedia
production system with higher hardware requirements.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Dyne%3Abolic%20at%20school</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Open source gaze tracker</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Open%20source%20gaze%20tracker</link>
<description><![CDATA[Found this very interesting project today, thanks to Caedes:

Opengazer is an open source application that uses an ordinary webcam
to estimate the direction of your gaze. This information can then be
passed to other applications.  For example, used in conjunction with
Dasher, opengazer allows you to write with your eyes. Opengazer aims
to be  a low-cost software alternative  to commercial hardware-based
eye trackers.

which actually  works! after compiling the source  it runned smoothly,
tracking the  movements of my pupils  and moving the  mouse across the
screen very cool sensation.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Open%20source%20gaze%20tracker</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Untitled</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#20090319</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://www.repubblica.it/2009/03/sezioni/scuola_e_universita/servizi/scuola-2009-10/brunetta-onda/brunetta-onda.html



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#20090319</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Untitled</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#20090318</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://www.lavanguardia.es/sucesos/noticias/20090318/53662650766/el-robin-de-los-bancos-pasara-a-disposicion-judicial-tras-declarar-ante-mossos-barcelona-duran-unive.html


http://www.boingboing.net/2009/03/18/newspaper-box-gravey.html


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#20090318</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Untitled</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#20090310</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://www.radiomundial.com.ve/yvke/noticia.php?20929


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#20090310</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Winter Camp</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Winter%20Camp</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://networkcultures.org/wpmu/wintercamp/2009/03/08/opening-eyes-and-earlids/


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Winter%20Camp</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>:</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#%3A</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://hardware.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=09/02/24/1918217


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#%3A</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Labour in high tech China</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Labour%20in%20high%20tech%20China</link>
<description><![CDATA[High Tech Misery In China
http://news.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=09/02/15/2020200



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Labour%20in%20high%20tech%20China</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Empty for one year..</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Empty%20for%20one%20year%2E%2E</link>
<description><![CDATA[429 eviction law denied in dutch high court

http://www.ravagedigitaal.org/index.htm?2009nieuws/februari/12/nws.php~mainFrame
http://indymedia.nl/nl/2009/02/57634.shtml


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Empty%20for%20one%20year%2E%2E</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Vilem Flusser award</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Vilem%20Flusser%20award</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://www.transmediale.de/en/critical-consumer-practice-2-event

overwhelmed (video)

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Vilem%20Flusser%20award</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Blood and Coltan</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Blood%20and%20Coltan</link>
<description><![CDATA[Am Handy klebt Blut http://futurezone.orf.at/stories/1502204/

Vér tapad a PC-khez és a mobilokhoz
http://www.sg.hu/cikkek/65428/ver_tapad_a_pc_khez_es_a_mobilokhoz



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Blood%20and%20Coltan</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Forge.mil</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Forge%2Emil</link>
<description><![CDATA[Today  US  Dept.   of  Defense  announced  the  creation  of  its  own
open-source code repository: Forge.mil.

Mjasay writes on  slasldot:

The  US Department  of Defense,  which has  been flirting  with open
source for years as a way to improve software quality and cut costs,
has finally  burst the  dam on Defense-related  open-source adoption
with Forge.mil, an open-source code repository based on Sourceforge.
Though it currently only holds  three projects and is limited to DoD
personnel for  security reasons, all  code is publicly  viewable and
will almost  certainly lead to  other agencies participating  on the
site or  creating their  own.  Open source  has clearly come  a long
way. Years ago  studies declared open source a  security risk.  Now,
one of  the most security-conscious  organizations on the  planet is
looking to  open source to provide better  security than proprietary
alternatives."

This is a very interesting  move if interpreted as the potential start
for  a "planetary  intelligence", as  much as  open-source development
created  a planetary  dynamic that  spread horizontally  over national
boundaries.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Forge%2Emil</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>UK Gov. abandons piracy legislation</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#UK%20Gov%2E%20abandons%20piracy%20legislation</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://www.custompc.co.uk/news/605400/government-abandons-piracy-legislation.html

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#UK%20Gov%2E%20abandons%20piracy%20legislation</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>People's search engines</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#People%27s%20search%20engines</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://geek2live.blogspot.com/2009/01/people-search-engine-or-when-you-want.html

Community Networks — the Robin Hood Approach
http://blogs.nmss.com/communications/2009/01/community-networks-the-robinhood-approach.html

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#People%27s%20search%20engines</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Anomalous Wave</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Anomalous%20Wave</link>
<description><![CDATA[We Won’t Pay for Your Crisis: Italian Struggles Against Education Reform

http://www.metamute.org/en/content/we_won_t_pay_for_your_crisis_italian_struggles_against_education_reform

http://www.insutv.it/domenicaut/numero-puntata/07


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Anomalous%20Wave</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Social Networking and Surveillance</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Social%20Networking%20and%20Surveillance</link>
<description><![CDATA[Fuchs, Christian. 2009. Social Networking Sites and the Surveillance
Society. A Critical Case Study of the Usage of studiVZ, Facebook, and
MySpace by Students in Salzburg in the Context of Electronic
Surveillance. Salzburg/Vienna: Research Group UTI. ISBN 978-3-200-01428-2.

Study: http://fuchs.icts.sbg.ac.at/SNS_Surveillance_Fuchs.pdf

Background Information: http://fuchs.icts.sbg.ac.at/SNS_E.html


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Social%20Networking%20and%20Surveillance</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Obama's stimulus</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Obama%27s%20stimulus</link>
<description><![CDATA[An  article titled  Yes, We  Can  Make the  Stimulus More  Stimulating
appeared  online and  bounced across  many geek's  websites especially
because mentioning the "Funding  for the Development of Open Software"
in  USA, apparently  a possible  concern on  the new  president's desk
Barack Obama.

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Obama%27s%20stimulus</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Al-Jazeera footage released (CC) BY-NC-ND</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Al%2DJazeera%20footage%20released%20</link>
<description><![CDATA[The news  network Al-Jazeera, originally Arabic and  recently also run
by  English speaking  editors, decided  to licence  all  its published
materials under  a Creative Commons  non-commercial and non-derivative
license.

The  CC.Al-Jazeera  repository was  launched,  archiving all  released
materials in a organized way and providing download of high-resolution
media files.


http://firefogg.org/


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Al%2DJazeera%20footage%20released%20</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>The silkworm dish</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20silkworm%20dish</link>
<description><![CDATA[Among the list  of efficient food sources, not  really vegetarian, but
apparently sustainable: eating silkworms.


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#The%20silkworm%20dish</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Politics in Israel</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Politics%20in%20Israel</link>
<description><![CDATA[Just before  the elections in Israel  and right after  the massacre of
civilians in Gaza, which also  included bombing of UN headquarters and
public incitations to murder peace  activists, it's maybe time to have
a look at  how reasonable people are doing over there.

One impressive  campaign is  December 18th: at  the motto of  FREE THE
SHMINISTIM" young conscious objectors (among them also the daughter of
a former deputy  head of Mossad) stepped forward  and refused to serve
the omnipresent  militarization of Israel, the country  where they are
born and that still forces them to serve IDF for 2 to 3 years.

Since 20 years now (and finally) we had abolition of coercive military
service  for youth  in  Europe: this  is  definitely one  of the  most
important political standpoints  for Israel to work on,  if it intends
to get closer to Europe.

More on what the militarization of  Israel is doing to the soul of its
children is  poetically depicted by  the animation Waltz  with Bashir,
the story of massacres in Sabra  and Shatila in the eyes and memory of
those who actually served the IDF operated massacres in 1982.



]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Politics%20in%20Israel</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>Not quite in the zone</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Not%20quite%20in%20the%20zone</link>
<description><![CDATA[http://www.metamute.org/en/content/not_quite_in_the_zone
Ben Watson http://www.militantesthetix.co.uk/


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#Not%20quite%20in%20the%20zone</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>:</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#%3A</link>
<description><![CDATA[uscito zeitgeist final ???


]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#%3A</guid>

</item>

<item>
<title>:</title>
<link>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#%3A</link>
<description><![CDATA[John Maddog Hall: http://www.linux-magazine.com/online/blogs/paw_prints_writings_of_the_maddog/campus_party_brazil_maddog_s_challenge_multimedia_and_free_software

]]></description>
<author>jaromil</author>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 00:00:00 CET</pubDate>
<guid>http://jaromil.dyne.org/journal/research_2009.html#%3A</guid>

</item>

  </channel>
</rss>
